<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="\rss\stylesheet.xsl"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:itunes="http://www.itunes.com/dtds/podcast-1.0.dtd" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:georss="http://www.georss.org/georss" xmlns:fh="http://purl.org/syndication/history/1.0">
  <channel>
    <title>McKinsey Insights &amp; Publications</title>
    <link>http://www.mckinsey.com/insights</link>
    <description>McKinsey Insights &amp; Publications RSS Feeds</description>
    <language>en</language>
    <managingEditor>test@mckinsey.com</managingEditor>
    <webMaster>web@mckinsey.com</webMaster>
    <pubDate>Mon, 23 Sep 2013 13:53:11 GMT</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 26 Sep 2013 19:19:36 GMT</lastBuildDate>
    <category domain="Syndic8">Business</category>
    <ttl>5</ttl>
    <skipHours>
      <hour>0</hour>
      <hour>3</hour>
      <hour>14</hour>
      <hour>23</hour>
    </skipHours>
    <image>
      <url>http://www.mckinsey.com/~/media/McKinsey/dotcom/Global/logo_mckinsey-quarterly.ashx</url>
      <title>McKinsey Insights &amp; Publications</title>
    </image>
    <fh:incremental>false</fh:incremental>
    <atom:link rel="hub" href="http://pubsubhubbub.appspot.com" />
    <atom:link rel="self" href="http://www.mckinsey.com/insights/flipboardrss" />
    <copyright>Copyright (c) McKinsey &amp; Company. All rights reserved. Reprinted by permission.</copyright>
    <generator>Sitecore CMS: http://www.sitecore.net. Sitecore RSS module: McKinsey.RSS, Version=1.3.2.24631, Culture=neutral, PublicKeyToken=null</generator>
    <item>
      <title>How to choose the right nonexecutive board leader</title>
      <description>It’s time to use a structured process for selecting the nonexecutive leader of the board. Defining the role is a good start.</description>
      <link>http://www.mckinsey.com/insights/leading_in_the_21st_century/copy_how_to_choose_the_right_nonexecutive_board_leader</link>
      <guid>http://www.mckinsey.com/insights/leading_in_the_21st_century/copy_how_to_choose_the_right_nonexecutive_board_leader</guid>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 Sep 2013 19:17:14 GMT</pubDate>
      <ID>5b288945-c072-4f79-a770-5167f9823838</ID>
      <category>Leadership</category>
      <dc:creator><![CDATA[Dennis Carey, John J. Keller, and Michael Patsalos-Fox]]></dc:creator>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><strong>Ever since stock-listing requirements</strong> prompted many US companies to name an independent director to serve as the chairman, lead director, or presiding director of the board, these companies have been grappling with what, exactly, this board leader should do and how to find the right person for the job.</p>
<p>The change in governance followed corporate scandals (in the early part of the decade) that led to investor pressures to strengthen corporate governance by separating the roles of CEO and chairman. This separation represented a step into the unknown, because the CEO traditionally served as chairman in most US companies and was the board’s undisputed leader. The combined role of CEO and chairman is still very common, but the governance structure at most Fortune 100 companies<a href="#" class="link-footnote" onclick="return false;" rel="#footnote1"><sup>1</sup></a> <span style="display: none;" id="footnote1" class="tooltip"><span class="footnote-content"><span class="footnote-number">1.</span><span class="footnote-text"> According to <i>Agenda</i>’s 2009 board leadership guide, of the 96 Fortune 100 public companies included in the research, 43.8 percent had a presiding director and 37.5 percent a lead director. The most common governance structure in the largest US companies combined the positions of chairman and CEO and complemented this with a presiding director. For more, see <a href="http://agendaweek.com" target="_blank">agendaweek.com</a>. </span><span class="clear"></span></span><span class="footnote-bottom"></span></span>has now been complemented by a presiding or lead director, who plays a substantial role in leading the board’s work.</p>
<p>To examine how the new board leader role has evolved, and the best practices for appointing one, we invited 11 current and former board leaders of large US companies to share their views and experiences (see sidebar, “Who’s who”). One of their insights was that there is little difference in how their companies utilize the board leader whether the organization refers to that person as a presiding or lead director or as a nonexecutive chairman, although a few interviewees saw the latter title as having more importance symbolically. These board leaders spoke of a role that has grown beyond mandated process requirements, to carry a more substantive meaning for the creation of corporate value. At many leading companies today, the board leader is a real partner of the CEO on strategy issues and has taken over or partnered with the CEO on some functions the chief executive has historically led, such as setting board agendas, recruiting new directors, and more aggressively assessing risk.</p>
<!--roadblock-->
     <p>
    <details>
    <summary><strong>Who’s who</strong></summary>
    <figure>
      <table  cellspacing="0" cellpadding="1" border="1">
        <tr><td><table width="545" border="1" bordercolor="#000000"><tr><th style="padding:10px" VALIGN="top"><strong>Executive</strong></th><th style="padding:10px" VALIGN="top"><strong>Title</strong></th><th style="padding:10px" VALIGN="top"><strong>Company</strong></th></tr><tr><td style="padding:10px" VALIGN="top">James G. Cullen</td><td style="padding:10px" VALIGN="top">Nonexecutive chairman<br /><br />Lead director</td><td style="padding:10px" VALIGN="top">Agilent Technologies<br /><br />Johnson & Johnson</td></tr><tr><td style="padding:10px" VALIGN="top">David W. Dorman</td><td style="padding:10px" VALIGN="top">Nonexecutive chairman</td><td style="padding:10px" VALIGN="top">Motorola</td></tr><tr><td style="padding:10px" VALIGN="top">Bruce S. Gordon</td><td style="padding:10px" VALIGN="top">Lead director</td><td style="padding:10px" VALIGN="top">Tyco International</td></tr><tr><td style="padding:10px" VALIGN="top">James F. Hardymon</td><td style="padding:10px" VALIGN="top">Lead director</td><td style="padding:10px" VALIGN="top">WABCO Holdings</td></tr><tr><td style="padding:10px" VALIGN="top">Bonnie G. Hill</td><td style="padding:10px" VALIGN="top">Lead director</td><td style="padding:10px" VALIGN="top">Home Depot</td></tr><tr><td style="padding:10px" VALIGN="top">Irvine O. Hockaday Jr.</td><td style="padding:10px" VALIGN="top">Lead director</td><td style="padding:10px" VALIGN="top">Ford Motor</td></tr><tr><td style="padding:10px" VALIGN="top">Constance J. Horner</td><td style="padding:10px" VALIGN="top">Lead director</td><td style="padding:10px" VALIGN="top">Pfizer</td></tr><tr><td style="padding:10px" VALIGN="top">John A. “Jack” Krol</td><td style="padding:10px" VALIGN="top">Nonexecutive chairman<br /><br />Former lead director</td><td style="padding:10px" VALIGN="top">Delphi<br /><br />Tyco International
</td></tr><tr><td style="padding:10px" VALIGN="top">Linda Fayne Levinson</td><td style="padding:10px" VALIGN="top">Lead director</td><td style="padding:10px" VALIGN="top">NCR</td></tr><tr><td style="padding:10px" VALIGN="top">Harold A. “Hap” Wagner</td><td style="padding:10px" VALIGN="top">Former lead director</td><td style="padding:10px" VALIGN="top">United Technologies</td></tr><tr><td style="padding:10px" VALIGN="top">Tony L. White</td><td style="padding:10px" VALIGN="top">Former lead director</td><td style="padding:10px" VALIGN="top">Ingersoll-Rand</td></tr></table></td></tr>
      </table>
    </figure>
    </details></p>
    
<p>Our panel also noted how the process of selecting a board leader has been evolving from an unstructured and haphazard approach toward one that should ideally resemble the best practices for CEO succession. The board leaders we interviewed agreed, without exception, that good board succession planning starts with producing a formal document that specifies the duties and the personal characteristics the board leader should have, even though they may change over time. This document could also be used for evaluating the board leader from time to time.</p>
<p>Based on our interviews and experience of serving on corporate boards, we believe that the leader’s duties should ideally include chairing executive sessions, board meetings in the absence of the chairman (when the CEO has that role too), and meetings of the independent directors when necessary, as well as presiding over the board evaluation process to ensure that the board functions effectively. The duties should also involve frequent cooperation with the CEO in communicating with shareholders and external stakeholders, working with board committee chairmen (for example, on the CEO’s evaluation and compensation), and acting as a liaison between the board and management. What’s more, the board leader should ensure that a succession plan is in place for the CEO and the board leader, as well as work in partnership with the CEO on strategy issues.</p>
<p>Every one of the interviewees emphasized the need for close collaboration and trusted communication with the CEO and fellow directors to help the board navigate the challenges of a complex business environment and to focus boardroom discussions on strategy and overall value creation. Some interviewees discussed the need for the board leader to facilitate the evaluation of the board’s performance and, if needed, to deal with problem directors. Most interviewees believed that “firing a director” should be a process led by the board leader, based on peer- and/or self-assessments.</p>
<p>Given the focus on meetings and conversations, many directors in our panel stressed that the board leader must be a superb facilitator. “A skilled board leader can wring a lot out of these discussions,” said Jim Cullen, the lead director of Johnson & Johnson and nonexecutive chairman of Agilent Technologies. And this function “lies at the heart of what a board leader can bring to the governance process and to the successful strategic momentum of the business.” Doing one’s homework on the business is also key. “You have to stay current [and] understand the priorities of the business, the strategy, and the direction of the business, especially if you are going to have candid one-on-one discussions with the CEO,” Cullen said.</p>
<p>When Jack Krol became the lead director at Tyco International, in 2003, he developed, in conjunction with CEO Edward Breen, a document specifying his own role. With input from the board, the governance committee then developed some general characteristics of the role for whoever would succeed Krol in the future. Krol said three competencies or characteristics were deemed most critical.</p>
<p>First, Krol said, “the ideal candidate has to have stature with the other directors and be seen as a leader in the boardroom.” Krol also noted that “the ideal board leader is an engaged and thoughtful director. This candidate adds value during board deliberations, with significant comments when compared to others who may talk more but, over time, indicate a lack of substance”—adding that “you just know it when you see it.” Second, “the candidate must have compatibility with the CEO as well as good chemistry, and the person should not be adversarial.” Third, “the candidate must express interest and have the time to do the job.” Krol added, “at Tyco I was involved nearly every day for a year during the crisis, either at a company location or on the phone.” (Krol was referring to Tyco’s 2002 financial woes, which were compounded by accounting scandals involving its former CEO L. Dennis Kozlowski.) Indeed, many of the directors we interviewed underlined that boards should select leaders with the assumption that at some stage during their tenure, the company would be under some form of stress or in a crisis.</p>
<p>Advance planning and a well-vetted description of the role were essential when Krol recently handed over the reins as lead director to fellow Tyco International director Bruce Gordon. Krol, now nonexecutive chairman of Delphi, knew the stakes were high. If he and Tyco International’s board hadn’t found a successor capable of carrying on the dynamic created by the board and CEO Edward Breen, that failure might have unraveled years of progress in transforming the company’s governance in the eyes of shareholders and employees alike. The process was conducted over several months. The governance committee developed a list of three Tyco directors who best met the selection criteria and then conducted discussions, led by Krol, with each candidate and the CEO. Ultimately, an executive session of the board made the selection, based on the committee’s recommendation. The process, not unlike one that should be used to evaluate inside candidates for the job of CEO, enabled the board to engage in a thoughtful, well-paced process to arrive at the right answer.</p>
<p>The smooth succession at Tyco exemplifies best rather than common practice. Few of the companies in our sample had a formal specification for the board leader position when the time came to pass the baton, but all believed that such a specification should be created for the next “baton pass.” We find there is an increasing number of companies whose board leader says his or her board intends to develop a better profile of the ideal leader and then goes after the right candidate based on the formal specification rather than requiring candidates to compete with only nebulous criteria as their guide.</p>
<p>The old method of picking a successor wouldn’t stand up in today’s governance environment, noted Harold A. (“Hap”) Wagner, who was lead director at United Technologies for five years. Wagner recalls that when it was time for him to step down, in 2008, there was no document specifying the criteria for the selection of his successor. “Today, the position of lead director has been much more magnified,” he said. “I suspect that there is a specification now for lead director at UTC, and, if not, there should be.”</p>
<div class="articleBreak"></div>
<p>The board leader role has come a long way and is still evolving. What works best for one company may not necessarily fit another, because of varying degrees of business success, different cultures, and unique personal chemistry on the board. However, the common themes and recommendations uncovered by our research might help to shape the outlook of all boards when the time comes to pick a new board leader. </p>
<div class="about-authors">
<h3 class="sm black">About the authors</h3>
<p><strong>Dennis Carey</strong> is vice chairman of Korn/Ferry International, where <strong>John Keller</strong> is senior client partner. <strong>Michael Patsalos-Fox</strong> is a director in McKinsey’s New York office. </p>
<p>The authors wish to acknowledge the contributions to this article of Ram Charan, president of Charan Associates.</p>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Leading in the 21st century</title>
      <description>Six global leaders confront the personal and professional challenges of a new era of uncertainty.</description>
      <link>http://www.mckinsey.com/insights/leading_in_the_21st_century/copy_leading_in_the_21st_century</link>
      <guid>http://www.mckinsey.com/insights/leading_in_the_21st_century/copy_leading_in_the_21st_century</guid>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 Sep 2013 19:15:32 GMT</pubDate>
      <ID>0ae23f35-1e3c-472e-9290-e6cdd6aa2b6b</ID>
      <category>Leadership</category>
      <dc:creator><![CDATA[Dominic Barton, Andrew Grant, and  Michelle Horn]]></dc:creator>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><strong>It is often said</strong> that the principles of great leadership are timeless, or based on immutable truths. But when we meet with the men and women who run the world’s largest organizations, what we hear with increasing frequency is how different everything feels from just a decade ago. Leaders tell us they are operating in a bewildering new environment in which little is certain, the tempo is quicker, and the dynamics are more complex. They worry that it is impossible for chief executives to stay on top of all the things they need to know to do their job. Some admit they feel overwhelmed.</p>
<p>To understand the leadership challenge of our volatile, globalized, hyperconnected age more clearly, we recently initiated a series of structured interviews with the leaders of some of the world’s largest and most vibrant organizations. Excerpts from six of those conversations appear below. The leaders—Josef Ackermann, formerly of Deutsche Bank; Carlos Ghosn of Nissan and Renault; Moya Greene of Royal Mail Group; Ellen Kullman of DuPont; President Shimon Peres of Israel; and Daniel Vasella of Novartis (see sidebar, “Leaders on leadership”)—represent a diverse array of viewpoints. All are grappling with today’s environment in different ways. But the common themes that emerged from these conversations—what it means to lead in an age of upheaval, to master personal challenges, to be in the limelight continually, to make decisions under extreme uncertainty—offer a useful starting point for understanding today’s leadership landscape.</p>

     <p>
    <details>
    <summary><strong>Leaders on leadership</strong></summary>
    <figure>
      <table  cellspacing="0" cellpadding="1" border="1">
        <tr><td><h3>Meet the leaders</h3><p><img src='http://www.mckinsey.com/~/media/McKinsey/dotcom/Insights/Leadership/Leading in the 21st century/Spot_Ackermann.ashx' alt='Josef Ackermann'/></p><p><p><b>Josef Ackermann</b> is the former CEO and chairman of the management board at Deutsche Bank. He recently retired after a decade as CEO and six years as chairman.</p></p><p><img src='http://www.mckinsey.com/~/media/McKinsey/dotcom/Insights/Leadership/Leading in the 21st century/spot_Ghosn.ashx' alt='Carlos Ghosen'/></p><p><p><b>Carlos Ghosn</b> is the CEO and chairman of the Renault-Nissan Alliance. He has been the CEO of Nissan since 2001 and the CEO of Renault since 2005. Together, the two companies produce more than one in ten cars sold worldwide.</p></p><p><img src='http://www.mckinsey.com/~/media/McKinsey/dotcom/Insights/Leadership/Leading in the 21st century/spot_Greene.ashx' alt='Moya Greene'/></p><p><p><b>Moya Greene</b> was appointed CEO of the United Kingdom’s Royal Mail Group in 2010. From 2005 to 2010, she was CEO of Canada Post.</p></p><p><img src='http://www.mckinsey.com/~/media/McKinsey/dotcom/Insights/Leadership/Leading in the 21st century/spot_Kullman.ashx' alt='Ellen Kullman'/></p><p><p><b>Ellen Kullman</b> has served as DuPont’s CEO and board chair since 2009. She joined the company from General Electric in 1988 and was ranked fourth on the <i>Forbes</i> 100 Most Powerful Women list in 2011.</p></p><p><img src='http://www.mckinsey.com/~/media/McKinsey/dotcom/Insights/Leadership/Leading in the 21st century/spot_Peres.ashx' alt='Shimin Peres'/></p><p><p><b>Shimon Peres</b> is the ninth and current president of Israel. In a political career spanning more than 65 years, he has served twice as Israel’s prime minister and has been a member of 12 cabinets.</p></p><p><img src='http://www.mckinsey.com/~/media/McKinsey/dotcom/Insights/Leadership/Leading in the 21st century/spot_Vasella.ashx' alt='Daniel Vasella'/></p><p><p><b>Daniel Vasella</b> has been chairman of the Swiss pharmaceutical company Novartis AG since 1999. He served as the company’s CEO from 1996 to 2010. </p></p></td></tr>
      </table>
    </figure>
    </details></p>
    
<p>After presenting the ideas of these leaders on leadership, we offer a few additional reflections on the topic. They draw in part on the interviews, as well as on our experiences with clients; on conversations with dozens of experts in academia, government, and the private sector; and on our review of the extensive academic and popular literature on the subject. All reinforce our belief that today’s leaders face extraordinary new challenges and must learn to think differently about their role and how to fulfill it. Those who do may have an opportunity to change the world in ways their predecessors never imagined.</p>
<br />
<!--roadblock-->
<h3>Leading in an age of upheaval</h3>
<p><i>A convergence of forces is reshaping the global economy: emerging regions, such as Africa, Brazil, China, and India, have overtaken economies in the West as engines of global growth; the pace of innovation is increasing exponentially; new technologies have created new industries, disrupted old ones, and spawned communication networks of astonishing speed; and global emergencies seem to erupt at ever-shorter intervals. Any one of these developments would have profound implications for organizations and the people who lead them. Taken together, these forces are creating a new context for leadership.</i></p>
<p><strong>Josef Ackermann:</strong> We experienced a tremendous shift in the global balance of power, which manifests itself in our business. In the 1980s, over 80 percent of Deutsche Bank revenues were generated in Germany. In the mid-1990s, they still accounted for about 70 percent. Today, Germany, despite its continuing economic strength, stands for 38 percent of global revenues. Over the years, people in our headquarters, in Frankfurt, started complaining to me, “We don’t see you much around here anymore.” Well, there was a reason why: growth has moved elsewhere—to Asia, Latin America, the Middle East—and this of course had consequences on the time spent in each region.</p>
<p>Managing risk also has become much more complex for banks. It’s not only market risk; there is more and more political and social risk. Increasingly, financial markets are becoming political markets. That requires different skills—skills not all of us have acquired at university; how to properly deal with society, for example, a stakeholder that has immensely grown in importance since the financial crisis.</p>
<p><strong>Carlos Ghosn:</strong> I don’t think leadership shows unless it is highlighted by some kind of crisis. There are two kinds. There are internal crises that arise because a company has not been managed well. Then there are external crises, like the collapse of Lehman Brothers or the earthquake in Japan or the flood in Thailand. In that case, you are managing your company, and all of a sudden there is this thing falling on you.</p>
<p>Business schools may prepare people to deal with internal crises. But I think we need to be more prepared for external crises, where it’s not the strategy of the company that is in question; it’s the ability of leaders to figure out how to <i>adapt</i> that strategy.</p>
<p>We are going to have a lot more of these external crises because we are living in such a volatile world—an age where everything is leveraged and technology moves so fast. You can be rocked by something that originated completely outside your area.</p>
<p>I think one of the reasons Nissan has been able to cope with external crises better than some of our competitors is that we have a more diverse, multinational culture. We don’t just sit around waiting for the solution to come from headquarters. We are accustomed to always looking around, trying to find out who has the best ideas. Our people in the US talk to our people in Japan on an equal level. We have a lot more reference points.</p>
<p><strong>Ellen Kullman:</strong> These days, there are things that just come shooting across the bow—economic volatility and the impact of natural events like the Japanese earthquake and tsunami—at much greater frequency than we’ve ever seen. You have to be able to react very quickly. And the world is so connected that the feedback loops are more intense. You’ve got population growth and the world passing seven billion people last year, and the stresses that causes, whether it’s feeding the world, creating enough energy, or protecting the environment. We matched our focus, our research and development, and our capital expenditures up against megatrends like these over the last five years. This is the future, so we need to understand how our science relates to it.</p>
<p><strong>Shimon Peres:</strong> The last two decades have witnessed the greatest revolution since Genesis. States have lost their importance and strength. The old theories—from Adam Smith to Karl Marx—have lost their value because they are based on things like land, labor, and wealth. All of that has been replaced by science. Ideas are now more important than materials. And ideas are unpredictable. Science knows no customs, no borders. It doesn’t depend on distances or stop at a given point.</p>
<p>Science creates a world where individuals can play the role of the collective. Two boys create Google. One boy creates Facebook. Another individual creates Apple. These gentlemen changed the world without political parties or armies or fortunes. No one anticipated this. And they themselves did not know what would happen as a result of their thoughts. So we are all surprised. It is a new world. You may have the strongest army—but it cannot conquer ideas, it cannot conquer knowledge.</p>
<br />
<h3>Mastering today’s personal challenges</h3>
<p><i>The rigors of leadership have prompted many leaders to think of themselves as being in training, much like a professional athlete: continually striving to manage their energy and fortify their character. There is a growing recognition of the connection between physical health, emotional health, and judgment—and of how important it can be to have precise routines for diet, sleep, exercise, and staying centered.</i><a href="#" class="link-footnote" onclick="return false;" rel="#footnote1"><sup>1</sup></a> <span class="tooltip" id="footnote1" style="display: none;"><span class="footnote-content"><span class="footnote-number">1.</span><span class="footnote-text"> For more on centered leadership, see Joanna Barsh, Josephine Mogelof, and Caroline Webb, “<a href="http://www.mckinseyquarterly.com/article_page.aspx?ar=2678">How centered leaders achieve extraordinary results</a>,” mckinseyquarterly.com, October 2010. </span><span class="clear"></span></span><span class="footnote-bottom"></span></span></p>
<p><strong>Moya Greene:</strong> The first criterion is: do you love it? It’s a seven-day-a-week job. I think that’s true for anyone in these roles. If you don’t love the company and the people—<i>really</i> love them— you can’t do a job like this.</p>
<p>I’m pretty energetic. I start at five in the morning. I don’t even think about it anymore; the alarm goes off and I’m up. I go for a 30-minute run. I do weight training three mornings a week. I try to eat well, but not too much. I’m a big walker—that’s my favorite thing. I try to get a good walk every weekend. I go on walking vacations.</p>
<p>I’ve usually got three or four books on the go. I’ve given up on novels. I can’t get through them no matter how good they are; there’s no way I’ll finish before there’s some kind of interruption. So I read poetry now: the collected works of Ted Hughes, Emily Dickinson. I’m working my way through Philip Larkin. You can take a Larkin poem and read it on the bus in 15 minutes. The good ones stay with you and will come back to you. That’s what I like about poetry: you get a little shot of mental protein without a lot of time.</p>
<p><strong>Josef Ackermann:</strong> Just to give you an idea of my calendar for the next ten days: Berlin tomorrow, then Seoul, then Munich, then Frankfurt, then Singapore, then the Middle East. I’m almost constantly on a plane. With all this traveling, physical stamina has become much more important.</p>
<p>I remember a time when after flying to Hong Kong you could take a whole day off to recover. Today, right after landing you rush to your first meeting. And maybe you already have a conference call in the car on your way into town. You are lucky if you get enough time to take a shower.</p>
<p>And of course, with all the new information technology, you are constantly available, and the flow of information you have to manage is huge; that has added to the pressure. You are much more exposed to unforeseen shifts and negative surprises and you have to make quick decisions and respond to or anticipate market movements around the world. So you have to have a very stable psyche as well. I see more and more people these days who just burn out.</p>
<p>I’m not a tech freak. I use my iPhone and send text messages, that’s it. I still like to have paper in front of me and I do a lot in written-memo form. I think people who constantly use their BlackBerry or iPhone easily lose sight of the big picture.</p>
<p>It also helps me enormously that I can sleep anywhere, whether I am in a car or an airplane. If you’re unable to relax quickly, I think you can’t be a CEO for a considerable length of time. Some people do meditation or yoga. I don’t do any such thing. I think you have it in your DNA or you don’t.</p>
<p><strong>Dan Vasella:</strong> I talk to my team about the seductions that come with taking on a leadership role. There are many different forms: sexual seduction, money, praise. You need to be aware of how you can be seduced in order to be able to resist and keep your integrity.</p>
<p>Every CEO needs someone who can listen—a board member, an adviser—someone to whom he can speak in total confidence, to whom he can say, “I’ve had it; I’m about to resign.” Or, “I really want to beat this guy up.” You need someone who understands and can help you to find the balance. Leaders often forget the importance of stable emotional relationships—especially outside the company. It helps tremendously to manage stress. Your partner will do a lot to help keep you in sync.</p>
<p>You have to be able to switch on and switch off. Are you entirely present when you’re present? Can you be entirely away when you’re away? The expectation is that your job is 24/7. But no one can be the boss 24/7. You need to have a moment when you say, “I’m home now,” and work is gone.</p>
<p><strong>Carlos Ghosn:</strong> Leading takes a lot of stamina. I became CEO at 45. But I was working like a beast. You think, “So I work 15, 16 hours a day; who cares?” But you can’t do that when you are 60 or 65.</p>
<p>And now companies are more global. So you have jet lag, you are tired, the food is different. You have to be very disciplined about schedules and about organizing everything. Physical discipline is crucial, for food, exercise, sleep. I live like a monk—well, maybe not a monk, but a Knight Templar. I wake at a certain hour, sleep at a certain hour. There are certain things I won’t do past a certain time.</p>
<p><strong>Ellen Kullman:</strong> I spend a lot more time on communication, more time out at plant sites, in sales offices, with customers, in our research laboratories. I’m bringing my board of directors to India in a couple of weeks to help them really see the issues we’re facing. That’s where I get my energy from. It’s contagious. I come away from these engagements with ideas, energy, and a real sense of focus on where we as a company need to go. That’s part of what drives me.</p>
<p><strong>Shimon Peres:</strong> The mind of a leader must be free—a mind that can dream and imagine. All new things were born in dreams. A leader must have the courage to be a nonconformist, just like a scientist. He must dream, even if he dreams alone or if people laugh at him. He must not let his heart falter.</p>
<p>Today, the separation between generations is stronger than between nations. Our children say, “Please don’t impose upon us your own arrogance—the world you created, wounded by war, corrupted by money, separated by hatred. And don’t try to build artificial walls between us and other youngsters.” Because they were born in a new age. For them, the modern equipment of communication is what paper and pen are for us. They can communicate much more easily and don’t feel all this hidden discrimination that we were born with and find so difficult to get rid of.</p>
<h3>The (now 24/7) public face of leadership</h3>
<p><i>Nearly everyone we spoke with commented on the challenge of dealing with constant scrutiny and of acting as a connector in a complex ecosystem. As the face of the organization, leaders must be prepared to address the immediate, practical concerns of the job while also maintaining and articulating a long-term vision of the organization’s purpose and role in society—all against a backdrop of 24-hour financial coverage, ubiquitous blogs, and Twitter feeds. That means learning new modes of communicating across today’s far-flung networks and working harder to craft clear, simple messages that resonate across cultures.</i></p>
<p><strong>Josef Ackermann:</strong> CEOs have become highly public figures. And media scrutiny has become very personal. Particularly in our home market, Germany, it’s always, “Ackermann says this” or “Ackermann’s doing that”—even if I personally had nothing to do with it. You are the institution you lead.</p>
<p>After I became CEO, the former head of the Bundesbank one day took me aside and gave me some valuable advice: “From now on, you must remember that you are two people. You are the person whom you and your friends know, but you are also a symbol for something. Never confuse the two. Don’t take criticism of the symbol as criticism of the person.” That advice has helped me a lot.</p>
<p><strong>Dan Vasella:</strong> People have a legitimate demand for access to the CEO. But you have to modulate that so you avoid overexposure. You’re a product. And the press will paint you as either a hero or a villain—whatever sells. If they paint you as a hero today, you should be prepared to be painted as a villain tomorrow. Not everything you do will work out every time, and you have to accept that people will be unfair.</p>
<p><strong>Moya Greene:</strong> A decade ago, I’d have said that it was harder to be a public official than an executive in the private sector. But the tables have turned. It’s tough these days to be the CEO of any business—even a very successful one with a balanced view of the corporation’s position in society.</p>
<p>My public-sector experience has helped me to understand how easily sound policies can be derailed by small, symbolic things. It may not matter that the policy change you are advocating is the product of fantastic analytics or years of brilliant stakeholder management; the tiniest little spark can become a flash fire—something that takes hold and transforms perceptions in ways that don’t seem rational. If you work in the public sector, you learn the value of developing antennae for popular perceptions and keeping them finely tuned.</p>
<p>I spend about 15 percent of my time trying to help our own people understand how good we are at what we do, which isn’t always easy, because there is so much negativism in the press. I see good internal communications as a way to punch through and get our message out, to tell our people—who are the most powerful ambassadors for our brand—“Stand up and be proud.”</p>
<p><strong>Carlos Ghosn:</strong> In business, there are no more heroes. The media has become a lot more negative about corporate leaders over the past ten years. Small mistakes get blown up into huge things.</p>
<p>I cannot imagine myself today doing what I did in Japan in 1999, when I stood up and said: “We’re going to get rid of the seniority system. We’re going to shut down plants. We’re going to reduce headcount. We’re going to undo the keiretsu system.” I had a lot of criticism. But there were also people who said, “Let’s give him the benefit of the doubt.” Today, if I were to stand up and try to do something like that, I would get massacred. I would need much more emotional stability and certainty. Leaders of tomorrow are going to have to be incredibly secure and sure of themselves.</p>
<p>Leaders of the future will also need to have a lot more empathy and sensitivity—not just for people from their own countries but for people from completely different countries and cultures. They are going to need global empathy, which is a lot more difficult.</p>
<p><strong>Shimon Peres:</strong> Words are the connection between leaders and the public. They must be credible and clear and reflect a vision, not just a position. The three greatest leaders of the 20th century were Winston Churchill, Charles de Gaulle, and David Ben-Gurion. Each had a brilliant mind and a brilliant pen. Their ability with a pen demonstrated many things: curiosity, memory, courage. They understood that you lead not with bayonets but with words. A leader’s words must be precise and totally committed.</p>
<br />
<h3>Decision making under uncertainty</h3>
<p><i>A final theme is that leaders must increasingly resist the temptation to cope with chaos and complexity by trusting their gut. At a time of extreme volatility, past experience is an unreliable guide to future outcomes. Leaders must create cultures of constructive skepticism and surround themselves with people who bring multiple perspectives and have no fear of challenging the boss.</i></p>
<p><strong>Carlos Ghosn:</strong> It is a paradox: on the one hand, you have to be more confident and secure, but on the other, you have to be a lot more open and empathetic. You need to listen, but then when you make a decision, that’s it—you must be a very hard driver. Usually, these are not attributes you find in the same person.</p>
<p>Once you have done the analysis and made the decision, then you have to learn to simplify the decision in communicating it to others. Everything’s complex, but once you have decided, sometimes you need to simplify so much it’s almost a caricature. You must say, “Nothing matters beyond this.” You must reduce everything to zeros or ones, black or white, go or no-go. You can’t have too much nuance.</p>
<p>In a crisis, you have to be able to do all of these things—listening, deciding, and then simplifying—very quickly. That is what makes leading in a crisis so interesting. And because you have to move so fast, you have to empower people to make decisions themselves. That’s the best way to restore calm.</p>
<p><strong>Moya Greene:</strong> When I came here, we were running out of cash. I was grappling with decisions that would determine whether or not we could stay in business. But you cannot position your company in the broader social and economic fabric of the nation if all you do is look at the financial dimensions of performance. You have to look at what your customers think, what your employees think, and what you can do for your customers.</p>
<p><strong>Daniel Vasella:</strong> As a leader, to whom can you express your doubts—and should you? In which situation is it appropriate and when not? I believe that you have to be able to express doubt in your team and with a board. If you don’t—and you pretend—then you are playing a role, which eventually leads to an unhealthy situation. That’s not to say you should act like you’re in a confessional. At some point [in decision making], you have to take the sword and cut through the Gordian knot and make a decision, despite any uncertainties.</p>
<p>But the question is: are you being led by the context or do you lead? Are you being led by your followers and are they choosing for you? Or do you choose and do you lead? I think you have to be aware of the context, and what people expect and hope for. But as a leader, you’re not there to feed people with all the things they hope for. Your job is to persuade people to do the things you believe will be the right direction for the long term. People want you to lead. And if you lead, you will hurt. You will satisfy sometimes. You will celebrate and you will blame. That’s all part of your job.</p>
<p><strong>Josef Ackermann:</strong> Problems have become so complex today that you have to collect the expertise and opinions of a lot of people before you can make a sound decision. Some people say, “Don’t decide until you have to.” I have a completely different view. I hate to be under time pressure. I think it is important that you aren’t confronted with a situation where you haven’t heard anything on a particular issue for half a year—and then suddenly you have to make a quick decision on the basis of an executive summary.</p>
<p>I believe in personal leadership, but no CEO can do it all on his own. You need the expertise, judgment, and buy-in of your team.</p>
<br />
<br />
<div class="articleBreak"></div>
<h3>Preparing for a new era of leadership</h3>
<p>It’s never been realistic to break leadership into a fixed set of essential competences, and that’s particularly the case in today’s complex, volatile environment. Still, the themes our interviewees sounded represent a rich set of opportunities for leaders to boost their effectiveness. To close, we’d like to amplify and extend those themes by emphasizing three skills that can help leaders thrive in today’s turbulent environment, which for many has prompted a reexamination of fundamental assumptions about how they do their jobs, while underscoring the importance of leading with a purpose. Resilient leaders, as Shimon Peres reminded us, are those who have “ambition for a cause greater than themselves.”</p>
<h3>1. See with a microscope and a telescope</h3>
<p>Over the next two decades, McKinsey research suggests, the conditions of the late 20th century—cheap capital, low interest rates, a global demographic dividend, and a gradual decline in commodity prices—will either be reversed or seesaw violently. Managing the immediacy of these changes, while also staying alert for the inflection points that signal bigger, long-term “trend breaks,” will require leaders to see the world in multiple ways at once.</p>
<p>In different ways, many leaders have told us they’ve needed to develop a facility for viewing the world through two lenses: a telescope, to consider opportunities far into the future, and a microscope, to scrutinize challenges of the moment at intense magnification. Most of us are naturally more comfortable with one lens or the other; we are “farsighted” or “nearsighted,” but rarely both. In times of complexity, leaders must be able to see clearly through either lens and to manage the shift between the two with speed and ease.</p>
<p>Leaders must use the telescope to watch for long-term trends, dream big dreams, imagine where a company should be in five or ten years, and reallocate resources accordingly. The accelerating pace of technological innovation makes this aspect of a leader’s role more important than ever. The microscope, too, affords a critical perspective. Leaders must force their organizations to challenge conventional wisdom; consider the implications of unlikely, “long-tail” scenarios; and focus on pressing issues in minute detail. As organizations grow larger and more complex, leaders must work harder to stay in touch with the front line and view themselves as “chief reality testers.”</p>
<h3>2. Compete as a tri-sector athlete</h3>
<p>Many of the forces buffeting leaders in the private sector—slow growth, unemployment, sovereign indebtedness—can be addressed only in concert with the public sector and are heavily influenced by the actions of groups that are neither commercial nor governmental entities. When governments play an ever more active role in regulating markets, and social movements can spring up in a matter of days, corporate leaders must be nimble “tri-sector athletes,” to borrow a phrase from Harvard political scientist Joseph Nye: able to engage and collaborate across the private, public, and social sectors. Leaders of governments and nongovernmental organizations must likewise break out of their silos. Issues such as infrastructure, unemployment, education, or protecting the environment are too complex and interrelated to deal with in isolation. Many of the leaders with whom we spoke said they have learned the value of examining their business decisions in a social and political context. Even those wary of open-ended discussions about corporate social responsibility say they find it useful to think about managing a “triple bottom line” that reflects their organizations’ performance in the public, private, and social spheres.</p>
<h3>3. Stay grounded during a crisis </h3>
<p>Everyone we interviewed agreed that modern leaders spend far more of their time firefighting than their predecessors did. Coping with externally generated crises, many argued, has become a key part of the modern leader’s role. In an age when crisis is the new normal, global organizations need leaders who are able to act quickly and calmly amid chaos. Many leaders highlighted the value of “stress-testing” members of the top team to gauge their ability to cope with crisis. We heard again and again that otherwise competent managers can’t always perform in moments of extraordinary pressure. The chief executive of one of the world’s largest companies marveled at how, in the face of a cash flow crisis following the collapse of Lehman Brothers, two of his top reports “shattered like glass.”</p>
<p>The emotional and physical stamina demanded of leaders today is extraordinary. Many of those we interviewed reserve crucial decisions for moments when they know they will be rested and free from distraction. They also talked about sequencing decisions to focus on key issues first, not after they have been depleted by lesser matters. We are intrigued by the growing body of research in psychology, sociology, and neuroscience that highlights the importance of “decision fatigue.” The implication of this research is that trying to make too many decisions at once diminishes the ability to make wise decisions at all.</p>
<div class="articleBreak"></div>
<p>If the burden of leadership in the modern age seems overwhelming, the potential benefits are overwhelming too. Large organizations— if led well—can do more for more people than they have at any other moment in history. That is the flip side of all the chaos, complexity, and pressure, and it makes leading through those challenges a noble endeavor.</p>
<div class="about-authors">
<h3 class="sm black">About the authors</h3>
<p><b>Dominic Barton</b> is McKinsey’s global managing director, <b>Andrew Grant</b> is a director in McKinsey’s Singapore office, and <b>Michelle Horn</b> is a principal in the Atlanta office.</p>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A CEO’s guide to innovation in China in master</title>
      <description>Dynamic domestic players and focused multinationals are helping China churn out a growing number of innovative products and services. Intensifying competition lies ahead; here’s a road map for navigating it.</description>
      <link>http://www.mckinsey.com/insights/asia-pacific/copy_ceos_guide_to_innovation_in_china_1</link>
      <guid>http://www.mckinsey.com/insights/asia-pacific/copy_ceos_guide_to_innovation_in_china_1</guid>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 Sep 2013 19:14:29 GMT</pubDate>
      <ID>2abc4c3f-176e-4fe0-8b9a-94dc3ca7383e</ID>
      <category>Asia-Pacific</category>
      <dc:creator><![CDATA[Gordon Orr and Erik Roth]]></dc:creator>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><strong>China is innovating.</strong> Some of its achievements are visible: a doubling of the global percentage of patents granted to Chinese inventors since 2005, for example, and the growing role of Chinese companies in the wind- and solar-power industries. Other developments—such as advances by local companies in domestically oriented consumer electronics, instant messaging, and online gaming—may well be escaping the notice of executives who aren’t on the ground in China.</p>
<p>As innovation gains steam there, the stakes are rising for domestic and multinational companies alike. Prowess in innovation will not only become an increasingly important differentiator inside China but should also yield ideas and products that become serious competitors on the international stage.</p>
<!--roadblock-->
<p>Chinese companies and multinationals bring different strengths and weaknesses to this competition. The Chinese have traditionally had a bias toward innovation through commercialization—they are more comfortable than many Western companies are with putting a new product or service into the market quickly and improving its performance through subsequent generations. It is common for products to launch in a fraction of the time that it would take in more developed markets. While the quality of these early versions may be variable, subsequent ones improve rapidly.<a href="#" class="link-footnote" onclick="return false;" rel="#footnote1"><sup>1</sup></a> <span class="tooltip" id="footnote1" style="display: none;"><span class="footnote-content"><span class="footnote-number">1.</span><span class="footnote-text"> Commercialization differs from <i>shanzhai</i>, or “copycat innovation.” Many executives in the developed world misunderstand <i>shanzhai</i>, believing that it is purely the replication of an innovation developed in another market. Although this does occur, products developed through the <i>shanzhai</i> approach incorporate features specifically for the Chinese market. <i>Shanzhai</i> is quite prevalent in consumer products categories such as packaged goods and electronics. It can also be found in the business-to-business domain, where local companies produce knockoffs of successful foreign products or business models. </span><span class="clear"></span></span><span class="footnote-bottom"></span></span></p>
<p>Chinese companies also benefit from their government’s emphasis on indigenous innovation, underlined in the latest five-year plan. Chinese authorities view innovation as critical both to the domestic economy’s long-term health and to the global competitiveness of Chinese companies. China has already created the seeds of 22 Silicon Valley–like innovation hubs within the life sciences and biotech industries. In semiconductors, the government has been consolidating innovation clusters to create centers of manufacturing excellence.</p>
<p>But progress isn’t uniform across industries, and innovation capabilities vary significantly: several basic skills are at best nascent within a typical Chinese enterprise. Pain points include an absence of advanced techniques for understanding—analytically, not just intuitively—what customers really want, corporate cultures that don’t support risk taking, and a scarcity of the sort of internal collaboration that’s essential for developing new ideas.</p>

     <p>
    <details>
    <summary><strong>Improving the patent process</strong></summary>
    <figure>
      <table  cellspacing="0" cellpadding="1" border="1">
        <tr><td><p>
In innovative sectors such as biotechnology, electric vehicles, pharmaceuticals, and solar energy, the number of patent applications from Chinese companies is rising. In fact, Huawei and ZTE ranked among the world’s top five corporate patent registrants by volume in 2010. Intensifying patent activity reflects a growing recognition that intellectual property is essential to value. As this mentality takes hold, domestic innovators may pressure the government to create a more modern intellectual-property system.</p><p>
Currently, China recognizes three categories of patents: invention (what most people elsewhere think of as worthy of a patent), utility (a new use for something that already exists), and design. Invention patents run for 20 years, the others only for 10. Patent reform—such as reducing the duration of design or utility patents and raising the bar for what can be registered in those categories—would be a powerful way for the Chinese government to signal its seriousness about promoting indigenous innovation. If China decides to move ahead with patent reform, a desire for global consistency could well make it a high-priority multilateral issue.</p><p>Without patent reform, companies must rely on one of two strategies for protecting intellectual property. The first is to continue to outrun the competition by developing increasingly innovative solutions or building in protection through complex integration that is difficult to reverse-engineer. The second is to create easily identifiable technology “signatures” that would be hard to refute in legal proceedings.</p></td></tr>
      </table>
    </figure>
    </details></p>
    
<p>Multinationals are far stronger in these areas but face other challenges, such as high attrition among talented Chinese nationals that can slow efforts to create local innovation centers. Indeed, the contrasting capabilities of domestic and multinational players, along with the still-unsettled state of intellectual-property protection (see sidebar, “Improving the patent process”), create the potential for topsy-turvy competition, creative partnerships, and rapid change. This article seeks to lay out the current landscape for would-be innovators and to describe some of the priorities for domestic and multinational companies that hope to thrive in it.</p>
<h3>China’s innovation landscape</h3>
<p>Considerable innovation is occurring in China in both the business- to-consumer and business-to-business sectors. Although breakthroughs in either space generally go unrecognized by the broader global public, many multinational B2B competitors are acutely aware of the innovative strides the Chinese are making in sectors such as communications equipment and alternative energy. Interestingly, even as multinationals struggle to cope with Chinese innovation in some areas, they seem to be holding their own in others.</p>
<h3 class="sm black">The business-to-consumer visibility gap</h3>
<p>When European and US consumers think about what China makes, they reflexively turn to basic items such as textiles and toys, not necessarily the most innovative products and rarely associated with brand names.</p>
<p>In fact, though, much product innovation in China stays there. A visit to a shop of the Suning Appliance chain, the large Chinese consumer electronics retailer, is telling. There, you might find an Android-enabled television complete with an integrated Internet-browsing capability and preloaded apps that take users straight to some of the most popular Chinese Web sites and digital movie-streaming services. Even the picture quality and industrial design are comparable to those of high-end televisions from South Korean competitors.</p>
<p>We observe the same home-grown innovation in business models. Look, for example, at the online sector, especially Tencent’s QQ instant-messaging service and the Sina Corporation’s microblog, Weibo. These models, unique to China, are generating revenue and growing in ways that have not been duplicated anywhere in the world. QQ’s low, flat-rate pricing and active marketplace for online games generate tremendous value from hundreds of millions of Chinese users.</p>
<p>What’s keeping innovative products and business models confined to China? In general, its market is so large that domestic companies have little incentive to adapt successful products for sale abroad. In many cases, the skills and capabilities of these companies are oriented toward the domestic market, so even if they want to expand globally, they face high hurdles. Many senior executives, for example, are uncomfortable doing business outside their own geography and language. Furthermore, the success of many Chinese models depends on local resources—for example, lower-cost labor, inexpensive land, and access to capital or intellectual property—that are difficult to replicate elsewhere. Take the case of mobile handsets: most Chinese manufacturers would be subject to significant intellectual property–driven licensing fees if they sold their products outside China.</p>
<h3 class="sm black">Successes in business to business</h3>
<p>Several Chinese B2B sectors are establishing a track record of innovation domestically and globally. The Chinese communications equipment industry, for instance, is a peer of developed-world companies in quality. Market acceptance has expanded well beyond the historical presence in emerging markets to include Europe’s most demanding customers, such as France Télécom and Vodafone.</p>
<p>Pharmaceuticals are another area where China has made big strides. In the 1980s and 1990s, the country was a bit player in the discovery of new chemical entities. By the next decade, however, China’s sophistication had grown dramatically. More than 20 chemical compounds discovered and developed in China are currently undergoing clinical trials.</p>
<img alt="China solar-cell factory" src="~/media/McKinsey/dotcom/Insights/Asia-Pacific/A CEOs guide to innovation in China/solar-cell.ashx?mw=510">
<p class="grayNote small">Workers produce solar-cell modules in a factory in China’s Jiangsu Province.<br>© Imaginechina/Corbis</p>
<p>China’s solar- and wind-power industries are also taking center stage. The country will become the world’s largest market for renewable-energy technology, and it already has some of the sector’s biggest companies, providing critical components for the industry globally. Chinese companies not only enjoy scale advantages but also, in the case of solar, use new manufacturing techniques to improve the efficiency of solar panels.</p>
<p>Success in B2B innovation has benefited greatly from friendly government policies, such as establishing market access barriers; influencing the nature of cross-border collaborations by setting intellectual-property requirements in electric vehicles, high-speed trains, and other segments; and creating domestic-purchasing policies that favor Chinese-made goods and services. Many view these policies as loading the dice in favor of Chinese companies, but multinationals should be prepared for their continued enforcement.</p>
<img alt="Wind Turbine" src="~/media/McKinsey/dotcom/Insights/Asia-Pacific/A CEOs guide to innovation in China/turbine.ashx?mw=510">
<p class="grayNote small">Wind turbine manufacturing in China’s Shandong Province.<br>
© Guo Xulei/Xinhua Press/Corbis</p>
<p>Despite recent setbacks, an interesting example of how the Chinese government has moved to build an industry comes from high-speed rail. Before 2004, China’s efforts to develop it had limited success. Since then, a mix of two policies—encouraging technology transfer from multinationals (in return for market access) and a coordinated R&D-investment effort—has helped China Railways’ high-speed trains to dominate the local industry. The multinationals’ revenue in this sector has remained largely unchanged since the early 2000s.</p>
<p>But it is too simplistic to claim that government support is the only reason China has had some B2B success. The strength of the country’s scientific and technical talent is growing, and local companies increasingly bring real capabilities to the table. What’s more, a number of government-supported innovation efforts have <i>not</i> been successful. Some notable examples include attempts to develop an indigenous 3G telecommunications protocol called TDS-CDMA and to replace the global Wi-Fi standard with a China-only Internet security protocol, WAPI.</p>
<h3 class="sm black">Advantage, multinationals?</h3>
<p>Simultaneously, multinationals have been shaping China’s innovation landscape by leveraging global assets. Consider, for example, the joint venture between General Motors and the Shanghai Automotive Industry Corporation, which adapted a US minivan (Buick’s GL8) for use in the Chinese market and more recently introduced a version developed in China, for China. The model has proved hugely popular among executives.</p>
<p>In fact, the market for vehicles powered by internal-combustion engines remains dominated by multinationals, despite significant incentives and encouragement from the Chinese government, which had hoped that some domestic automakers would emerge as leaders by now. The continued strength of multinationals indicates how hard it is to break through in industries with 40 or 50 years of intellectual capital. Transferring the skills needed to design and manufacture complex engineering systems has proved a significant challenge requiring mentorship, the right culture, and time.</p>
<p>We are seeing the emergence of similar challenges in electric vehicles, where early indications suggest that the balance is swinging toward the multinationals because of superior product quality. By relying less on purely indigenous innovation, China is trying to make sure the electric-vehicle story has an ending different from that of its telecommunications protocol efforts. The government’s stated aspiration of having more than five million plug-in hybrid and battery electric vehicles on the road by 2020 is heavily supported by a mix of extensive subsidies and tax incentives for local companies, combined with strict market access rules for foreign companies and the creation of new revenue pools through government and public fleet-purchase programs. But the subsidies and incentives may not be enough to overcome the technical challenges of learning to build these vehicles, particularly if multinationals decline to invest with local companies.</p>
<h3>Four priorities for innovators in China</h3>
<p>There’s no magic formula for innovation—and that goes doubly for China, where the challenges and opportunities facing domestic and multinational players are so different. Some of the priorities we describe here, such as instilling a culture of risk taking and learning, are more pressing for Chinese companies. Others, such as retaining local talent, may be harder for multinationals. Collectively, these priorities include some of the critical variables that will influence which companies lead China’s innovation revolution and how far it goes.</p>
<img alt="China high-speed train" src="~/media/McKinsey/dotcom/Insights/Asia-Pacific/A CEOs guide to innovation in China/ChinaTrain.ashx?mw=510">
<p class="grayNote small">A Chinese-built high-speed train at the Wuhan Railway Station, in Wuhan, China.<br>© Guo Xulei/Xinhua Press/Corbis</p><h3 class="sm black">Deeply understanding Chinese customers</h3>
<p>Alibaba’s Web-based trading platform, Taobao, is a great example of a product that emerged from deep insights into how customers were underserved and their inability to connect with suppliers, as well as a sophisticated understanding of the Chinese banking system. This dominant marketplace enables thousands of Chinese manufacturers to find and transact with potential customers directly. What looks like a straightforward eBay-like trading platform actually embeds numerous significant innovations to support these transactions, such as an ability to facilitate electronic fund transfers and to account for idiosyncrasies in the national banking system. Taobao wouldn’t have happened without Alibaba’s deep, analytically driven understanding of customers.</p>
<p>Few Chinese companies have the systematic ability to develop a deep understanding of customers’ problems. Domestic players have traditionally had a manufacturing-led focus on reapplying existing business models to deliver products for fast-growing markets. These “push” models will find it increasingly hard to unlock pockets of profitable growth. Shifting from delivery to creation requires more local research and development, as well as the nurturing of more market-driven organizations that can combine insights into detailed Chinese customer preferences with a clear sense of how the local business environment is evolving. Requirements include both research techniques relevant to China and people with the experience to draw out actionable customer insights.</p>
<p>Many multinationals have these capabilities, but unless they have been operating in China for some years, they may well lack the domestic-market knowledge or relationships needed to apply them effectively. The solution—building a true domestic Chinese presence rather than an outpost—sounds obvious, but it’s difficult to carry out without commitment from the top. Too many companies fail by using “fly over” management. But some multinationals appear to be investing the necessary resources; for example, we recently met (separately) with top executives of two big industrial companies who were being transferred from the West to run global R&D organizations from Shanghai. The idea is to be closer to Chinese customers and the network of institutions and universities from which multinationals source talent.</p>
<h3 class="sm black">Retaining local talent</h3>
<p>China’s universities graduate more than 10,000 science PhDs each year, and increasing numbers of Chinese scientists working overseas are returning home. Multinationals in particular are struggling to tap this inflow of researchers and managers. A recent survey by the executive-recruiting firm Heidrick & Struggles found that 77 percent of the senior executives from multinational companies responding say they have difficulty attracting managers in China, while 91 percent regard employee turnover as their top talent challenge.</p>
<p>Retention is more of an issue for multinationals than for domestic companies, but as big foreign players raise their game, so must local ones. Chinese companies, for example, excel at creating a community-like environment to build loyalty to the institution. That helps keep some employees in place when competing offers arise, but it may not always be enough.</p>
<p>Talented Chinese employees increasingly recognize the benefits of being associated with a well-known foreign brand and like the mentorship and training that foreign companies can provide. So multinationals that commit themselves to developing meaningful career paths for Chinese employees should have a chance in the growing fight with their Chinese competitors for R&D talent. Initiatives might include in-house training courses or apprenticeship programs, perhaps with local universities. General Motors sponsors projects in which professors and engineering departments at leading universities research issues of interest to the automaker. That helps it to develop closer relations with the institutions from which it recruits and to train students before they graduate.</p>
<p>Some multinationals energize Chinese engineers by shifting their roles from serving as capacity in a support of existing global programs to contributing significantly to new innovation thrusts, often aimed at the local market. This approach, increasingly common in the pharma industry, may hold lessons for other kinds of multinationals that have established R&D or innovation centers in China in recent years (read about AstraZeneca’s experience in “Three snapshots of Chinese innovation”). The keys to success include a clear objective— for instance, will activity support global programs or develop China-for-China innovations?—and a clear plan for attracting and retaining the talent needed to staff such centers. Too often, we visit impressive R&D facilities, stocked with the latest equipment, that are almost empty because staffing them has proved difficult.</p>
<h3 class="sm black">Instilling a culture of risk taking</h3>
<p>Failure is a required element of innovation, but it isn’t the norm in China, where a culture of obedience and adherence to rules prevails in most companies. Breaking or even bending them is not expected and rarely tolerated. To combat these attitudes, companies must find ways to make initiative taking more acceptable and better rewarded.</p>
<p>One approach we found, in a leading solar company, was to transfer risk from individual innovators to teams. Shared accountability and community support made increased risk taking and experimentation safer. The company has used these “innovation work groups” to develop everything from more efficient battery technology to new manufacturing processes. Team-based approaches also have proved effective for some multinationals trying to stimulate initiative taking (read about General Motors’ approach in “Three snapshots of Chinese innovation”).</p>
<p>How fast a culture of innovation takes off varies by industry. We see a much more rapid evolution toward the approach of Western companies in the way Chinese high-tech enterprises learn from their customers and how they apply that learning to create new products made for China (read a perspective on the evolution of its semiconductor sector in “Thee snapshots of Chinese innovation”). That approach is much less common at state-owned enterprises, since they are held back by hierarchical, benchmark-driven cultures.</p>
<h3 class="sm black">Promoting collaboration</h3>
<p>One area where multinationals currently have an edge is promoting collaboration and the internal collision of ideas, which can yield surprising new insights and business opportunities. In many Chinese companies, traditional organizational and cultural barriers inhibit such exchanges.</p>
<p>Although a lot of these companies have become more professional and adept at delivering products in large volumes, their ability to scale up an organization that can work collaboratively has not kept pace. Their rigorous, linear processes for bringing new products to market ensure rapid commercialization but create too many hand-offs where insights are lost and trade-offs for efficiency are promoted.</p>
<p>One Chinese consumer electronics company has repeatedly tried to improve the way it innovates. Senior management has called for new ideas and sponsored efforts to create new best-in-class processes, while junior engineers have designed high-quality prototypes. Yet the end result continues to be largely undifferentiated, incremental improvements. The biggest reason appears to be a lack of cross-company collaboration and a reliance on processes designed to build and reinforce scale in manufacturing. In effect, the technical and commercial sides of the business don’t cooperate in a way that would allow some potentially winning ideas to reach the market. As Chinese organizations mature, stories like this one may become rarer.</p>
<div class="articleBreak"></div>
<p>China hasn’t yet experienced a true innovation revolution. It will need time to evolve from a country of incremental innovation based on technology transfers to one where breakthrough innovation is common. The government will play a powerful role in that process, but ultimately it will be the actions of domestic companies and multinationals that dictate the pace of change—and determine who leads it.</p>
<div class="about-authors">
<h3 class="sm black">About the authors</h3>
<p><b>Gordon Orr</b> is a director in McKinsey’s Shanghai office, where <b>Erik Roth</b> is a principal.</p>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Another oil shock?</title>
      <description>It’s possible, though far from certain, that oil prices will spike in the years ahead. Here’s why—and how you can prepare.
</description>
      <link>http://www.mckinsey.com/insights/energy_resources_materials/copy_another_oil_shock</link>
      <guid>http://www.mckinsey.com/insights/energy_resources_materials/copy_another_oil_shock</guid>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 Sep 2013 19:13:58 GMT</pubDate>
      <ID>a79dcdad-7009-43bb-9791-314a56c9c7ea</ID>
      <category>Energy, Resources &amp; Materials</category>
      <dc:creator><![CDATA[Tom Janssens, Scott Nyquist, and Occo Roelofsen]]></dc:creator>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><strong>It’s been a while</strong> since the world has been truly preoccupied with the threat of sustained high oil prices. The global economic recovery has been muted, and a double-dip recession remains possible.</p>
<p>But that dour prospect shouldn’t make executives sanguine about the risk of another oil shock. Emerging markets are still in the midst of a historic transition toward greater energy consumption. When global economic performance becomes more robust, oil demand is likely to grow faster than supply capacity can. As that happens, at some point before too long supply and demand could collide—gently or ferociously.</p>
<p>The case for the benign scenario rests on a steady evolution away from oil consumption in areas such as transportation, chemical production, power, and home heating. Moves by many major economies to impose tougher automotive fuel efficiency standards are a step in this direction. However, fully achieving the needed transition will take more stringent regulation, such as the abolition of fuel subsidies in oil-producing countries, Asia, and elsewhere, as well as widespread consumer behavior changes. And historically, governments, companies, and consumers have been disinclined to tackle tough policy choices or make big changes until their backs are against the wall. </p>
<!--roadblock-->
<p>This inertia suggests another scenario—one that’s sufficiently plausible and underappreciated that we think it’s worth exploring: the prospect that within this decade, the world could experience a period of significant volatility, with oil prices leaping upward and oscillating between $125 and $175 a barrel (or higher) for some time. The resulting economic pain would be significant. Economic modeling by our colleagues suggests that by 2020, global GDP would be about $1.5 trillion smaller than expected, if oil prices spiked and stayed high for several years. </p>
<p>But like any difficult transition, this one also would create major opportunities—for consumers of energy to differentiate their cost structures from competitors that aren’t prepared and for a host of energy innovators to create substitutes for oil and tap into new sources of supply. Furthermore, if we endured a period of high and volatile prices that lasted for two or three years, by 2020 or so oil could face real competition from other energy sources. </p>

     <p>
    <details>
    <summary><strong>The automotive sector’s road to greater fuel efficiency</strong></summary>
    <figure>
      <table  cellspacing="0" cellpadding="1" border="1">
        <tr><td><p><b>Russel Hensley and Andreas Zielke</b></p><p><strong>Regulatory standards already in place</strong> should dramatically enhance the efficiency of autos around the world. The European Union’s carbon emissions rules, for example, require annual improvements of 6 percent a year between 2015 and 2020. This implies, according to our analysis, that new cars driving on European roads will consume 40 to 50 percent less fuel in 2020 than they did in 2010. Regulators in China, Japan, and the United States are also eyeing ambitious rates of improvement, albeit from different starting points. US fuel economy levels in 2020—at around 40 miles a gallon—would lag behind China’s in that year and simply match Europe’s 2010 levels. </p><p>
The automotive industry, boxed in by fierce global competition and flat prices, has responded in the past by pushing design improvements and productivity gains that make room for costly new content, including technology required for meeting regulatory standards. Here’s one example: if you adjust for inflation the cost of a 2001 Toyota Camry, you see that by 2010, the price of the car to US consumers had actually dropped by $2,500 in real terms—although the 2010 Camry was better equipped and 10 percent more fuel efficient. As automakers work hard to meet new and tougher fuel economy standards, they are likely to follow the same playbook. The starting point: improving internal-combustion engines, which still offer significant opportunities to enhance efficiency and emissions performance. On the other hand, high battery costs would be likely to require automakers to raise prices, making a sweeping shift to electric vehicles more difficult between now and, say, 2020. </p><p>
A sustained oil price spike could well prompt regulators in mature economies to up the ante—for example, by increasing support for electric vehicles—and speed a broader adoption of tougher standards in developing economies, which will represent most of the new demand for transportation fuel going forward. This would create additional momentum for change.</p><p>
Still, for a major shift in the global automotive stock to occur within the decade, consumer behavior or technology would need to change in dramatic and currently unforeseen ways. One possibility would be for a higher proportion of car buyers to begin prioritizing fuel economy. While the importance of this factor varies around the world, our consumer research suggests that in two major car markets, Germany and the United States, car buyers rank this attribute outside the top ten they consider when buying a new car.<a class='link-footnote' rel='#footnote4' href='#' onclick='return false;'><sup>1</sup></a> <span id='footnote4' class='tooltip' style='display:none;'><span class='footnote-content'><span class='footnote-number'>1.</span><span class='footnote-text'>
We conducted online interviews with 2,200 new-vehicle buyers in Germany and the United States. The sample included purchasers of cars, trucks, flex-fuel vehicles, and diesel vehicles, weighted to match the demographic characteristics and brand and power train preferences of each national market. Consumer rankings of attributes, derived through conjoint analysis, represented the implied importance attached to them by buyers. Implied importance often differs from stated importance but can be more accurate because it is less likely to reflect respondents’ beliefs about the answers they are “expected” to provide. 
</span><span class='clear'></span> </span><span class='footnote-bottom'></span></span></p><p>Significant consumer change is likely to require compelling economics that don’t take many years of ownership to realize. Comparing Europe and the United States highlights the magnitude of the challenge: although gasoline prices are twice as high in the former, the share of autos running on oil-based derivatives (gasoline and diesel) and alternative fuels is roughly the same in both. For the economics to become more appealing, advanced technology, especially electric-vehicle batteries, would need to come down the cost curve faster than expected while oil and gasoline prices crossed some new threshold of pain.</p><div class="about-authors"><h3 class="sm black">About the authors</h3><p><b>Russell Hensley</b> is a principal in McKinsey’s Detroit office, and <b>Andreas Zielke</b> is a director in the Berlin office.</p></div></td></tr>
      </table>
    </figure>
    </details></p>
    
<p>To paint a clearer picture for senior executives of what such a world would mean for them—and how to prepare now—we asked several colleagues to join us in a thought experiment about the impact of a prolonged oil price spike. Russell Hensley and Andreas Zielke, from McKinsey’s automotive practice, explain how intensified regulation already is leading a transition toward greater fuel economy, as well as the potential for higher oil prices to reinforce that momentum (see sidebar “The automotive sector’s road to greater fuel efficiency”). Jonathan Ablett, Lowell Bryan, and Sven Smit, from McKinsey’s strategy practice, assess the global economic impact of an oil price spike and the strategic implications of a slower-growth environment (see sidebar “Anticipating economic headwinds”). Finally, Knut Alicke and Tobias Meyer, from McKinsey’s operations practice, describe energy-efficient supply chain strategies that some companies are already undertaking (see sidebar “Building a supply chain that can withstand high oil prices”). </p>

     <p>
    <details>
    <summary><strong>Anticipating economic headwinds</strong></summary>
    <figure>
      <table  cellspacing="0" cellpadding="1" border="1">
        <tr><td><p><i>High, volatile oil prices would place a premium on fine-grained growth approaches and dynamic management processes.</i></p><p><b>Jonathan Ablett, Lowell Bryan, and Sven Smit</b></p><p><strong>If crude-oil prices rose</strong> to $125 or $150 a barrel and stayed there long enough—for years, not months—global growth would undoubtedly suffer. Indeed, we estimate that this type of shock would drive down global growth by 0.6 to 0.9 percentage points in the first year.<a class='link-footnote' rel='#footnote5' href='#' onclick='return false;'><sup>1</sup></a> <span id='footnote5' class='tooltip' style='display:none;'><span class='footnote-content'><span class='footnote-number'>1.</span><span class='footnote-text'>
All GDP and growth estimates in this article are the result of economic analysis we and our colleagues in McKinsey’s strategy practice conducted using the firm’s global-growth model, a tool for long-term scenario planning. The model links energy and capital markets to output and highlights relationships between growth and structural factors such as urbanization, education, and industry structure shifts. It can generate globally consistent scenarios for 20 countries, nine regions, and the world as a whole.
</span><span class='clear'></span> </span><span class='footnote-bottom'></span></span> Over time, as economies adjusted to the new higher prices (and shifted to different types of fuel, technologies, and production techniques) the impact would diminish. But the rate of global GDP growth would be affected for years. By 2020, the global economy would be between $1.1 trillion and $1.7 trillion smaller than the baseline outlook: the equivalent of losing Spain’s or Italy’s output for a year.</p><p>
A sustained growth drag of that magnitude would be serious, particularly for Europe and the United States, which are already suffering from sluggish recoveries and lingering unemployment. It could contribute to a double-dip recession in those markets and to trouble in the global economy as a whole, which also is fragile and faces other potential shocks, including sovereign-debt defaults, inflation in emerging markets, and problems in the Chinese financial sector.</p><p>
Senior executives can reduce the odds of getting whipsawed by the impact of an oil price spike if they push their planning teams to evaluate, at a fairly granular level, the likely growth impact of surging energy prices. Where are customers most vulnerable to energy cost increases, and where would they be less significant? In fact, our modeling suggests that the country-level impact of spiking oil prices would be quite uneven—and not just because of differences in the energy efficiency of various economies. Even more important, our analysis indicates, are variations in the relative size of the industrial sector in different countries. That means export-oriented advanced manufacturing economies, such as Germany and Japan, are more vulnerable than their relative energy efficiency might indicate (exhibit).</p> 
    <div id="v2">
      <h4></h4>
      <a exhibiturl="http://www.mckinsey.com/tools/Wrappers/Wrapper.aspx?sid={1A9F8A08-C53C-4530-B10F-355647787821}&amp;pid={A79DCDAD-7009-43BB-9791-314A56C9C7EA}" exhibitwd="0" exhibitht="0">
        <h3></h3>
      </a>
      <p></p>
      <div>
        <a exhibiturl="http://www.mckinsey.com/tools/Wrappers/Wrapper.aspx?sid={1A9F8A08-C53C-4530-B10F-355647787821}&amp;pid={A79DCDAD-7009-43BB-9791-314A56C9C7EA}" exhibitwd="0" exhibitht="0">
          <img width="510" data-nosvg="http://www.mckinsey.com/~/media/McKinsey/dotcom/Insights/Energy Resources Materials/Another oil shock/Image_Exhibit 2_2.ashx" src="http://www.mckinsey.com/~/media/McKinsey/dotcom/Insights/Energy Resources Materials/Another oil shock/Image_Exhibit 2_2.ashx">
        </a>
      </div>
    </div>
    <p>
In addition, business leaders should be preparing for a world in which energy-related growth slowdowns could occur in an oscillating and unpredictable manner. For example, oil prices might fly up to a point (far in excess of $125 a barrel) where global GDP growth completely stalled and new sources of energy supply rapidly became economic. That, in turn, might drive prices down somewhat, leading to a resumption of economic growth and a repetition of the cycle. In a world like that, management approaches that some companies experimented with during the financial crisis—such as shorter financial-planning cycles or even moving away from calendar-based approaches to budgeting and planning—may be important.<a class='link-footnote' rel='#footnote6' href='#' onclick='return false;'><sup>2</sup></a> <span id='footnote6' class='tooltip' style='display:none;'><span class='footnote-content'><span class='footnote-number'>2.</span><span class='footnote-text'>
For more on principles for managing in extreme uncertainty, see Lowell Bryan, “<a href='http://www.mckinseyquarterly.com/article_page.aspx?ar=2475'>Dynamic management: Better decisions in uncertain times</a>,” mckinseyquarterly.com, December 2009.
</span><span class='clear'></span> </span><span class='footnote-bottom'></span></span></p><p>
When you combine the likelihood of oil price volatility with related uncertainties—such as the potential for swings in the dollar versus other currencies and commodities as global economic activity rebalances from the developed world toward emerging markets—you may want to abandon any presumption that you can predict medium-term oil prices.<a class='link-footnote' rel='#footnote7' href='#' onclick='return false;'><sup>3</sup></a> <span id='footnote7' class='tooltip' style='display:none;'><span class='footnote-content'><span class='footnote-number'>3.</span><span class='footnote-text'>
For more on uncertainties related to global economic rebalancing, see Lowell Bryan, “<a href='http://www.mckinseyquarterly.com/article_page.aspx?ar=2624'>Globalization’s critical imbalances</a>,” mckinseyquarterly.com, June 2010.
</span><span class='clear'></span> </span><span class='footnote-bottom'></span></span> Indeed, it may be more fruitful to stress-test your financial plans and strategies for different oil (and currency) prices, see what happens to the plans at the extremes, and then prepare for contingencies. One example: if oil prices rose significantly, that would accelerate the accumulation of capital by sovereign-wealth funds in oil-producing countries, complicating financing decisions and raising the importance of building strong relationships with a diverse group of capital suppliers.<a class='link-footnote' rel='#footnote8' href='#' onclick='return false;'><sup>4</sup></a> <span id='footnote8' class='tooltip' style='display:none;'><span class='footnote-content'><span class='footnote-number'>4.</span><span class='footnote-text'>
For more on diversifying sources of financing, see Richard Dobbs, Susan Lund, and Andreas Schreiner, “<a href='http://www.mckinseyquarterly.com/article_page.aspx?ar=2715'>How the growth of emerging markets will strain global finance</a>,” mckinseyquarterly.com, December 2010.
</span><span class='clear'></span> </span><span class='footnote-bottom'></span></span> In general, using multiple scenarios for even base-case planning, and developing a portfolio of responses to each scenario, will enable you to act swiftly when you can see where prices are moving.</p><div class="about-authors"><h3 class="sm black">About the authors</h3><p><b>Jonathan Ablett</b> is a consultant in McKinsey’s Waltham Knowledge Center, <b>Lowell Bryan</b> is a director in McKinsey’s New York office, and <b>Sven Smit</b> is a director in the Amsterdam office.</p></div></td></tr>
      </table>
    </figure>
    </details></p>
    
<h3>A delicate balance</h3>
<p>The world is very far from running out of oil. By most estimates, at least a trillion barrels of conventional oil still reside beneath the earth’s surface, not to mention several trillion more barrels of oil or gas that could be extracted through unconventional sources, such as oil sands.</p>

     <p>
    <details>
    <summary><strong>Building a supply chain that can withstand high oil prices</strong></summary>
    <figure>
      <table  cellspacing="0" cellpadding="1" border="1">
        <tr><td><p><i>Opportunities abound to boost supply chain efficiency. Most are in the money today, and will become even more attractive if oil prices rise.</i></p>
<p><b>Knut Alicke and Tobias Meyer</b></p>
<p><strong>We don&rsquo;t need to look very hard</strong> for a live case study of what happens to global supply chains when oil prices spike. Just three years ago, when they shot up to $125 and beyond, it became painfully obvious to many companies that their supply chains were not viable at those levels.</p>
<p>Research we conducted at that time indicated that even if oil prices were as low as $40 a barrel, it would still make economic sense for companies to take a variety of actions that collectively would reduce the energy intensity of global supply chains by almost one-fourth. Energy intensity could be reduced by more than one-third if oil prices stayed above $100 a barrel for a prolonged period (exhibit). The potential would be even greater at higher prices. </p>

    <div id="v2">
      <h4></h4>
      <a exhibiturl="http://www.mckinsey.com/tools/Wrappers/Wrapper.aspx?sid={593EFE77-754D-44C2-A910-C61A05E08406}&amp;pid={A79DCDAD-7009-43BB-9791-314A56C9C7EA}" exhibitwd="0" exhibitht="0">
        <h3></h3>
      </a>
      <p>If oil is priced at $100 a barrel, a number of activities to reduce the energy intensity of global supply chains become economically feasible.
</p>
      <div>
        <a exhibiturl="http://www.mckinsey.com/tools/Wrappers/Wrapper.aspx?sid={593EFE77-754D-44C2-A910-C61A05E08406}&amp;pid={A79DCDAD-7009-43BB-9791-314A56C9C7EA}" exhibitwd="0" exhibitht="0">
          <img width="510" data-nosvg="http://www.mckinsey.com/~/media/McKinsey/dotcom/Insights/Energy Resources Materials/Another oil shock/Image_Exhibit 3_3.ashx" src="http://www.mckinsey.com/~/media/McKinsey/dotcom/Insights/Energy Resources Materials/Another oil shock/Image_Exhibit 3_3.ashx">
        </a>
      </div>
    </div>
    
<p>Here are some of the opportunities that farsighted companies are beginning to act on:</p>
<p><b>Utilizing space-saving packages.</b> A retailer and a wholesaler partnered to create a new, stackable format for milk containers. As a result, they no longer need traditional shipping crates for truck transport, thus freeing up additional space for other cargo and avoiding the need to haul back the empty crates.</p>
<p><b>Operating larger ships and trucks.</b> Vale, the Brazil-based miner, took delivery this year of its first new ultralarge ore carrier, with 400,000 deadweight tons of capacity&mdash;more than twice that of today&rsquo;s standard vessel on the most important trade routes&mdash;to ship iron ore from Brazil to China. Scale is important because doubling the capacity of a transport asset typically increases its energy efficiency by one-fourth. The same goes for trucks too. In emerging markets, where average truck size is less than half that in OECD<a href="#" class="link-footnote" onclick="return false;" rel="#footnote9"><sup>1</sup></a> <span class="tooltip" id="footnote9" style="display: none;"><span class="footnote-content"><span class="footnote-number">1.</span><span class="footnote-text"> Organisation for Economic Co-operation and Development. </span><span class="clear"></span></span><span class="footnote-bottom"></span></span>countries, partly because of poorer infrastructure and smaller retail outlets, every percentage point of average truck size would reduce fuel consumption per unit of capacity by about 0.4 to 0.6 points. </p>
<p><b>Combining new technologies.</b> Maersk, the Danish container liner, used most of the available technological advances when it placed orders for its new 400-meter-long vessels, each with space for 18,000 20-foot container units. These vessels set a new benchmark in maritime energy efficiency by virtue of their size, slower speed, design improvements, and a waste heat&ndash;recovery system that reduces the engine&rsquo;s fuel consumption.</p>
<p><b>Switching to alternative fuels.</b> A road transport company recently estimated that it would save &euro;15,000 a year per truck by converting its small fleet to run on vegetable oil rather than traditional diesel fuel. Because of North America&rsquo;s recent flood of supply of natural gas, companies could also convert fleets to run on liquified natural gas (LNG) instead of diesel. </p>
<p><b>Practicing smarter driving.</b> Examining data collected by onboard computers, a logistics company found significant differences in the driving patterns and fuel consumption of drivers. Shifting to best practice could shave 10 percent off its $4 million annual fuel bill, with onboard computers helping employees drive more economically. </p>
<p>Regulators also have a role to play. In the United States, the fuel efficiency gain of lowering the cap on truck speeds on highways could be 7 to 10 percent. Truck speeds are already capped to lower levels in Europe. But there are still opportunities&mdash;for instance, allowing longer (and potentially heavier) truck/trailer combinations in Europe&rsquo;s road transport market could reduce its use of diesel by around 15 percent. </p>
<p>These examples are just the tip of the iceberg. Further existing technological opportunities&mdash;such as trucks with better aerodynamics and ocean vessels with new, friction-reducing hull coatings&mdash;are economical at the $100-a-barrel prices that have prevailed recently. High prices also should induce companies to cut the distance products travel. Moving final assembly into regions of demand would make it sensible to manufacture less valuable components there, such as primary packaging, manuals, or power cables for electric goods. An alternative is to ship products with low value density by slow and more energy efficient modes of transport. </p>
<p>Optimizing the energy efficiency of a supply chain&rsquo;s production process, location footprint, transportation, and inventory is a complex task made harder by inevitable tensions between the supply chain group and functions such as sales, service, and product development. There are thorny trade-offs&mdash;for example, between service levels and the lower speed of energy-efficient transport. </p>
<p>Part of the answer will be creating nimbler supply chains&mdash;for example, by using slower, more energy-efficient modes (such as ocean freight) for the base load and reserving the faster, less energy-efficient modes (such as air freight) for peak demand. CEOs also will need to facilitate meaningful discussion of important cross-functional supply chain issues so that executives can collaborate to uphold a company&rsquo;s best interests.</p>
<div class="about-authors">
<h3 class="sm black">About the authors</h3>
<p><b>Knut Alicke</b> is a consultant in McKinsey&rsquo;s Stuttgart office, and <b>Tobias Meyer</b> is a principal in the Frankfurt office.</p>
</div></td></tr>
      </table>
    </figure>
    </details></p>
    
<p>More relevant for prices, though, is how much spare oil production capacity exists in the world. Three million or four million barrels a day typically represents a comfortable buffer when the global economy is healthy. If that buffer shrinks, and markets expect strong demand growth to continue, prices can rise—sometimes dramatically. That’s what happened prior to the 2008–09 financial crisis as surging emerging-market demand strained production capacity and prices approached $150 a barrel. This fly-up was short lived because the ensuing deep recession wiped out between three million and four million barrels a day of demand, sending oil prices sharply down. </p>
<p>During the sluggish recovery that followed, the global supply cushion shrank again, punctuated in the first half of 2011 by Libya’s civil war, which disrupted supplies from that country and knocked off a million barrels a day of global capacity. That tightness set the stage for price fly-ups to $120 a barrel in the first half of this year and underscores the strength of the pre-2008 fundamentals. </p>
<p>Going forward, barring prolonged economic stagnation, demand growth for liquids<a href="#" class="link-footnote" onclick="return false;" rel="#footnote1"><sup>1</sup></a> <span class="tooltip" id="footnote1" style="display: none;"><span class="footnote-content"><span class="footnote-number">1.</span><span class="footnote-text"> For the sake of simplicity, in most of this article we use the term “oil” as short-hand for “liquids,” which comprise all liquid fuels derived from crude oil, as well as liquid fuels from natural-gas liquids (NGLs), biofuels, gas to liquids (GTLs), and coal to liquids (CTLs). </span><span class="clear"></span></span><span class="footnote-bottom"></span></span>is likely to chug ahead at around 1.5 percent a year. The pace would be even faster without the steady improvements in energy efficiency that we and other energy analysts foresee, particularly for cars and trucks as a result of technology improvements and stiffening regulatory standards that are already on the books.</p>
<p>Could supply growth accelerate to keep pace? Many industry analysts and our own supply model suggest that it won’t be easy. Despite high oil prices for much of the past decade and surging investment outlays by many major private and national oil companies alike, capacity has risen by only slightly more than 1 percent a year during that time. The logistics, supply systems, and political alignment needed to extract new oil supplies make that a complex, expensive, and time-consuming business. And coaxing more output out of existing oil fields, which typically have high production-decline rates, also is costly and challenging. </p>
<p>Our current projections suggest that in a “business as usual” scenario,<a href="#" class="link-footnote" onclick="return false;" rel="#footnote2"><sup>2</sup></a> <span class="tooltip" id="footnote2" style="display: none;"><span class="footnote-content"><span class="footnote-number">2.</span><span class="footnote-text"> Our business-as-usual scenario assumes that between 2010 and 2020, the world economy will grow at the rate currently anticipated by many analysts (3.0 to 3.5 percent) and that oil prices won’t significantly exceed $100 a barrel during this period. </span><span class="clear"></span></span><span class="footnote-bottom"></span></span>the world could reach a realistic supply capacity of around 100 million barrels a day by 2020, up from 91 million or 92 million today. That, however, would barely suffice to meet the roughly 100 million barrels of liquids the world would consume each day in such a scenario, up from 88 million or 89 million today. </p>
<h3>When supply and demand collide</h3>
<p>Simple math suggests that at some point, something has to give. And when it does, the world will have to start taking steps away from today’s oil dependence. The question is how rapid and volatile that transition will be.</p>
<h3 class="sm black">The case for a gentle collision</h3>
<p>This critical shift could happen in an orderly fashion, without price spikes, if governments, companies, and consumers worked together to accelerate the adoption of measures that reduce demand. Indeed, a common denominator of current forecasts by industry analysts (including ourselves) is a gradual transition in most regions toward lower oil intensity in transportation, power, and residential heating. But according to our analysis, it would take more than current trends in oil conservation (spurred by existing legislation) for supply to meet demand if robust economic growth returned. </p>
<p>A few examples illustrate the scale and scope of the task facing the world if we are to realize a gentle transition. Governments would need to raise auto fuel efficiency standards further, and consumers would need to place greater emphasis on fuel economy when they bought new cars. Policy makers in several developing countries would need to abolish fuel subsidies so that consumers felt the real price of oil. Around the world, we’d need to see deeper reductions in the use of oil for heating, power generation, and chemical manufacturing. Some transport by ships and heavy trucks would need to start shifting toward more reliance on natural gas as a fuel.</p>
<p>Changes like these could push oil supply and demand roughly into balance. However, they would require new policies and significant changes in how consumers and businesses behave. What’s more, they would need to start now because it will take years before the changes required to constrain oil consumption begin to take effect. If we do not succeed in implementing these changes in a farsighted way, the system faces a risk of falling out of balance. </p>
<h3 class="sm black">Why the adjustment could be violent</h3>
<p>That brings us to a second scenario: it’s possible to imagine global supply and demand for oil colliding faster, and more ferociously, resulting in a price spike as the global capacity buffer melted away. As we’ve said, anticipated economic growth alone could cause demand to expand faster than supply. Another possible trigger: supply disruption, which does happen from time to time. The possibilities include an exceptionally severe hurricane in the Gulf of Mexico, violence in the Niger Delta, instability in Venezuela, and further tension in the Middle East.</p>
<p>If this new price spike took place, it could have a more significant impact on global consumption patterns than most executives expect (for audio commentary by Occo Roelofsen, see the interactive, “How might a sustained oil price spike affect demand?”). For starters, it would hit global growth, which in turn would immediately knock down oil demand. In addition, there would be some rapid behavioral effects, such as a reduction in car, air, and sea travel. If the spike lasted longer, it could cause several more structural shifts, such as prompting individuals to use different modes of transport or even to look for work closer to home, encouraging companies to reverse offshoring trends and bring supply chains closer to home, accelerating the substitution of videoconferences for air travel, and pushing the freight transport industry to adopt less oil-intensive modes. </p>

    <h4>Interactive</h4>
    <div id="V2">
    <a id="interactive" onclick="newwindow=window.open ('http://www.mckinsey.com/tools/Wrappers/Wrapper.aspx?sid={BCB26AB6-4B62-40A6-8396-E9323C9CDE67}&amp;pid={A79DCDAD-7009-43BB-9791-314A56C9C7EA}','WrapperWindow','toolbar=no, location=no, directories=no, resizable=yes, status=no,titlebar = no,scrollbars=yes, top=0,width=750,height=550'); newwindow.focus();return false;"><h3>How might a sustained oil price spike affect demand?</h3></a>
    <p>Occo Roelofsen discusses demand during a sustained oil price spike, from both a general and sector-specific perspective.</p>
    <div>
      <a id="interactive" onclick="newwindow=window.open ('http://www.mckinsey.com/tools/Wrappers/Wrapper.aspx?sid={BCB26AB6-4B62-40A6-8396-E9323C9CDE67}&pid={A79DCDAD-7009-43BB-9791-314A56C9C7EA}','WrapperWindow','toolbar=no, location=no, directories=no, resizable=yes, status=no,titlebar = no,scrollbars=yes, top=0,width=1000,height=680'); newwindow.focus();return false;">
        <img id="svgImage" width="510" data-nosvg="http://www.mckinsey.com/~/media/McKinsey/dotcom/Insights/Energy Resources Materials/Another oil shock/How might a sustained oil price spike affect demand_interactive.ashx" src="http://www.mckinsey.com/~/media/McKinsey/dotcom/Insights/Energy Resources Materials/Another oil shock/How might a sustained oil price spike affect demand_interactive.ashx" style="border-width:0px;"/>
      </a>
    </div></div>
<p>Because such shifts would take time, a high-price environment could last for years, not months, accelerating several other ongoing trends that, when combined, could lead to even further demand reductions. In other words, a sustained price spike could scare consumers, companies, and governments into more drastic responses—accelerating the transition to a less oil-dependent economy. A price spike of one to three years could be long enough to make governments raise standards for fuel efficiency at an accelerated pace and prompt automakers, reacting to regulatory changes, to modify their product-development road maps. Ultimately, all this would lead to more rapid efficiency gains and potentially to faster electric-vehicle penetration. </p>
<p>A prolonged price spike also could prompt investments in infrastructure needed to support the use of electric vehicles or other alternatives (such as natural gas and hydrogen) to traditional fuel sources. Such investments could have an impact on oil demand for trucking, light vehicles, and shipping. What’s more, very high oil prices would intensify energy efficiency efforts up and down the supply chain and reduce the amount of plastics used in packaging, thus shrinking demand for oil in chemicals. Additional government action, in the form of either more stringent regulation on the use of plastics or subsidized financing that reduced the up-front cost to consumers of switching away from fuel oil in residential heating, could play an important role in this transition. </p>
<p>All along the way, of course, these reactions, plus slower global growth, would do their part to exert some downward pressure on oil prices. Expanded supply would also play a role. From now to 2020, OPEC<a href="#" class="link-footnote" onclick="return false;" rel="#footnote3"><sup>3</sup></a> <span class="tooltip" id="footnote3" style="display: none;"><span class="footnote-content"><span class="footnote-number">3.</span><span class="footnote-text"> Organization of the Petroleum Exporting Countries. </span><span class="clear"></span></span><span class="footnote-bottom"></span></span>could increase its capacity by, say, two million barrels a day above currently assumed increases, and new investments in mature assets could slow decline rates, leading to an additional one million to two million barrels of daily production. Furthermore, additional investments in unconventional oil sources, such as oil sands, could increase supply by, say, one million to two million barrels a day. Biofuels, too, would have room to grow. But given the time it would take to pursue some of the available opportunities—and the danger that they could quickly become uneconomic once oil prices fell—the supply response is likely to be slower and more muted than that of demand. </p>
<p>In the end, once all the efficiency gains and supply expansions described above kicked in, the world could again wind up in balance and with significant excess capacity, so that eventually—perhaps by 2020, perhaps later—prices fell below the $80 to $100 range. Until then, however, given how slowly many of the demand changes would unfold, it’s only prudent to imagine the possibility that the world could experience a prolonged period of both significant volatility and generally much higher prices. </p>
<h3>Preparing for the unexpected</h3>
<p>If the shock scenario outlined above unfolded, sustained high oil prices would challenge the top and bottom lines of many companies. However, high prices also could create opportunities for companies to differentiate themselves from competitors whose cost structures and operating approaches were ill suited to the new environment. And for companies on the front lines of the resource productivity revolution, a prolonged oil price increase would be beneficial. Providers of a range of new technologies—from car batteries for electric vehicles, to horizontal drilling and other tools for unconventional oil extraction, to biofuel production techniques, to electricity cogeneration equipment for manufacturers—would see their businesses grow, faster, than they would in a world of lower oil prices. </p>
<p>In many cases, these companies would be supplying or partnering with more established firms: oil companies in need of unconventional extraction technologies, auto manufacturers trying to create the winning vehicle of the future, and chemical companies hoping to take advantage of new feedstock sources, for example. From a strategic perspective, the interesting question is who would grab the most profitable positions in the new energy ecosystem.</p>
<p>No less fascinating are the managerial implications of the second-order and feedback effects that would occur as this ferocious collision played itself out. For example, our analysis suggests that even if prices subsequently fell, companies that pursued strategies for reducing their dependence on oil would be unlikely to regret it. One reason is that many strategies are already “in the money” at today’s prices. If prices got high enough, they would concentrate the attention of consumers, businesses, and governments sufficiently to promote many positive-return investments that haven’t been implemented so far, because of behavioral inertia. This development would accelerate the changes in our capital stock, while leaving them economically viable even if prices fell again. </p>
<p>Furthermore, many technologies could become significantly cheaper as demand for them increased and their providers went down learning curves. Examples include batteries for vehicles, highly efficient internal-combustion engines, and certain biofuel technologies, such as those that are cellulosic or perhaps even based on algae. In a high-price environment, more capital would flow into these technologies, enabling them to scale up. The time needed for them to become economically attractive would fall by five or even ten years compared with the time frame if oil prices stayed at lower levels, potentially making these technologies economically viable even if oil prices subsequently fell.</p>
<p>Indeed, a striking and often-underestimated feature of energy price shocks is the nonlinearity of their impact. Take electric vehicles. The market for car batteries would likely be about five or ten times larger if oil prices stayed for a considerable period at $150 a barrel than it would be at $100 a barrel. Few corporate-planning processes, however, place sufficient emphasis on extremes like this—even though these are precisely the scenarios that produce many of the most interesting opportunities and powerful threats for a business. Building corporate processes and skills that enable thoughtful reflection on a wider, more volatile range of outcomes could be a significant competitive differentiator in the years to come.</p>
<div class="articleBreak"></div>
<p>In the long run, these structural changes could well be a positive development for the world—resulting in more predictable and sustainable energy supplies and prices. But navigating the transition would be challenging and would reward the well prepared. The time is now for companies to start planning for the possibility of another price shock and a powerful market response.</p>
<div class="about-authors">
<h3 class="sm black">About the authors</h3>
<p><b>Tom Janssens</b> is a principal in McKinsey’s Houston office, where <b>Scott Nyquist</b> is a director; <b>Occo Roelofsen</b> is a principal in the Amsterdam office.</p>
<p>The authors wish to acknowledge the contributions of Tim Fitzgibbon, Pedro Haas, Yousuf Habib, Matt Rogers, Valerie Tann, and Koen Vermeltfoort to the development of this article.</p>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A strategic role for China’s CIOs</title>
      <description>CIOs have a key part to play as Chinese enterprises start looking to IT for business growth and global competitiveness.</description>
      <link>http://www.mckinsey.com/insights/business_technology/testrss</link>
      <guid>http://www.mckinsey.com/insights/business_technology/testrss</guid>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Sep 2013 20:21:31 GMT</pubDate>
      <ID>c9d05196-8ccc-4e19-9e23-3953a4085d81</ID>
      <category>Business  Technology</category>
      <dc:creator><![CDATA[Driek Desmet, Kevin Wei Wang, and Chenan Xia]]></dc:creator>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>As Chinese organizations move from early-stage businesses to large global players, IT will need to play an increasingly important and strategic role. However, a 2012 McKinsey survey on business technology in China, undertaken in collaboration with Peking University, finds that Chinese enterprises continue to spend less than their global counterparts when it comes to IT investment. What’s more, many Chinese CEOs and business leaders view their IT function as good at helping to <em>run</em> the business but not strong at helping to <em>grow</em> it.</p>
<p>Indeed, the results of the survey show the majority of corporate IT investment in China remains skewed toward improving operational efficiency. Comparatively little investment is directed to delivering customer-facing, top-line pursuits. Such pursuits could include digital-sales channels tapping big-data analytics to improve the customer experience (Exhibit 1) or leveraging social media for marketing of products and services.</p>

<p>
    <div id="v2">
      <h4>Exhibit - Eyebrow</h4>
      <a exhibiturl="http://www.mckinsey.com/tools/Wrappers/Wrapper.aspx?sid={4D220119-58B1-42BA-B65F-EF3228F521A1}&amp;pid={C9D05196-8CCC-4E19-9E23-3953A4085D81}" exhibitwd="0" exhibitht="0">
        <h3>Exhibit - Headline</h3>
      </a>
      <p><b>Cultural and skill barriers - desc</b></p>
      <div>
        <a exhibiturl="http://www.mckinsey.com/tools/Wrappers/Wrapper.aspx?sid={4D220119-58B1-42BA-B65F-EF3228F521A1}&amp;pid={C9D05196-8CCC-4E19-9E23-3953A4085D81}" exhibitwd="0" exhibitht="0">
          <img width="510" data-nosvg="http://www.mckinsey.com/~/media/test/Q1_MGIdeleveraging_ex2 REV.ashx" src="http://www.mckinsey.com/~/media/test/Q1_MGIdeleveraging_ex2 REV.ashx">
        </a>
      </div>
    </div>
    </p>

<p>This will need to change as Chinese businesses expand globally and as pressure for innovation and fully enabled digital enterprises grows. Our analysis of the survey data and discussions with Chinese CIOs and other business executives reveal four ways that Chinese organizations can raise their technology game and maximize the value and performance of their IT investments.</p>
<h6>Align IT investment with business strategy</h6>



<p>Among Chinese companies, IT has historically been seen as a support function that helps run the day-to-day business by operating, for example, basic domestic enterprise-resource-planning (ERP) and core-banking systems. IT has generally not been viewed as an enabler of strategic growth. Indeed, two-thirds of respon­dents say IT strategy is developed only after the business strategy has been agreed upon. This is partly because of how fast Chinese companies have grown over the past 20 years, prompting them to focus on providing basic IT functionality just to keep the business running smoothly.</p>


    <h4>Interactive Eyebrow</h4>
    <div id="V2">
    <a id="interactive" onclick="newwindow=window.open ('http://www.mckinsey.com/tools/Wrappers/Wrapper.aspx?sid={9186B046-4605-4425-93C8-4D6C3404AFB9}&amp;pid={C9D05196-8CCC-4E19-9E23-3953A4085D81}','WrapperWindow','toolbar=no, location=no, directories=no, resizable=yes, status=no,titlebar = no,scrollbars=yes, top=0,width=750,height=550'); newwindow.focus();return false;"><h3>The worlds new growth frontier - 2</h3></a>
    <p>Explore, track, and customize four years of survey results on how businesses use new Web technologies and tools - 2</p>
    <div>
      <a id="interactive" onclick="newwindow=window.open ('http://www.mckinsey.com/tools/Wrappers/Wrapper.aspx?sid={9186B046-4605-4425-93C8-4D6C3404AFB9}&pid={C9D05196-8CCC-4E19-9E23-3953A4085D81}','WrapperWindow','toolbar=no, location=no, directories=no, resizable=yes, status=no,titlebar = no,scrollbars=yes, top=0,width=1000,height=680'); newwindow.focus();return false;">
        <img id="svgImage" width="510" data-nosvg="http://www.mckinsey.com/~/media/test/MoF_AsianFIG_ex1svg.ashx" src="http://www.mckinsey.com/~/media/test/MoF_AsianFIG_ex1svg.ashx" style="border-width:0px;"/>
      </a>
    </div></div>

<p>Today, however, IT can no longer take a back seat, given the growing maturity and global appetite of Chinese businesses and increasing local competition. Expanding sales overseas, for example, typically requires a company to turn its domestic ERP system into a complex multicountry system that supports both unique local-market requirements and value-chain collaborations across borders. More than three-quarters of CIOs say they want to integrate business and IT strategy better. As one insurance-industry CIO said, “The role of IT is starting to shift from supplier and execution support to shaper of business.”</p>
<p>To get there, organizations must establish much closer collaboration among IT, other functions, and business units at all levels of the enterprise. CIOs should engage early and often with senior leaders to understand how best to direct resources and development efforts to meet their companies’ business objectives. Involving IT in business planning can help organizations achieve greater operational efficiency and promote continued expansion.</p>
<p>Rather than simply funding isolated projects, the business side and IT must agree on a road map to direct spending toward initiatives that support overall growth. Buy-in is also important. Some organizations have found it helpful to implement a chargeback to hold business units responsible for their IT requests. A handful of survey respondents, 5 percent, say they have taken collaboration further by establishing a joint IT and business investment committee. More than half of those surveyed also believe such committees can help ensure effective and efficient IT spending. Indeed, better collaboration between IT and business leaders when setting strategy and allocating investments has helped several leading Chinese companies that are global players success­fully drive their business-transformation programs forward and bring tangible business value.</p>
<h6>Elevate the CIO's role in business transformation</h6>

<p>
     <p>
    <details>
    <summary><strong>Biography of David Fisher, director of the Department of Defense’s Business Transformation Agency</strong></summary>
    <figure>
      <table  cellspacing="0" cellpadding="1" border="1">
        <tr><td><p>David Fisher</p><p><img src='http://www.mckinsey.com/~/media/McKinsey/dotcom/Insights/Business Technology/Boosting performance in public-sector IT An interview with a US Defense Depart/spot_bope08.ashx' alt='David Fisher'/></p><p><B> Test Description </b> <i> for David Fisher</i></p><p><p>Born in 1965, in San Francisco, California</p></p><p><p>Graduated with BA in communication in 1987 from Stanford University  </p><p>Earned MBA in 1998 from Leavey School of Business, Santa Clara University</p></p><p><p><strong>Department of Defense</strong></p><ul class="leftContentUL"><li><p>Director of Business Transformation Agency (2006–present) </p></li><li><p>Director, Transformation Planning and Performance (2005–06) </p></li></ul><p><strong>BearingPoint</strong></p><ul class="leftContentUL"><li><p>Managing director (2000–05)</p></li></ul></p><p><ul class="leftContentUL"><li><p>Author of <em>Optimize Now (or else!): How to Leverage Processes and Information to Achieve Enterprise Optimization (and Avoid Enterprise Extinction)</em></p></li><li><p>Speaker on business process optimization at conferences </p></li></ul></p></td></tr>
      </table>
    </figure>
    </details></p>
    </p>

<p>Those surveyed agreed that CIOs empowered by their CEO or other senior leaders are in a unique position to drive cross-functional business transformation and should shift their own roles from supply-focused IT providers to business-focused leaders of IT-enabled innovation. In that role they could help spur revenue growth, get products to market faster, and sometimes generate new business models. Nonetheless, few are actively doing so. While about 40 percent of CIOs say they have begun to move beyond traditional, narrow IT roles, less than a third of those in this group currently lead business-transformation programs (Exhibit 2). There is an opportunity for CIOs to elevate their positions and add greater value. The CIO’s role, for instance, is one of the few leadership positions able to look across different business functions and elements such as R&D, marketing, finance, and the supply chain. CIOs that couple technology expertise with an understanding of business processes can offer value-adding insight and solutions. That operational view should allow them to fill a void as well, since unlike Western enterprises, many Chinese companies still do not have a role equivalent to the COO. Alternatively, some organizations appoint a business leader to run the IT organization with the help of IT-savvy managers in order to ensure better alignment and collaboration.</p>

<p>CEO or other senior-level sponsorship is critical to help CIOs manage the inevitable trade-offs between business and IT, for example, when weighing business-unit needs for localized business processes against the benefits of centralizing these processes and thus reducing IT complexity.</p>
<p>Such decisions require changes in business behavior and ways of working, and they cannot be achieved without top-management backing. One successful CIO said, “The reason I can drive business change is that I’m fully support­ed by the CEO.”</p>
<p>In addition, because many CIOs do not have experience in frontline business management, such as business-unit P&L responsibilities, they need to strengthen their knowledge of business strategy and better understand the key elements of their company’s operating model.</p>
<p>Finally, they must earn their spot at the strategy table by bringing value from technology-enabled business solutions. Some leading Chinese companies have already successfully improved business performance by adopting a model where the CIO not only leads IT delivery work but also actively drives business-process trans­formation. This transformation may include supporting international expansion by designing and facilitating a multicountry operating model and establishing a global process template. It may also involve initiating coinnovation with business units in fields such as big-data customer analytics.</p>
<h6>Strengthen IT capabilities for large transformation projects</h6>
<p>Less than half of the CIOs and IT executives surveyed say they are satisfied with their IT team’s capabilities, with the result that many have turned to outsourcing. According to the survey, two to three times as many Chinese companies outsource architecture design as do their global peers. Such heavy reliance on vendors reduces control over projects and may make companies too dependent on external parties, all of which can erode the business team’s confidence in IT.</p>
<p><figure>
    <h4>Sample Chaptered video</h4>
    <div>
      <h3></h3>
      <p>MGI principal Michael Chui discusses the potential value in using social tools to enhance communications, knowledge sharing, and collaboration within and across enterprises.</p>
    </div>
    <video width="" height="" controls poster="http://brightcove.vo.llnwd.net/e1/pd/1971571337001/1971571337001_2341050688001_vs-517ff457e4b06c7f359a60e9-1592194042001.jpg?pubId=1971571337001">
      <source src="http://brightcove.vo.llnwd.net/e1/uds/pd/1971571337001/1971571337001_2341053918001_41-Steve-Case-restarting-small-business-growth.mp4" />
		</video>
    </figure></p>
<p>Instead, Chinese enterprises should consider building and retaining a core IT team with strong capabilities in architecture design, project management, and the analysis of business requirements. But given the shortage of IT talent in China, building that team must be part of a larger effort to develop scalable IT capabilities to deliver value.</p>
<p>To institutionalize those capabilities, companies should improve their training and vendor-management processes and put continuous-improvement opportunities high on their agenda. As one banking CIO said, “We have over 10,000 good-quality IT employees, but we lack a mechanism to make sure they can work together efficiently.” For instance, many Chinese enterprises still lack mature processes for application development and maintenance (ADM) such as demand management and early identification of development defects. Only a quarter of surveyed executives rate their ADM capability as medium to high, but these processes are essential for supporting large transformation projects.</p>
<p>Employee training and development is also key. Chinese organizations should establish formal capability-building programs that focus on cultivating seasoned managers with strong project-management skills. The goal is a virtuous cycle that will raise the status of IT in the organization. The more IT helps solve real business problems, the more respect and support it will receive from the business, and the more inclined its top talent will be to stay and build careers.</p>
<h6>Speed up the adoption of new technology to support business innovation</h6>
<p>Although the majority of companies we surveyed have deployed basic emerging tech­nologies, many are struggling to use them in creating customer-facing innovation. Nearly 90 percent of those surveyed say their companies have basic IT technologies in place, such as core transaction applications and security systems, and 50 to 60 percent have deployed emerging technologies such as mobility devices like smartphones and tablets to support remote operations and collaboration. But they are not yet adopting technologies that require them to develop new business models (Exhibit 3). Less than 15 percent of survey respondents, for instance, report having selectively or mean­ingfully adopted big data–based analytics applications.</p>

<p>Furthermore, a quarter of the surveyed CIOs say they cannot convince senior leaders to allocate sufficient budget and business support to expand teams and applications. As one CIO from a leading Internet player noted, “Technology is available; [the key ques­tion] is how you position yourself to use the technology to build a business model. We have the customer data, but we have not figured out how to use the data yet.”</p>
<p>Pilots are one way to bring business along. To speed up buy-in and results, Chinese organizations can adopt a faster experimental approach that identifies innovative use cases and pilots IT solutions. Taking this approach, one Chinese construction company successfully deployed a custom-made field-crew handset that significantly reduced response time and improved customer satisfaction. In another case, a leading Internet company in China realized 10 million renminbi in revenue after a 12-week, small-scale pilot using big-data analytics. To obtain such quick results, the business team worked hand in hand with the data-analytics team to identify opportunities and develop a prototype for a predictive customer-segmentation model to be used in tailored campaign promotions; the prototype was then tested and refined every one to two weeks.</p>
<p>Chinese organizations invest relatively little in delivering top-line pursuits such as digital-sales channels tapping big-data analytics to improve the customer experience. Chinese CIOs and their teams must act as stewards in building digital enterprises that enable business growth and allow companies to compete successfully against global rivals.</p>


<p><figure>
    <h4>Podcast</h4>
    <div>
      <h3></h3>
      <p>MGI principal Michael Chui discusses the potential value in using social tools to enhance communications, knowledge sharing, and collaboration within and across enterprises.</p>
    </div>
      <audio controls>
        <source src="http://www.mckinsey.com/assets/SampleMP3.mp3" />
			  </audio>
    </figure></p>



<div class="about-authors">
<h6>About the authors</h6>
<p><strong>Driek Desmet</strong> is a director in McKinsey’s Singapore office, and <strong>Kevin Wei Wang</strong> is a principal in the Shanghai office, where <strong>Chenan Xia</strong> is a consultant.</p>
<p>The authors wish to thank Peking University and its Guanghua School of Management and the Center for Informatization and Information Management for their support. The authors also thank McKinsey's Harrison Lung, Janet Tang, Eileen Tu, Jason Wang, and Ryan Yang for their contributions to this article.</p>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Hemang Test article</title>
      <description>test description</description>
      <link>http://www.mckinsey.com/insights/business_technology/hemang</link>
      <guid>http://www.mckinsey.com/insights/business_technology/hemang</guid>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 Sep 2013 19:21:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <ID>e0e37920-2204-4416-b595-ff0c6131a5c2</ID>
      <category>Business  Technology</category>
      <dc:creator><![CDATA[Mckinsey]]></dc:creator>
      <content:encoded />
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Sample Article: An interview with a US Defense Department agency director..</title>
      <description>David Fisher talks about his experiences after he went from the private sector to the biggest organization in the US government.</description>
      <link>http://www.mckinsey.com/insights/business_technology/copy_of_br_sample_code</link>
      <guid>http://www.mckinsey.com/insights/business_technology/copy_of_br_sample_code</guid>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 Sep 2013 19:12:06 GMT</pubDate>
      <ID>0244bb12-fdde-4c0c-8f2b-294450f394de</ID>
      <category>Business  Technology</category>
      <dc:creator><![CDATA[James M. Kaplan and Kreg Nichols]]></dc:creator>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><strong>Public-sector entities,</strong> like many commercial ones, are increasingly undertaking large transformation programs to streamline and improve their core operations. Nowhere is this task more challenging than in the US Department of Defense (DoD), which is committed to transforming its business practices to support faster and more agile operations. This multiyear mission will touch all aspects of the DoD, which has annual net operating costs exceeding $620 billion—including more than $30 billion for technology—2.9 million people, and a supply chain involving 5.2 million items.</p>
<p>[[exhibit exhibit 3]]</p>
<p>
In 2005, the DoD established the Business Transformation Agency (BTA) to help guide transformation efforts throughout the department. The BTA’s responsibilities include deploying enterprise IT systems, publishing the Business Enterprise Architecture, and helping to carry out investment decisions. The agency, for example, oversees programs that manage pay and travel for the armed services, makes proposals to organizations such as the army and the navy (called “components” inside the Pentagon) about how they can transform themselves most effectively, and encourages standardization throughout the department.</p>

    <h4>Slideshow</h4>
    <div id="V2">
    <a id="interactive" onclick="newwindow=window.open ('http://www.mckinsey.com/tools/Wrappers/Wrapper.aspx?sid={196BB28F-58CC-488C-A68A-0D4B47C9A4CA}&amp;pid={0244BB12-FDDE-4C0C-8F2B-294450F394DE}','WrapperWindow','toolbar=no, location=no, directories=no, resizable=yes, status=no,titlebar = no,scrollbars=yes, top=0,width=750,height=550'); newwindow.focus();return false;"><h3></h3></a>
    <p>Explore, track, and customize four years of survey results on how businesses use new Web technologies and tools. - desc</p>
    <div>
      <a id="interactive" onclick="newwindow=window.open ('http://www.mckinsey.com/tools/Wrappers/Wrapper.aspx?sid={196BB28F-58CC-488C-A68A-0D4B47C9A4CA}&pid={0244BB12-FDDE-4C0C-8F2B-294450F394DE}','WrapperWindow','toolbar=no, location=no, directories=no, resizable=yes, status=no,titlebar = no,scrollbars=yes, top=0,width=1000,height=680'); newwindow.focus();return false;">
        <img id="svgImage" width="510" data-nosvg="http://www.mckinsey.com/~/media/McKinsey/dotcom/Insights/Business Technology/Business and Web 20 An interactive feature/Business and Web 20 An interactive feature_interactive.ashx" src="http://www.mckinsey.com/~/media/McKinsey/dotcom/Insights/Business Technology/Business and Web 20 An interactive feature/Business and Web 20 An interactive feature_interactive.ashx" style="border-width:0px;"/>
      </a>
    </div></div>
<p>
Few people have as good a position to reflect upon the DoD’s transformation as David Fisher, the BTA’s first official director. Fisher joined the DoD from Silicon Valley, where as a consultant he helped private-sector companies to implement large enterprise systems. As a special assistant to the deputy undersecretary of defense for financial management, Fisher helped guide an enterprise-level business transformation and served on the team that launched the BTA. McKinsey’s James Kaplan and Kreg Nichols met with him in his office, in Arlington, Virginia, near Washington, DC, to discuss the differences between public- and private-sector transformations, as well as what he has learned about managing megaprojects.</p>

     <p>
    <details>
    <summary><strong>Biography of David Fisher, director of the Department of Defense’s Business Transformation Agency</strong></summary>
    <figure>
      <table  cellspacing="0" cellpadding="1" border="1">
        <tr><td><p>David Fisher</p><p><img src='http://www.mckinsey.com/~/media/McKinsey/dotcom/Insights/Business Technology/Boosting performance in public-sector IT An interview with a US Defense Depart/spot_bope08.ashx' alt='David Fisher'/></p><p><B> Test Description </b> <i> for David Fisher</i></p></td></tr>
      </table>
    </figure>
    </details></p>
    
<p><strong>The <em>Quarterly</em>:</strong> Coming from Silicon Valley, how similar do you think the public and private sectors are?</p>
<p><strong>David Fisher:</strong> While the mission may be different, many of the business challenges are the same—for example, tracking supply chains or making certain that people are paid correctly and on time. But the public sector differs in some significant ways. For example, the scale is very different. The size and scope of the Department of Defense are challenging. The best way to think about our size is to take a look at our budget. In all, last year we had gross costs of over $600 billion, more than the sum of the revenues of, say, Wal-Mart, GE, and IBM. It’s enormous, and there’s nothing comparable to it in the private sector.</p>

<p>
Also, our leadership changes regularly—at least every eight years, when presidential administrations turn over, and generally more often. This is a challenge when you consider that huge organizations in the public and private sectors work at transformations for a long time, sometimes up to ten years, before really starting to reap the benefits. Paul Brinkley, the deputy undersecretary of defense for business transformation, reminds us that IBM was undergoing transformation for ten years before the company really started to reap the benefits of overhauling the supply chain, for example. Even in the best situations, transformations take a long time to accomplish. We look to commercial business for an indicative timeline, but you’d have to combine four or five of the Fortune 10 to get the scale of the DoD.</p>

    <h4>Interactive 2</h4>
    <div id="V2">
    <a id="interactive" onclick="newwindow=window.open ('http://www.mckinsey.com/tools/Wrappers/Wrapper.aspx?sid={5406E2C1-FA0E-492E-809F-F94ED4635249}&amp;pid={0244BB12-FDDE-4C0C-8F2B-294450F394DE}','WrapperWindow','toolbar=no, location=no, directories=no, resizable=yes, status=no,titlebar = no,scrollbars=yes, top=0,width=750,height=550'); newwindow.focus();return false;"><h3>The worlds new growth frontier - 2</h3></a>
    <p>Explore, track, and customize four years of survey results on how businesses use new Web technologies and tools - 2</p>
    <div>
      <a id="interactive" onclick="newwindow=window.open ('http://www.mckinsey.com/tools/Wrappers/Wrapper.aspx?sid={5406E2C1-FA0E-492E-809F-F94ED4635249}&pid={0244BB12-FDDE-4C0C-8F2B-294450F394DE}','WrapperWindow','toolbar=no, location=no, directories=no, resizable=yes, status=no,titlebar = no,scrollbars=yes, top=0,width=1000,height=680'); newwindow.focus();return false;">
        <img id="svgImage" width="510" data-nosvg="http://www.mckinsey.com/~/media/McKinsey/dotcom/Insights/Business Technology/Business and Web 20 An interactive feature/Business and Web 20 An interactive feature_interactive.ashx" src="http://www.mckinsey.com/~/media/McKinsey/dotcom/Insights/Business Technology/Business and Web 20 An interactive feature/Business and Web 20 An interactive feature_interactive.ashx" style="border-width:0px;"/>
      </a>
    </div></div>
<p><strong>The <em>Quarterly</em>:</strong> What have you been able to use from your commercial-sector experience?</p>
<p><strong>David Fisher:</strong> My experience working with large companies helped prepare me for this type of role by giving me a willingness to buck the cultural trend and to suggest new ways of doing business. The BTA has been trying to apply the best practices from the commercial world, especially about how we govern and manage IT investments. If there are processes that we can streamline to help programs deliver capabilities faster, without getting bogged down in some of the administrative activities, we try to do that.</p>

<p>
This can be hard to do in a complex, hierarchical environment like the Department of Defense. Fortunately, many people around me, who have more experience within the government culture, have proved to be tremendously valuable at identifying constraints we face in public projects—constraints that just wouldn’t be there in the private sector.</p>
<p>
The department has been trying to modernize the way it does business for a long time, and we still have a long way to go. Every administration tries, and I’m sure we make some progress each time. But on the whole, we’re not where we want to be—or where we need to be. We want to build on the good work that’s been done before us, but we also need to question previous actions that weren’t successful and to offer new solutions.</p>
<p><strong>The <em>Quarterly</em>:</strong> What are the goals of your transformation efforts?</p>
<p><strong>David Fisher:</strong> Our overall objective is to guide business transformation efforts at the enterprise level of the Department of Defense in order to improve the DoD’s ability to perform its mission. We do that sometimes directly, sometimes indirectly. The BTA has a combination of operational and technical roles to play—for example, we manage the systems that handle travel and payroll for about 1.5 million employees of the DoD. But a big part of our role is to identify skill sets that are scattered throughout the DoD and unite them so that its components can work better together. For example, we bring the functional people and the technical people together so that a set of data standards affecting multiple areas can be agreed on.</p>
<p>
Successful coordination among the components doesn’t come from exercising authority but rather from exerting influence. People in the components don’t have to open the door to us, and I’m not empowered to make them open the door. But if I can demonstrate value, they’re going to open the door to me, whether I’m empowered or not. It’s all about adding value. There are certain things that we have authority for, but even in an environment where you have authority, your authority will only carry you so far in the effort to move things forward in a positive direction.</p>
<p><strong>The <em>Quarterly</em>:</strong> What are the main challenges in deploying technology to support the transformation?</p>
<p><strong>David Fisher:</strong> We spend about $2 billion each year on IT business transformation, half of it on enterprise resource planning systems throughout the Department of Defense. Much of the work for these ERP systems focuses on deciding what should be centralized, at the DoD enterprise level, and what should be managed by components—the military services, defense agencies, combatant commands, and military health services. As in any large organization, the people at the enterprise level are consumers of information. As long as information in different systems can be aggregated in a standard way, these people can do their jobs. On the other hand, some decision making is distributed, occurring within organizations that make up the DoD. The challenge lies in the gray area. Where is it more effective to have a single system at the center as opposed to multiple versions that adhere to common standards?</p>
<p>
[video Sample Chaptered video]
We have 27 systems in our enterprise portfolio today, and many of these are centralized only because the components did not have the ability to run their own when these systems were implemented years ago. As the capabilities of the components mature, we must ask if there are more efficient and effective ways to complete those transactions while still providing the members of our cross-component community with the information they need to do their jobs.</p>
<p><strong>The <em>Quarterly</em>:</strong> How do you manage such a large-scale transformation?</p>
<p><strong>David Fisher:</strong> Much depends on governance and on discipline in setting and implementing standards. Consider our experience implementing a set of standards for financial data. Initially, the reaction in the field was that this would cost too much to embed in individual IT systems, so we came up with a two-pronged approach.</p>
<p>
In the short term, we agreed to create a bridge system to the components’ legacy accounting systems, to save costs. It wasn’t a perfect solution, but it moved us toward interoperable data at a relatively low cost in a short time frame. Our longer-term challenge involved integrating these standards into various ERP systems. It was critical to get this right, from the beginning. Again, the components’ managers were concerned that this would be expensive and difficult to integrate with their SAP and Oracle systems. So we deployed ERP experts among the components who worked with teams there to identify ways to configure the ERP systems so they could work with standardized data. It’s been very successful.</p>
<p><strong>The <em>Quarterly</em>:</strong> How do you keep people motivated and set performance measures?</p>
<p><strong>David Fisher:</strong> When I left the commercial environment, I thought one of the great things about leaving was putting behind me the need to meet quarterly profit-and-loss targets and to deal with the short-term decision making that results from a quarterly focus. But now that I don’t have those constraints, I miss having the motivation to hit quarterly numbers. So you have to look for different kinds of motivators to keep projects on time.</p>
<p>
The people who go into public service are unbelievably passionate about what they do. There is a tangible internal motivation about doing public service that is different from what you find in the commercial marketplace. It’s not something you can necessarily put your finger on, but it’s real. We appreciate that. It’s very important. That said, we have to find ways to measure accountability. In the commercial world, there’s the P&L—you’re held accountable for the numbers. We are always in search of ways to hold people accountable, not least because if you succeed at something, you want to be recognized for it.</p>
<p>
We and the rest of the Defense Department have recently begun to move away from an old tenure-based performance model to a new system—the National Security Personnel System—that is closer to pay for performance. This is the type of system that’s familiar to commercial enterprises, but it’s new to this public environment, so we had to spend some time explaining that the goals had to be objective, measurable, time constrained. It’s been somewhat controversial because not everyone likes this shift. But as a manager, I have found it a positive shift, especially in terms of getting people to think about time. Sometimes, impatience is exactly right because within the public sector, things do tend to run on for a while. We need to build in that internal motivator that makes people ask, what did I get done today?</p>
<p>
In the end, however, while people care about their compensation, just as they should, it’s a small part of what motivates people here. It’s about the contribution to public service. One of the things that rallies the passion of these folks is seeing that they’re making a difference on a national security–related issue that helps the people on the ground.</p>
<p><strong>The <em>Quarterly</em>:</strong> With such large-scale technology deployments, what have you learned about managing megaprojects?</p>
<p><strong>David Fisher:</strong> Many of the things that would portend a successful ERP implementation of small to medium size would portend success for the large programs at the DoD. We’ve looked at the top reasons ERP implementations fail. Many failures come down to governance, change management, requirements management, customization, the skill sets of the people involved, and testing. Those concepts are immutable, regardless of size and scale. Our challenge with these immense projects is that implementation takes such a long time, spanning several generations of IT development. That can be problematic and leave an opportunity for endless analysis and debate.</p>
<p>
It’s also important to clarify what we’re trying to optimize, since one person’s definition of the enterprise may be different from another’s. From my perspective, the enterprise is the Department of Defense. But if I go to the army or navy, they might define the enterprise differently; if they’re trying to optimize the army or navy as opposed to the DoD, we end up with different solutions.</p>
<p>
Let me give you one example of how the BTA’s involvement helped the army reexamine the scope of some of its systems to good effect. The army had three big ERP systems—one that handled finance and two for logistics (a more tactical system for the front end and a more wholesale system for the back end). All three systems were operating fairly independently. Our observation was that, although these independent systems may be optimizing the parts, they were suboptimizing the whole in terms of business processes, management, and the utilization of technology.</p>
[video Sample Video]
<p>
Through some pretty heavy engagements—some well received, others not—we were able to demonstrate that there was a better way to use technology to reduce risks the army would face in the way the systems communicated, reconciled data, and otherwise performed together. We recommended that the army connect the three systems more closely because, for example, each of the logistics transactions was eventually going to be a financial transaction. If you look at things that way from the beginning, it fosters an environment where you look at the business from end to end. The army has now adopted some of those concepts and has a cross-domain governance model. So we got the conversation going and it’s had this positive impact. We weren’t empowered to do any of that by our authority. We were passionate about it, and we were able to convince the army to let us in on the dialogue and help them come to decisions that represented a change for the better.</p>
<p><strong>The <em>Quarterly</em>:</strong> Any other big lessons to pass along?</p>
<p><strong>David Fisher:</strong> Question every assumption. We often assume that we have to do something in a certain way because it’s the policy or the way we’ve done it before. Question that assumption, and if it doesn’t make sense, find out who owns the policy or who owns the way it was done before. Even laws change. Sometimes the answer is no, and that’s it. But if you have a case that helps everyone to agree that the old way doesn’t make sense and that there’s a better way, a transformational way, of doing things, question the old way.  </p>
<div class="about-authors">
<h3 class="sm black">About the authors</h3>
<p><strong>James Kaplan</strong> is a principal in McKinsey’s New York office, and <strong>Kreg Nichols</strong> is an associate principal in the Atlanta office.</p>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Increasing the ‘meaning quotient’ of work</title>
      <description>Through a few simple techniques, executives can boost workplace “MQ” and inspire employees to perform at their peak.</description>
      <link>http://www.mckinsey.com/insights/organization/increasing_the_meaning_quotient_of_work</link>
      <guid>http://www.mckinsey.com/insights/organization/increasing_the_meaning_quotient_of_work</guid>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 Aug 2013 15:22:25 GMT</pubDate>
      <ID>3ee1d91a-8a53-4500-8e0b-d58a087c762d</ID>
      <category>Organization</category>
      <dc:creator><![CDATA[Susie Cranston and Scott Keller]]></dc:creator>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><strong>Musicians talk</strong> about being “in the groove,” sportsmen about being “in the zone.” Can employees in the workplace experience similar performance peaks and, if so, what can top management do to encourage the mental state that brings them about?</p><p>
We’ve long been interested in work environments that inspire exceptional levels of energy, increase self-confidence, and boost individual productivity. When we ask leaders about the ingredient they think is most often missing for them and for their colleagues—and by implication is most difficult to provide—they almost invariably signal the same thing: a strong sense of meaning. By “meaning,” we and they imply a feeling that what’s happening really matters, that what’s being done has not been done before or that it will make a difference to others.</p><p>
The idea of meaning at work is not new. Indeed, two contributions to <i>McKinsey Quarterly</i><a class='link-footnote' rel='#footnote1' href='#' onclick='return false;'><sup>1</sup></a> <span id='footnote1' class='tooltip' style='display:none;'><span class='footnote-content'><span class='footnote-number'>1.</span><span class='footnote-text'>
See Teresa Amabile and Steven Kramer, “<a href='http://www.mckinseyquarterly.com/article_page.aspx?ar=2910'>How leaders kill meaning at work</a>,” mckinseyquarterly.com, January 2012; and Cynthia A. Montgomery, “<a href='http://www.mckinseyquarterly.com/article_page.aspx?ar=2993'>How strategists lead</a>,” mckinseyquarterly.com, July 2012.
</span><span class='clear'></span> </span><span class='footnote-bottom'></span></span> over the past year have highlighted this theme. In one, the authors demonstrate how misguided leaders often kill meaning in avoidable ways. The author of the other suggests that “meaning maker” is a critical role for corporate strategists. In this article, we will show from our research how meaning drives higher workplace productivity and explain what business leaders can do to create meaning.</p><!--roadblock--><h3>Meaning and performance</h3><p>
The mental state that gives rise to great performance—in sports, business, or the arts—has been described in different ways. The psychologist Mihàly Csìkszentmihàlyi studied thousands of subjects, from sculptors to factory workers, and asked them to record their feelings at intervals throughout the working day. Csìkszentmihàlyi came up with a concept we consider helpful. He observed that people fully employing their core capabilities to meet a goal or challenge created what he called “flow.” More important, he found that individuals who frequently experienced it were more productive and derived greater satisfaction from their work than those who didn’t. They set goals for themselves to increase their capabilities, thereby tapping into a seemingly limitless well of energy. And they expressed a willingness to repeat those activities in which they achieved flow even if they were not being paid to do so.</p><p>
Athletes describe the same feeling as being in the zone. Bill Russell, a key player for the Boston Celtics during the period when they won 11 professional-basketball championships in 13 years, put it thus: “When it happened, I could feel my play rise to a new level. . . . It would surround not only me and the other Celtics, but also the players on the other team. . . . At that special level, all sorts of odd things happened. The game would be in the white heat of competition, and yet somehow I wouldn’t feel competitive. . . . I’d be putting out the maximum effort . . . and yet I never felt the pain.”<a class='link-footnote' rel='#footnote2' href='#' onclick='return false;'><sup>2</sup></a> <span id='footnote2' class='tooltip' style='display:none;'><span class='footnote-content'><span class='footnote-number'>2.</span><span class='footnote-text'>
William F. Russell, <i>Second Wind: The Memoirs of an Opinionated Man</i>, first edition, New York, NY: Random House, 1979.
</span><span class='clear'></span> </span><span class='footnote-bottom'></span></span></p><p>
Flow sounds great in theory, but few business leaders have mastered the skill of generating it reliably in the workplace. An easy first step is to consider what creates flow in your own work situation—a question we have put directly to more than 5,000 executives during workshops we’ve conducted over the last decade. In this exercise, individuals initially think about their own personal peak performance with a team, when, in other words, they have come closest to the feelings Csìkszentmihàlyi and Russell describe. Then they pinpoint the conditions that made this level of performance possible: what in the team environment was there more or less of than usual?</p><p>
The remarkably consistent answers we’ve received fall into three categories. The first set includes elements such as role clarity, a clear understanding of objectives, and access to the knowledge and resources needed to get the job done. These are what one might term rational elements of a flow experience or, to use a convenient shorthand, its intellectual quotient (IQ). When the IQ of a work environment is low, the energy employees bring to the workplace is misdirected and often conflicting.</p><p>
Another set of answers includes factors related to the quality of the interactions among those involved. Here, respondents often mention a baseline of trust and respect, constructive conflict, a sense of humor, a general feeling that “we’re in this together,” and the corresponding ability to collaborate effectively. These create an emotionally safe environment to pursue challenging goals or, to borrow from the writings of Daniel Goleman and others, an environment with a high emotional quotient (EQ). When the EQ of a workplace is lacking, employee energy dissipates in the form of office politics, ego management, and passive-aggressive avoidance of tough issues.</p><p>
While IQ and EQ are absolutely necessary to create the conditions for peak performance, they are far from sufficient. The longest list of words we have compiled from executives’ answers to our peak-performance question over the last ten years has little to do with either of these categories. This third one describes the peak-performance experience as involving high stakes; excitement; a challenge; and something that the individual feels matters, will make a difference, and hasn’t been done before. We describe this third category as the meaning quotient (MQ) of work. When a business environment’s MQ is low, employees put less energy into their work and see it as “just a job” that gives them little more than a paycheck.</p><p>
The opportunity cost of the missing meaning is enormous. When we ask executives during the peak-performance exercise how much more productive they were at their peak than they were on average, for example, we get a range of answers, but the most common at senior levels is an increase of five times. Most report that they and their employees are in the zone at work less than 10 percent of the time, though some claim to experience these feelings as much as 50 percent of it. If employees working in a high-IQ, high-EQ, and high-MQ environment are five times more productive at their peak than they are on average, consider what even a relatively modest 20-percentage-point increase in peak time would yield in overall workplace productivity—it would almost double.</p><p>
What’s more, when we ask executives to locate the bottlenecks to peak performance in their organizations, more than 90 percent choose MQ-related issues. They point out that much of the IQ tool kit is readily observable and central to what’s taught in business schools. The EQ tool kit, while “softer,” is now relatively well understood following Goleman’s popularization of the concept in the mid-1990s. The MQ tool kit is different.</p><h3>What to do differently</h3><p>
Business leaders, we know from other sources, are striving hard to find the missing MQ ingredients so they can improve motivation and workforce productivity. Late last year, for example, a survey (conducted by The Conference Board and McKinsey) of more than 500 US-based HR executives identified employee engagement as one of the top five critical human-capital priorities facing organizations.<a class='link-footnote' rel='#footnote3' href='#' onclick='return false;'><sup>3</sup></a> <span id='footnote3' class='tooltip' style='display:none;'><span class='footnote-content'><span class='footnote-number'>3.</span><span class='footnote-text'>
See <i>False Summit: The State of Human Capital 2012</i>, October 2012, a joint report from The Conference Board and McKinsey.
</span><span class='clear'></span> </span><span class='footnote-bottom'></span></span></p><p>
Management thinkers are also on the case. Gary Hamel urges modern managers to see themselves as “entrepreneurs of meaning.” In <i>The Progress Principle</i>, Harvard Business School professor Teresa Amabile and her coauthor Steve Kramer present rigorous field research highlighting the enormous benefits that a sense of forward momentum can have for employees’ “inner work life.”<a class='link-footnote' rel='#footnote4' href='#' onclick='return false;'><sup>4</sup></a> <span id='footnote4' class='tooltip' style='display:none;'><span class='footnote-content'><span class='footnote-number'>4.</span><span class='footnote-text'>
See Teresa Amabile and Steven Kramer, <i>The Progress Principle: Using Small Wins to Ignite Joy, Engagement, and Creativity at Work</i>, first edition, Boston, MA: Harvard Business School Publishing, 2011.
</span><span class='clear'></span> </span><span class='footnote-bottom'></span></span> Csìkszentmihàlyi writes extensively about “the making of meaning” in his book <i>Good Business</i>.<a class='link-footnote' rel='#footnote5' href='#' onclick='return false;'><sup>5</sup></a> <span id='footnote5' class='tooltip' style='display:none;'><span class='footnote-content'><span class='footnote-number'>5.</span><span class='footnote-text'>
See Mihàly Csìkszentmihàlyi, <i>Good Business: Leadership, Flow, and the Making of Meaning</i>, first edition, New York, NY: Viking, 2003.
</span><span class='clear'></span> </span><span class='footnote-bottom'></span></span></p><p>
In our experience, though, there’s often a disconnect between the desire of practitioners to create meaning in the workplace, the good ideas emerging from cutting-edge research, and the number of specific, practical, and reliable tools that leaders know how to use. Often, platitudes about communication, quality feedback, job flexibility, and empowerment are used as substitutes for such tools. Much of this amounts to little more than advice about how to be a good manager. Inspirational visions, along the lines of Walt Disney’s “make people happy” or Google’s “organize the world’s information,” have little relevance if you produce ball bearings or garage doors.</p><p>
In McKinsey’s research, we’ve uncovered a set of specific, actionable techniques underpinned both by experience and a significant body of social-science work. The full tool kit can be found in <i>Beyond Performance: How Great Organizations Build Ultimate Competitive Advantage</i>.<a class='link-footnote' rel='#footnote6' href='#' onclick='return false;'><sup>6</sup></a> <span id='footnote6' class='tooltip' style='display:none;'><span class='footnote-content'><span class='footnote-number'>6.</span><span class='footnote-text'>
Scott Keller and Colin Price, <i>Beyond Performance: How Great Organizations Build Ultimate Competitive Advantage</i>, first edition, Hoboken, NJ: John Wiley & Sons, 2011.
</span><span class='clear'></span> </span><span class='footnote-bottom'></span></span> The three examples described here are not only among the most counterintuitive (and therefore the most often overlooked) but also the most powerful.</p><h3 class="sm black">Strategy #1: Tell five stories at once</h3><p>We typically see organizational leaders tell two types of stories to inspire their teams. The first, the turnaround story, runs along the lines of “We’re performing below industry standard and must change dramatically to survive—incremental change is not sufficient to attract investors to our underperforming company.” The second, the good-to-great story, goes something like this: “We are capable of far more, given our assets, market position, skills, and loyal staff, and can become the undisputed leader in our industry for the foreseeable future.”</p><p>
The problem with both approaches is that the story centers on the company, and that will inspire some but by no means all employees. Our research shows that four other sources give individuals a sense of meaning, including their ability to have an impact on</p><ul class="leftContentUL"><li><p>society—for example, making a better society, building the community, or stewarding resources</p></li><li><p>the customer—for instance, making life easier and providing a superior service or product</p></li><li><p>the working team—for instance, a sense of belonging, a caring environment, or working together efficiently and effectively</p></li><li><p>themselves—examples include personal development, a higher paycheck or bonus, and a sense of empowerment</p></li></ul><p>
Surveys of hundreds of thousands of employees show that the split in most companies—regardless of management level, industry sector, or geography (developed or developing economies)—is roughly equal. It appears that these five sources are a universal human phenomenon.</p><p>
The implication for leaders seeking to create high-MQ environments is that a turnaround or a good-to-great story will strike a motivational chord with only 20 percent of the workforce. The same goes for a “change the world” vision like those of Disney and Google or appeals to individuals on a personal level. The way to unleash MQ-related organizational energy is to tell all five stories at once.</p><p>
A recent cost-reduction program at a large US financial-services company began with a rational-change story focused on the facts: expenses were growing faster than revenues. Three months into the program, it was clear that employee resistance was stymieing progress. The management team therefore worked together to recast the story to include elements related to society (more affordable housing), customers (increased simplicity and flexibility, fewer errors, more competitive prices), working teams (less duplication, more delegation, increased accountability, a faster pace), and individuals (bigger and more attractive jobs, a once-in-a-career opportunity to build turnaround skills, a great opportunity to “make your own” institution). The program was still <i>what</i> it was—a cost-reduction program—but the reasons it mattered were cast in far more meaningful terms.</p><p>
Within a month, the share of employees reporting that they were motivated to drive the change program forward jumped to 57 percent, from 35 percent, according to the company’s employee-morale pulse surveys. The program went on to exceed initial expectations, raising efficiency by 10 percent in the first year.</p><h3 class="sm black">Strategy #2: Let employees ‘write their own lottery ticket’</h3><p>The first strategy gives specific and practical guidance about how to <i>tell</i> the story. Yet the best meaning makers spend more time <i>asking</i> than telling.</p><p>
In one of Daniel Kahneman’s famous experiments, researchers ran a lottery with a twist. Half of the participants were randomly assigned a lottery ticket. The remaining half were given a blank piece of paper and asked to write down any number they pleased. Just before drawing the winning number, the researchers offered to buy back the tickets from their holders. The question they wanted to answer was how much more would you have to pay people who “wrote their own number” than people who received a number randomly. The rational answer should be no difference at all, since a lottery is pure chance, and therefore every ticket number, chosen or assigned, has the same odds of winning. A completely rational actor might even want to pay less for a freely chosen number, given the possibility of duplicate ones. The actual answer? Regardless of geography or demographics, researchers found they had to pay at least five times more to those who chose their own number.</p><p>
This result reveals a truth about human nature: when we choose for ourselves, we are far more committed to the outcome—by a factor of at least five to one.</p><p>
In business, of course, leaders can’t just let everyone decide their own direction. But they can still apply the lessons of the lottery-ticket experiment. The head of financial services at one global bank we know first wrote down his change story, shared it with his team for feedback, and then in effect asked all individual team members to write their own lottery ticket: what change story, in each of the businesses, supported the wider message? His team members in turn wrote change stories, shared them with <i>their</i> teams, and the process continued all the way to the front line. Although this method took far longer than the traditional road-show approach, the return on commitment to the program was considered well worth the investment and an important reason the bank achieved roughly two times its revenue-per-banker-improvement targets.</p><p>
Likewise, when Neville Isdell took charge at Coca-Cola, in 2004, he cocreated a turnaround strategy by bringing together his top 150 employees for three multiday “real work” sessions. The process was then cascaded further down into the organization, at small working meetings where participants could in effect write their own lottery ticket about the implications for their particular parts of the business. With hindsight, this process of creating and interactively cascading what became known as The Manifesto for Growth is seen as a pivotal intervention in a two-year turnaround in which the group stopped destroying shareholder value and generated returns of 20 percent, driven by volume increases equivalent to selling an extra 105 million bottles of Coke a day. In this period, staff turnover fell by 25 percent, and the company reported what external researchers called unprecedented increases in employee engagement for an organization of this size.</p><p>
Leaders who need to give their employees more of a sense of direction can still leverage the lottery-ticket insight by augmenting their telling of the story with asking about the story. David Farr, chairman and CEO of Emerson Electric, for example, is known for asking virtually everyone he encounters in the organization four questions: (1) how do you make a difference? (testing for alignment with the company’s direction); (2) what improvement idea are you working on? (emphasizing continuous improvement); (3) when did you last get coaching from your boss? (emphasizing the importance of people development); and (4) who is the enemy? (emphasizing the importance of “One Emerson” and no silos, as well as directing the staff’s energy toward the external threat). The motivational effect of this approach has been widely noted by Emerson employees.</p><h3 class="sm black">Strategy #3: Use small, unexpected rewards to motivate</h3><p>US author Upton Sinclair once wrote, “It is difficult to get a man to understand something when his salary depends upon his not understanding it.” The flip side, however, isn’t true. When business objectives are linked to compensation, the motivation to drive for results is rarely enhanced meaningfully.</p><p>
The reason is as practical as psychological. Most annual-compensation plans of executives are so full of key performance indicators that the weighting of any one objective becomes largely meaningless in the grand scheme of things. Furthermore, most compensation plans typically emphasize financial metrics whose results depend on myriad variables, many beyond individual control. On top of that, most companies don’t have deep enough pockets to make compensation a significant driver of MQ in the workplace.</p><p>
Leaders of organizations that successfully instill meaning understand the power of other methods. Terry Burnham and Jay Phelan’s book, <i>Mean Genes</i>,<a class='link-footnote' rel='#footnote7' href='#' onclick='return false;'><sup>7</sup></a> <span id='footnote7' class='tooltip' style='display:none;'><span class='footnote-content'><span class='footnote-number'>7.</span><span class='footnote-text'> Terry Burnham and Jay Phelan, <i>Mean Genes: From Sex to Money to Food: Taming Our Primal Instincts</i>, first edition, New York, NY: Perseus Publishing, 2000. 
</span><span class='clear'></span> </span><span class='footnote-bottom'></span></span> describes an experiment in which 50 percent of a group of people using a photocopier found a dime in the coin-return slot. When all were asked to rate their satisfaction level, those who got the dime scored an average of 6.5 on a scale of 1 to 7, while those who didn’t scored just 5.6. The lesson here is that when we aren’t expecting a reward, even a small one can have a disproportionate effect on our state of mind. And that’s also true of employees in the workplace.</p><p>
At ANZ Bank, John McFarlane gave all employees a bottle of champagne for Christmas, with a card thanking them for their work on a major change program. The CEO of Wells Fargo, John Stumpf, marked the first anniversary of its change program by sending out personal thank-you notes to all the employees who had been involved, with specific messages related to the impact of their individual work. Indra Nooyi, CEO of PepsiCo, sends the spouses of her top team handwritten thank-you letters. After seeing the impact of her own success on her mother during a visit to India, she began sending letters to the parents of her top team, too.</p><p>
Some managers might dismiss these as token gestures—but employees often tell us that the resulting boost in motivation and in connection to the leader and the company can last for months if not years. As Sam Walton, founder of Wal-Mart Stores, put it, “Nothing else can quite substitute for a few well-chosen, well-timed, sincere words of praise. They’re absolutely free—and worth a fortune.”</p><div class="articleBreak"></div><p>Of the three Qs that characterize a workplace likely to generate flow and inspire peak performance, we frequently hear from business leaders that MQ is the hardest to get right. Given the size of the prize for injecting meaning into people’s work lives, taking the time to implement strategies of the kind described here is surely among the most important investments a leader can make.<br /></p><div class="about-authors"><h3 class="sm black">About the authors</h3><p><b>Susie Cranston</b> is a senior expert in McKinsey’s San Francisco office, and <b>Scott Keller</b> is a director in the Southern California office.</p></div>]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Managing when vendor and supplier risk becomes your own</title>
      <description>Financial institutions are being held accountable for the actions of their suppliers. A new approach can help to identify and manage sources of third-party risk.</description>
      <link>http://www.mckinsey.com/insights/risk_management/managing_when_vendor_and_supplier_risk_becomes_your_own</link>
      <guid>http://www.mckinsey.com/insights/risk_management/managing_when_vendor_and_supplier_risk_becomes_your_own</guid>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Aug 2013 09:33:48 GMT</pubDate>
      <ID>016bd1b3-a3dc-4de3-b8ab-b4bd8f3053f0</ID>
      <category>Risk Management</category>
      <dc:creator><![CDATA[Hamid Samandari, John Walsh, and Emily Yueh]]></dc:creator>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>
<strong>The rising tide</strong> of regulatory scrutiny stemming from the global financial crisis has now reached beyond banks, to the companies that supply them. Under the broad notion that activities can be outsourced, but responsibility can’t, the Consumer Financial Protection Bureau (CFPB) and other regulators are holding financial institutions responsible not only for their own actions but also for those of their vendors and suppliers. In the past year, for example, American Express, Capital One, and Discover Bank have paid a total of more than $530 million to settle complaints of deceptive selling and predatory behavior by their third-party suppliers.</p>
<p>
This new regulatory thrust poses a big challenge for financial institutions because some of them have a limited perspective on their suppliers’ interactions with customers. The largest banks and credit-card companies can have close to 50,000 suppliers. They are quite careful about some of these relationships and often have teams to manage large and midsize suppliers. Of course, many vendors provide paper, computers, and other innocuous goods and services. But a significant number of vendor relationships are not closely managed, and some carry hidden risks. A company that molds and prints credit cards, for example, is entrusted with customer data, and that poses any number of privacy and security risks.</p>
<p>
At many institutions, vendor-management programs have focused predominantly on risks to the bank and the financial system—specifically, on business continuity, financial strength, and credit risk. With the scope of regulatory oversight broadening to include the consumer, many firms are underprepared. But since financial institutions must bear the responsibility for their suppliers’ misdeeds, they must improve the way they manage these relationships.</p>
<p>
In response to the changes, financial firms are looking for new solutions to identify and manage third-party risk. A number of leading banks and credit-card companies are developing and embracing best practices. Our research and experience have helped us develop a comprehensive approach to managing third-party risk. It consists of six essential steps, some of which can be executed in parallel.</p>
<h3>1. A comprehensive inventory of third parties</h3>
<p>
Regulators now expect institutions to know their third parties, how each of them interacts with consumers, and what activities it performs. Many firms do not have this information readily available. Supplier databases can be incomplete, and some of the most sensitive risks can reside in relationships that are not found in them. Cobranded partnerships, joint ventures, sponsorships, and similar relationships can account for up to 80 percent of the spending that some business units assign to suppliers. But these relationships are often managed in ways that emphasize commercial goals, with only a secondary focus on risk. What’s more, in some firms individual business units have different ways of tracking their suppliers, making it difficult to compare and collate them across an entire organization.</p>
<p>
In our experience, an effective database of third parties includes all of them—that is, any noncustomer entity with which a financial institution has a business relationship. An enterprise-wide survey is a good way to get started.</p>
<h3>2. A comprehensive catalog of third-party risks</h3>
<p>
To monitor consumer risk successfully, firms must develop a comprehensive catalog of these risks, also known as breakpoints, which form the basis for scorecards, audit routines, and other monitoring activities. Consider one breakpoint for a third-party call center: if there is a risk that agents will misrepresent product information to customers, a bank may investigate this specific problem by having calls monitored and may request regular reports on their quality and on customer-escalation metrics (exhibit). Identifying the relevant breakpoints for each category of suppliers and determining the relative weight and importance of every breakpoint can be challenging. Building a master register of breakpoints and their associated risk weights for all of these categories can help. Although broadly relevant to most firms, the master register can be adapted to the particular circumstances of an individual organization and its unique third-party relationships. This process is essential, as it helps the firm identify the true drivers of its risks and guides its mitigation program.</p>
[[exhibit 1]]
<h3>3. A risk-based segmentation</h3>
<p>
Once a firm has a complete inventory of third-party suppliers and the risks they pose to customers, it can segment its suppliers by risk level. Even a simple system of high-, medium-, and low-risk categories can be useful. We have observed that most leading institutions have 200 to 300 high-risk relationships at a time, irrespective of the total number of third parties with which they contract. An effective segmentation can help a firm determine how to utilize its resources strategically. It may, for example, conduct additional due diligence on high-risk relationships and automate regular reviews of low-risk suppliers.</p>
<p>
In our experience, firms typically use either of two approaches to segment third-party suppliers. Companies that follow the score-based approach conduct due diligence across all dimensions and use the results to develop a composite risk score. Although very thorough, this approach can be onerous and resource intensive for many organizations. Using the rules-based approach, a firm identifies specific rules or criteria for each segment and thereby streamlines the process of assigning suppliers to risk categories. In fact, this approach is about 40 to 60 percent faster than the score-based one. Given the importance of an approach to segmentation, leading institutions tend to invest heavily in designing it. Typically, they appoint a core team of risk experts to lead the design, the fine-tuning, and the implementation.</p>
<h3>4. A rules-based due-diligence test</h3>
<p>
Today, firms are expected to expand their due-diligence efforts beyond the traditional assessments for supplier, operational, and IT-security risks. Regulators are increasingly sensitive to strategic and reputational risks that third parties can create for customers. Traditional approaches align specific due-diligence activities with the risk category identified by the risk-based segmentation; a supplier in the high-risk category is subject to all due-diligence investigations. Like the score-based segmentation approach, this one can be overly onerous and resource intensive. Here too the rules-based approach can be a better answer because it triggers an appropriate set of due-diligence activities for the risks identified. For example, even if a third party is deemed to pose a high risk, an information-security or data-privacy screening is unnecessary if the supplier does not hold information that personally identifies customers. We estimate that the rules-based approach can cut employee time by close to 40 percent.   </p>
<h3>5. A disciplined governance and escalation process</h3>
<p>
Organizational alignment is particularly important when decision-making rights are spread across a range of businesses and functions, such as procurement, compliance, and operational-risk management. By proactively establishing governance structures and processes to address misalignments, institutions can resolve challenges quickly.</p>
<p>
Governance can be centralized or decentralized; both models (and some hybrids) can be successful. In the centralized model, most major risk decisions reside within a single group, such as procurement or shared services. While the centralized model identifies a clear and accountable “owner,” it can sometimes lead to tension between the business unit that has a working relationship with a third party and the centralized body accountable for risk assessments.</p>
<p>
In the decentralized model, the business unit that owns the relationship also manages the risk. This arrangement can sometimes result in a duplication of resources: several business units may, for example, assess a major third-party supplier for similar contracts. In some cases, the application and alignment of risk standards can be inconsistent in a decentralized model: the groups managing, say, procurement and operational risk could have different perspectives. A hybrid approach, carefully tailored to the organizational context, can help mitigate challenges associated with the two models as long as risk ownership is clear.</p>
<p>
An escalation framework is critical to resolve issues—such as requests for exceptions and the resolution of third-party breaches—that exceed the decision-making limits set out in the governance structure. While most organizations have an operational-risk management group, its governance model and mandate might not be sufficient to address the additional volume of third-party issues. In our experience, leading financial institutions often choose to assign new responsibilities to standing committees rather than create new ones to support third-party escalations. Each organization must find an appropriate approach given its appetite for risk and its culture.</p>
<h3>6. An integrated management-reporting and workflow process and tools</h3>
<p>
Clear, actionable management reports and well-designed workflow systems are essential for accountability across the business units, compliance, and audit. To work well, these tools must track and monitor the relevant data. More important, they must aid the workflow within and across business units and give managers a clear picture of real-time risk, with actionable recommendations. In our experience, most organizations currently have tools that address one or two of these functional needs, but to our knowledge none has a single tool that performs all three.</p>
<p>
Building a new third-party risk application from scratch is a big undertaking; so too is enhancing a current risk tool to perform new functions. Some firms have turned to off-the-shelf workflow- and risk-management tools that can easily be customized to an organization’s specific needs.</p>
<div class="articleBreak"></div>
<p>
Risks from vendors and suppliers pose a significant challenge to financial institutions. A systematic approach to managing those risks can lower costs and help banks present a coherent approach to all key stakeholders, including regulators.</p>
<p>For more on this research, download the full report, <em><a href="~/media/C7D004EEEE304157B6EEE717B1B3638B.ashx" data-analytics="Managing third party risk in a changing regulatory environment>download>pdf>body">Managing third-party risk in a changing regulatory environment</a></em> (PDF–625KB).</p>
<div class="about-authors">
<h6>About the authors</h6>
<p>
<strong>Hamid Samandari</strong> is a director in McKinsey’s New York office, where <strong>Emily Yueh</strong> is a consultant; <strong>John Walsh</strong> is a senior expert in the Washington, DC, office.</p>
<p>
The authors would like to thank Dmitry Krivin for his contribution to the development of this article.</p>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Three snapshots from China’s next chapter</title>
      <description>A new middle class. An urban transformation. An e-tailing revolution. This slideshow details the key trends that will define a new China.</description>
      <link>http://www.mckinsey.com/insights/economic_studies/three_snapshots_from_chinas_next_chapter</link>
      <guid>http://www.mckinsey.com/insights/economic_studies/three_snapshots_from_chinas_next_chapter</guid>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Jul 2013 13:53:10 GMT</pubDate>
      <ID>2ea004fa-89a4-4621-9d9e-81cf94486c06</ID>
      <category>Economic Studies</category>
      <dc:creator><![CDATA[Mckinsey]]></dc:creator>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><strong>To fully grasp</strong> China’s future direction, it is essential to understand its new middle class. A huge wave of increasingly affluent consumers will constitute China’s urban majority in less than a decade. The rapid emergence of this prosperous, digitally savvy, individualistic, and sophisticated class of consumers is creating opportunities and challenges for the companies that serve them. This slideshow looks at this consumer and urbanization phenomenon by the numbers. To understand, for example, how Singles Day—China’s alternative to Valentine’s Day—dwarfs Cyber Monday in the United States in online sales revenue, look inside.</p>
[[Interactive slideshow]]]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Long-haul China</title>
      <description>This photo-essay offers a passenger-seat view of China’s long-haul trucking industry.</description>
      <link>http://www.mckinsey.com/insights/travel_transportation/long-haul_china</link>
      <guid>http://www.mckinsey.com/insights/travel_transportation/long-haul_china</guid>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Jul 2013 10:09:20 GMT</pubDate>
      <ID>135b1e52-f6e1-4e75-a565-a6de49e03bdb</ID>
      <category>Travel &amp; Transportation</category>
      <dc:creator><![CDATA[Rachel Katz]]></dc:creator>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><strong>Long-distance trucking</strong>  is the backbone of China’s economy, yet the industry is fragmented and inefficient—particularly in the country’s interior. These photos capture the spirit of this disorganized but vibrant sector, whose continued modernization is critical to China’s economic development.</p>
[[Interactive slideshow]]<br />
<div class="about-authors">
<h6>About the author</h6>
<p><strong>Rachel Katz</strong> is a consultant in McKinsey’s San Francisco office. As a Fulbright Scholar during 2011, she conducted research on China’s trucking sector. Highlights of her work, now available at <a href="http://longhaulchina.com/" target="_blank">longhaulchina.com</a>, will soon be published as a book.</p>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Africa at work: Job creation and inclusive growth</title>
      <description />
      <link>http://www.mckinsey.com/insights/africa/a_test</link>
      <guid>http://www.mckinsey.com/insights/africa/a_test</guid>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Jul 2013 11:55:22 GMT</pubDate>
      <ID>43d94db0-63eb-43f1-bae4-eb007f2ddf52</ID>
      <category>Africa</category>
      <dc:creator><![CDATA[David Fine, Arend van Wamelen, Susan Lund, Armando Cabral, Mourad Taoufiki, Norbert Dörr, Acha Leke, Charles Roxburgh, Jörg Schubert and Paul Cook]]></dc:creator>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Africa is the world’s second-fastest-growing region. Poverty is falling, and around 90 million of its households have joined the world’s consuming classes—an increase of 31 million in just over a decade. But a new McKinsey Global Institute report, <em>Africa at work: Job creation and inclusive growth</em>, shows that the continent must create wage-paying jobs more quickly to sustain these successes and ensure that growth benefits the majority of its people. </p>
<p>Despite the creation of 37 million new and stable wage-paying jobs over the past decade, only 28 percent of Africa’s labor force holds such positions. Instead, some 63 percent of the total labor force engages in some form of self-employment or “vulnerable” employment, such as subsistence farming or urban street hawking. If the trends of the past decade continue, Africa will create 54 million new, stable wage-paying jobs over the next ten years—but this will not be enough to absorb the 122 million new entrants into the labor force expected over the same period. However, by implementing a five-part strategy to accelerate the pace of job creation, we estimate that Africa could add as many as 72 million new wage-paying jobs over the next decade, raising the wage-earning share of the labor force to 36 percent. </p>
<p class="mck_h6"><h6>Exhibit</h6></p>
<p class="mck_h6"><h6><img width="510" height="472" alt="Africa at work: Job creation and inclusive growth - Job creation acceleration" src="~/media/AFE1ED372EA04D4F9CB639A9F1B27306.ashx" /></h6></p>
<p><span class="mck_h3_sm"><h3>1. Identify one or more labor-intensive subsectors in which an African country has a global competitive advantage or could fill strong domestic demand.</span> Lesotho, for example, capitalized on the African Growth and Opportunity Act (2000), granting some African exports duty-free access to US markets. A landlocked nation surrounded entirely by South Africa, Lesotho developed industrial zones for the apparel industry and built rail links between them, offered incentives to foreign investors, and simplified the regulation of the sector. Today, Lesotho’s apparel exports to the United States are almost 100 times as large as South Africa’s on a per capita basis, and the sector is the single largest creator of jobs, employing about 40,000 people in 2008 in a country of just two million. </h3></span>
<p><span class="mck_h3_sm"><h3>2. Improve access to finance in target sectors. Cape Verde, for instance, encouraged foreign direct investment to ease financial constraints on its tourism sector.</span> To capitalize on the country’s beautiful beaches, it offered investors a five-year tax holiday, exemption from import duties, and unrestricted expatriation of profits. Revenues generated by foreign tourism increased from $23 million in 1999 to $542 million in 2008, and the sector now employs 21 percent of Cape Verde’s workforce. </h3></span>
<p><span class="mck_h3_sm"><h3>3. Build a suitable infrastructure. Countries that remove infrastructure constraints in target subsectors, particularly in export-oriented industries, can reap sizable benefits.</span> Mali’s exports of mangoes to the European Union, for example, grew sixfold between 2003 and 2008 after a concerted public–private program helped the country build integrated road, rail, and other infrastructure necessary to access export markets. These moves cut the transit time for shipments in half. </h3></span>
<p><span class="mck_h3_sm"><h3>4. Cut unnecessary regulations. Removing needless red tape in certain sectors is also important.</span> In Rwanda, for instance, streamlining the procedures needed to open a business dramatically increased the number of new companies, from only 700 a year before the reform to 3,000 a year today. </h3></span>
<p><span class="mck_h3_sm"><h3>5. Develop skills in target sectors. Around 40 percent of African workers now have at least some secondary education, and that share will rise to 48 percent by 2020.</span> Few employers in our survey of businesses in Egypt, Kenya, Nigeria, Senegal, and South Africa reported that a lack of skilled workers was a top barrier to growth. Still, Africa’s educational attainment lags behind that of other regions, and the continent would undoubtedly benefit from continued improvement. Two things are of particular importance: work readiness among school graduates and, in some countries, specific vocational skills. </h3></span>]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Can Africa continue to grow?Upated</title>
      <description>A panel of regional business leaders discusses its prospects.</description>
      <link>http://www.mckinsey.com/insights/africa/copy_of_can_africa_continue_to_grow</link>
      <guid>http://www.mckinsey.com/insights/africa/copy_of_can_africa_continue_to_grow</guid>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Jul 2013 11:55:21 GMT</pubDate>
      <ID>5525cbd6-93af-45bf-8f79-d9e6918640b1</ID>
      <category>Africa</category>
      <dc:creator><![CDATA[Mckinsey]]></dc:creator>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><strong>Gross corruption,</strong> constant wars, and irrational economics long made Africa a poor, troubled continent where natural-resource companies were almost the only multinationals that dared or cared to do business. But in the 1990s, the picture improved. The wars started subsiding. Many governments balanced their budgets and created a better, safer environment for companies, both foreign and domestic. And the African consumer began to stir. Now 80 million households earn at least the equivalent of $5,000 annually, the point where discretionary spending commences—an increase of 80 percent in eight years. Meanwhile, the continent’s GDP has been rising steadily, at around 5 percent a year, for the past decade, reaching $1.6 trillion in 2008. Last year, Africa was one of just two regions (the other was Asia) where GDP rose. </p>
<p>Is all this good news sustainable? At the 2010 Fortune Global Forum, in Cape Town, South Africa, McKinsey Publishing’s Rik Kirkland spoke with Absa’s Maria Ramos, Coca-Cola’s Bill Egbe, and McKinsey’s Norbert Dörr to find the answer.</p>
<!--roadblock-->
<p>Watch the video, or <a href="~/media/50D1DB095F594BAD8EEACEE13B4CC99E.ashx">download a PDF</a> of the transcript.</p>
<figure>
    <h4>Video</h4>
    <div>
      <h3></h3>
      <p>A panel of regional business leaders discusses its prospects.</p>
    </div>
    <video width="" height="" controls poster="http://brightcove.vo.llnwd.net/e1/pd/1971571337001/1971571337001_2553694144001_ChinaTech-VideoStill-1024x576.jpg?pubId=1971571337001">
      <source src="http://brightcove.vo.llnwd.net/e1/uds/pd/1971571337001/1971571337001_2522840653001_Chinatech-full.mp4" />
		</video>
    </figure>]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A yen for global growth: The Japanese experience in cross-border M&amp;A</title>
      <description>Japanese companies have embarked on an increasing number of international acquisitions in recent years. Can they learn from past failures and create value from cross-border deals?</description>
      <link>http://www.mckinsey.com/insights/asia-pacific/copy_of_a_yen_for_global_growth_the_japanese_experience_in_cross-border_m_and_38a</link>
      <guid>http://www.mckinsey.com/insights/asia-pacific/copy_of_a_yen_for_global_growth_the_japanese_experience_in_cross-border_m_and_38a</guid>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Jul 2013 11:53:24 GMT</pubDate>
      <ID>ca7d036f-648f-4526-ae8b-1981c6780971</ID>
      <category>Asia-Pacific</category>
      <dc:creator><![CDATA[Keiko Honda,  Keith Lostaglio, and Genki Oka]]></dc:creator>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><strong>An appreciating yen</strong> and a stagnant domestic market make global expansion a logical move for Japanese companies with bold growth aspirations. Indeed, Japanese companies are making international forays, albeit quietly: it is a little-reported fact that the number of outbound M&A deals in Japan has been on an upward trajectory in recent years. If the trend continues, Japanese cross-border M&A activity will soon surpass its 1990 peak. </p><p>
Deal levels would be even higher if Japanese companies were not haunted by past M&A failures. Pitfalls abound along the road to international M&A, and although some of them are now well-known and thus studiously circumvented, others—particularly those having to do with fundamental differences in business and management culture—seem almost impossible for Japanese companies to avoid. Retaining foreign talent presents a particular challenge. </p><p>
To gain insights into how Japanese companies should manage international acquisitions, we interviewed non-Japanese executives whose companies have been acquired by Japanese companies in large cross-border M&A deals within the past decade. We also conducted in-depth outside-in analyses on a handful of deals in which Japanese companies—such as Hitachi Construction Machinery, Suzuki Motors, Takeda Pharmaceuticals, and Toshiba—were able to boost international sales through cross-border M&A.<a class='link-footnote' rel='#footnote1' href='#' onclick='return false;'><sup>1</sup></a> <span id='footnote1' class='tooltip' style='display:none;'><span class='footnote-content'><span class='footnote-number'>1.</span><span class='footnote-text'>
We focused on deals in which the acquirer sought partial integration (neither full autonomy for the subsidiary nor a complete merger) since this is a common model applied by Japanese companies, many of which do not have the confidence to fully integrate an overseas entity.
</span><span class='clear'></span> </span><span class='footnote-bottom'></span></span></p><p>
Our findings indicate that there is no silver-bullet approach to capturing the greatest value from an international acquisition. Companies have had success using a variety of approaches, each tailored to the acquirer’s strategic intentions, its unique characteristics, and the dynamics of the industry. Although a company’s particular industry, context, and objectives should dictate the specific tactics it uses, the approaches we studied can give acquirers a starting point to consider—whether that starting point entails focusing on one such tactic or emulating all of them. </p><!--roadblock--><h3>Perspectives of the acquired</h3><p>
Most Japanese executives who have played the global M&A game are familiar with the most common obstacles: disagreement between the acquirer and the acquired over how much value ought to be captured immediately after the deal closes or the positioning of the new subsidiary within the parent company, assumptions by Japanese leaders that what works for their company must also work elsewhere, inattention to the acquired company’s employees, and a lack of postacquisition-management leadership and skills. </p><p>
What may be less familiar—and even surprising—to them are the observations of executives at US and European companies that have been acquired by Japanese companies. Interviews with executives from six such companies of various sizes (from $200 million to $1 billion in value) indicate a number of stumbling blocks. The first four, in particular, are detrimental to talent retention; they are the main reasons that non-Japanese executives do not stay long at such companies. </p><p><strong>A hands-off approach.</strong> Although Japanese executives may think the acquired company would prefer to be left alone—and although the parent company’s restraint may at first appear admirable and wise—many foreign executives come to feel that this is the wrong approach. One major benefit of being acquired, they say, should be that the subsidiary can fully leverage the capabilities of its parent company. Foreign executives want the acquirer to engage with its new subsidiary and jointly tackle issues as they arise. </p><p><strong>An ambiguous power structure.</strong> Non-Japanese executives have difficulty determining where the true power lies within a Japanese organization. For example, the deal executive in an M&A situation could have a lofty title (such as senior managing director). The target company might therefore focus on building a relationship with this person, continue to interact with him after the acquisition, and belatedly discover that he actually has no direct reports and no influence over day- to-day business. In one case, the deal executive was kept on staff only because he was a favorite of the former CEO. </p><p><strong>The tyranny of the middle.</strong> Our interviewees said that middle managers at the parent company can be destructive forces: they derive power from their proximity to the Japanese CEO and try to control information. A common example: if the acquired company requests additional capital investment for growth, middle managers may choose not to raise this request to the CEO. When the leaders of the acquired company follow up with the CEO a few months later, they learn that the CEO was never informed of the request. Incidents such as this can cause middle management to lose the respect of line leaders at the acquired company. </p><p><strong>The glass ceiling for foreigners.</strong> Japanese companies often have an insular culture. The general assumption is that a foreigner can rise only so high in the organization. Foreign executives thus consider leaving not because of unsatisfactory compensation but because they feel their careers are unfairly capped. </p><p><strong>Detail orientation.</strong> American and European executives have difficulty understanding Japanese attention to detail. A Japanese company’s due-diligence checklist, for example, is typically three times longer than that of an acquisition-savvy Western company, in part due to Japanese companies’ risk aversion. In a postacquisition setting, a Japanese company would want to understand, for instance, the discrepancy between a sales forecast and actual sales. It could very well decide to investigate assumptions made a year ago, whereas a Western company would care only about the actual sales figure and how to improve it. </p><p><strong>Poor postacquisition planning.</strong> Attention to detail notwithstanding, Japanese companies tend to be laissez-faire about what happens immediately after a deal closes. They do not see value in creating a concrete architecture in the interim to ensure a successful transition. Foreign executives often lament that transition governance and interim processes for decision making, resource allocation, and escalation of business-critical issues are insufficiently discussed. </p><p><strong>Sudden metamorphosis from friendly partner to distant boss.</strong> Our interviewees reported several experiences in which the initial integration phase was friendly and collaborative, then abruptly morphed into an intense discussion about steep cost reduction. Although this happens in non-Japanese settings as well, it is particularly pronounced in Japanese M&A because Japanese buyers can be extremely polite—to a point that foreigners sometimes find misleading. In one case, even though the acquirer had already decided to eliminate the target company’s research department, executives still made multiple visits to the target’s research sites to keep up appearances. When employees at the target company learned that the decision was made months ago, their trust in the parent company crumbled. </p><h3>Four approaches</h3><p>
To find out how Japanese companies have addressed one or more of these pitfalls, we examined the approach of the very small number of companies—14, to be exact—that completed at least five acquisitions during the past decade and generate more than half their revenues from overseas markets. In each of the deals we examined, the acquirer used a different postacquisition approach depending on the focus of the change program (exhibit). The approaches are not mutually exclusive. A company can emulate elements from all of them, depending on its particular industry, context, and objectives. </p> 
    <div id="v2">
      <h4></h4>
      <a exhibiturl="http://www.mckinsey.com/tools/Wrappers/Wrapper.aspx?sid={99992263-A222-42A3-AD60-0A7826166CAC}&amp;pid={CA7D036F-648F-4526-AE8B-1981C6780971}" exhibitwd="0" exhibitht="0">
        <h3></h3>
      </a>
      <p></p>
      <div>
        <a exhibiturl="http://www.mckinsey.com/tools/Wrappers/Wrapper.aspx?sid={99992263-A222-42A3-AD60-0A7826166CAC}&amp;pid={CA7D036F-648F-4526-AE8B-1981C6780971}" exhibitwd="0" exhibitht="0">
          <img width="510" data-nosvg="" src="">
        </a>
      </div>
    </div>
    <h3 class="sm black">Establishing mentorship or exchange programs to build leadership talent</h3><p>For acquirers whose main objectives include leadership development, one tactic involves pairing high-potential managers from the acquired company with an executive from the parent company as a coach and mentor. This helps build alignment between the acquirer and the acquired. The frequent and direct communication between leaders at both entities—without having to go through middle management—also allows for tighter coordination. </p><p>
When in 2002 Japanese automaker Suzuki Motor acquired a majority stake of Indian company Maruti Udyog, Suzuki engineered change at the top. It appointed a Suzuki executive as president and CEO of Maruti and took over 6 of the 11 board seats. But it also promoted four high-potential Maruti leaders—in sales, marketing, R&D, and administration—to corporate-officer roles and assigned each a functional executive from Suzuki as a mentor. The pairs were held jointly accountable for formulating new strategies. If postacquisition performance is any indication, the mentorship program has worked: Maruti’s sales have quadrupled, and profits are up 17 times from 2002 levels. </p><p>
Another promising tactic is two-way dispatch of executives (from acquirer to target and vice versa). When Takeda acquired US pharmaceutical company Millennium in 2008, it engineered an exchange of personnel to facilitate mutual understanding of corporate cultures. It invited Millennium’s CEO to join Takeda’s management team. Researchers from both companies traveled between Japan and the United States to strengthen their research capabilities. In 2011, Takeda transferred several Millennium researchers to its new research center in Japan. And Takeda recently named Millennium’s head of strategy—a Westerner—as head of business development for Takeda, showing the company’s openness to high-potential leaders from its subsidiary. Thanks to Millennium, which has been put in charge of all oncology efforts at Takeda, the company is now preparing to begin trials of three or four cancer-drug candidates per year—a significant increase from historical levels. </p><p>
These talent-development programs signal to foreign executives that the parent company is willing to invest in their professional advancement, giving them confidence that they can break through the perceived glass ceiling. </p><h3 class="sm black">Creating a special coordination unit at the division level</h3><p>
Another model entails the creation of a dedicated coordination office or unit to manage the integration. Depending on the company’s objective, the unit can be large or small. A large coordination office may make sense if there is a strong appetite for capturing value from cost synergies (by streamlining operations) and revenue synergies (by launching new initiatives that leverage both companies’ strengths). If the goal is intervention in one or two functions, a smaller, SWAT-type team may be more apt. In either case, the model helps avoid a leadership gap in postacquisition management. With a dedicated team, there is no question as to who is leading the integration effort. Toshiba acquired US-based Westinghouse Electric in 2006 to raise Toshiba’s global presence in nuclear generation. Toshiba sought to influence Westinghouse while also allowing it a degree of autonomy—which was critical, since the two companies had different types of nuclear technology. Toshiba set up two coordination offices: one within Westinghouse, whose members were drawn from Toshiba and its strategic partners Shaw Group and IHI (both of which had minority stakes in Westinghouse), and another within Toshiba. The offices worked together on strategy development and implementation. Three years later, Toshiba had record orders, including its first US orders for two large-scale projects. </p><p>
Hitachi Construction Machinery took a slightly different tack when it acquired a majority stake in Indian construction-equipment manufacturer Telcon, a joint venture with Tata Motors, in 2010. With the goal of increasing the quality of Telcon’s products, Hitachi dispatched seven Hitachi experts to the Telcon functions that needed fundamental change, such as quality assurance and product design. This specialist team, which was expanded in 2010, had full authority to direct Telcon’s performance-improvement efforts and created plans to optimize manufacturing processes, support services, and employee training. By creating a dedicated team, a company can begin to build internal skills that will prove useful in subsequent acquisitions. In the best cases, the individuals chosen for the coordination office are high-potential executives with excellent communication skills and business savvy. </p><h3 class="sm black">Developing local trainers as change agents</h3><p>In the third model, the front line is the focus of change. Employees from the foreign company are brought to Japan for “train the trainer” sessions that are more than a means of technology transfer— they also become opportunities to promote Japanese corporate values and management philosophy. These sessions help create a sense of belonging among the acquired employees that can, in turn, lead to greater motivation and higher employee-retention rates. </p><p>
When a Japanese manufacturer acquired a Southeast Asian company in 2006, it became the industry’s second-largest player. The acquirer was deliberate in how it chose to transfer its technology to its new subsidiary: it abandoned its traditional system of sending senior Japanese engineers to overseas subsidiaries to serve as trainers. Instead, select employees from the acquired company came to Japan for training, then returned to their home countries to train local employees. Approximately 700 non-Japanese employees have now undergone training in Japan; 60 of them have gone on to further study and been designated expert trainers. Although the Japanese corporation suffered along with the rest of the industry during the economic crisis, the combined company was recently able to beat the market leader for a high-profile contract—an achievement in which the new subsidiary played a critical role. </p><p>
By choosing not to dispatch its own employees but rather to bring in employees from the acquired company, Japanese companies can create room for “translation”: the change agents at the new subsidiary come to understand the corporate strategy and the vision for the integrated entity, and they develop a greater understanding of and appreciation for the technical advantages that each company offers. These change agents become effective champions of Japanese techniques and practices. </p><h3 class="sm black">Implementing company-wide culture-infusion programs</h3><p>
To infuse Japanese business culture into an acquired company, acquirers can launch initiatives that differ completely from those preceding them and ensure frequent communication on all fronts (for example, through employee newsletters or town halls). The most effective initiatives appear to be informal mechanisms that model Japanese norms while also bridging the divide between management and the front line. Company-wide programs, implemented correctly, can help motivate and retain target-company employees.</p><p>Suzuki, for instance, gave all Maruti employees sufficient exposure to Suzuki’s unique way of doing things. It promoted an open corporate culture, which was foreign and jarring in the Indian context. Top management and employees eat in the same cafeteria. Everyone, from the CEO to the factory worker, wears the same uniform to work. All employees—again, including the CEO—participate in morning exercise routines. (Although several Japanese companies hold dear the ritual of morning exercises, no others, to our knowledge, have introduced it at a non-Japanese subsidiary.)</p><div class="articleBreak"></div><p>These case examples should give Japanese executives the confidence to venture beyond Japan’s borders. Our findings indicate that there are a variety of promising approaches to postacquisition management and that leaders of Japanese companies must develop their own winning approach—sometimes through trial and error and constant refinement. Their first step should be to compile a list of acquisition targets that make sense given their strategic intentions. They should then come up with guiding principles and a blueprint for a postacquisition-management approach, tailored to their company’s strengths and the key value drivers of the industry. Japanese companies can—and indeed, if they want to grow, must—go global.<br /></p><div class="about-authors"><h3 class="sm black">About the authors</h3><p><b>Keiko Honda</b> is a director in McKinsey’s Tokyo office, where <b>Keith Lostaglio</b> and <b>Genki Oka</b> are partners.</p></div>]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A CEO’s guide to innovation in China in master</title>
      <description>Dynamic domestic players and focused multinationals are helping China churn out a growing number of innovative products and services. Intensifying competition lies ahead; here’s a road map for navigating it.</description>
      <link>http://www.mckinsey.com/insights/asia-pacific/copy_of_a_ceos_guide_to_innovation_in_china</link>
      <guid>http://www.mckinsey.com/insights/asia-pacific/copy_of_a_ceos_guide_to_innovation_in_china</guid>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Jul 2013 11:53:23 GMT</pubDate>
      <ID>2cbefcae-1fad-40a9-9438-1f536de7e419</ID>
      <category>Asia-Pacific</category>
      <dc:creator><![CDATA[Gordon Orr and Erik Roth]]></dc:creator>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><strong>China is innovating.</strong> Some of its achievements are visible: a doubling of the global percentage of patents granted to Chinese inventors since 2005, for example, and the growing role of Chinese companies in the wind- and solar-power industries. Other developments—such as advances by local companies in domestically oriented consumer electronics, instant messaging, and online gaming—may well be escaping the notice of executives who aren’t on the ground in China.</p>
<p>As innovation gains steam there, the stakes are rising for domestic and multinational companies alike. Prowess in innovation will not only become an increasingly important differentiator inside China but should also yield ideas and products that become serious competitors on the international stage.</p>
<!--roadblock-->
<p>Chinese companies and multinationals bring different strengths and weaknesses to this competition. The Chinese have traditionally had a bias toward innovation through commercialization—they are more comfortable than many Western companies are with putting a new product or service into the market quickly and improving its performance through subsequent generations. It is common for products to launch in a fraction of the time that it would take in more developed markets. While the quality of these early versions may be variable, subsequent ones improve rapidly.<a href="#" class="link-footnote" onclick="return false;" rel="#footnote1"><sup>1</sup></a> <span class="tooltip" id="footnote1" style="display: none;"><span class="footnote-content"><span class="footnote-number">1.</span><span class="footnote-text"> Commercialization differs from <i>shanzhai</i>, or “copycat innovation.” Many executives in the developed world misunderstand <i>shanzhai</i>, believing that it is purely the replication of an innovation developed in another market. Although this does occur, products developed through the <i>shanzhai</i> approach incorporate features specifically for the Chinese market. <i>Shanzhai</i> is quite prevalent in consumer products categories such as packaged goods and electronics. It can also be found in the business-to-business domain, where local companies produce knockoffs of successful foreign products or business models. </span><span class="clear"></span></span><span class="footnote-bottom"></span></span></p>
<p>Chinese companies also benefit from their government’s emphasis on indigenous innovation, underlined in the latest five-year plan. Chinese authorities view innovation as critical both to the domestic economy’s long-term health and to the global competitiveness of Chinese companies. China has already created the seeds of 22 Silicon Valley–like innovation hubs within the life sciences and biotech industries. In semiconductors, the government has been consolidating innovation clusters to create centers of manufacturing excellence.</p>
<p>But progress isn’t uniform across industries, and innovation capabilities vary significantly: several basic skills are at best nascent within a typical Chinese enterprise. Pain points include an absence of advanced techniques for understanding—analytically, not just intuitively—what customers really want, corporate cultures that don’t support risk taking, and a scarcity of the sort of internal collaboration that’s essential for developing new ideas.</p>

     <p>
    <details>
    <summary><strong>Improving the patent process</strong></summary>
    <figure>
      <table  cellspacing="0" cellpadding="1" border="1">
        <tr><td><p>
In innovative sectors such as biotechnology, electric vehicles, pharmaceuticals, and solar energy, the number of patent applications from Chinese companies is rising. In fact, Huawei and ZTE ranked among the world’s top five corporate patent registrants by volume in 2010. Intensifying patent activity reflects a growing recognition that intellectual property is essential to value. As this mentality takes hold, domestic innovators may pressure the government to create a more modern intellectual-property system.</p><p>
Currently, China recognizes three categories of patents: invention (what most people elsewhere think of as worthy of a patent), utility (a new use for something that already exists), and design. Invention patents run for 20 years, the others only for 10. Patent reform—such as reducing the duration of design or utility patents and raising the bar for what can be registered in those categories—would be a powerful way for the Chinese government to signal its seriousness about promoting indigenous innovation. If China decides to move ahead with patent reform, a desire for global consistency could well make it a high-priority multilateral issue.</p><p>Without patent reform, companies must rely on one of two strategies for protecting intellectual property. The first is to continue to outrun the competition by developing increasingly innovative solutions or building in protection through complex integration that is difficult to reverse-engineer. The second is to create easily identifiable technology “signatures” that would be hard to refute in legal proceedings.</p></td></tr>
      </table>
    </figure>
    </details></p>
    
<p>Multinationals are far stronger in these areas but face other challenges, such as high attrition among talented Chinese nationals that can slow efforts to create local innovation centers. Indeed, the contrasting capabilities of domestic and multinational players, along with the still-unsettled state of intellectual-property protection (see sidebar, “Improving the patent process”), create the potential for topsy-turvy competition, creative partnerships, and rapid change. This article seeks to lay out the current landscape for would-be innovators and to describe some of the priorities for domestic and multinational companies that hope to thrive in it.</p>
<h3>China’s innovation landscape</h3>
<p>Considerable innovation is occurring in China in both the business- to-consumer and business-to-business sectors. Although breakthroughs in either space generally go unrecognized by the broader global public, many multinational B2B competitors are acutely aware of the innovative strides the Chinese are making in sectors such as communications equipment and alternative energy. Interestingly, even as multinationals struggle to cope with Chinese innovation in some areas, they seem to be holding their own in others.</p>
<h3 class="sm black">The business-to-consumer visibility gap</h3>
<p>When European and US consumers think about what China makes, they reflexively turn to basic items such as textiles and toys, not necessarily the most innovative products and rarely associated with brand names.</p>
<p>In fact, though, much product innovation in China stays there. A visit to a shop of the Suning Appliance chain, the large Chinese consumer electronics retailer, is telling. There, you might find an Android-enabled television complete with an integrated Internet-browsing capability and preloaded apps that take users straight to some of the most popular Chinese Web sites and digital movie-streaming services. Even the picture quality and industrial design are comparable to those of high-end televisions from South Korean competitors.</p>
<p>We observe the same home-grown innovation in business models. Look, for example, at the online sector, especially Tencent’s QQ instant-messaging service and the Sina Corporation’s microblog, Weibo. These models, unique to China, are generating revenue and growing in ways that have not been duplicated anywhere in the world. QQ’s low, flat-rate pricing and active marketplace for online games generate tremendous value from hundreds of millions of Chinese users.</p>
<p>What’s keeping innovative products and business models confined to China? In general, its market is so large that domestic companies have little incentive to adapt successful products for sale abroad. In many cases, the skills and capabilities of these companies are oriented toward the domestic market, so even if they want to expand globally, they face high hurdles. Many senior executives, for example, are uncomfortable doing business outside their own geography and language. Furthermore, the success of many Chinese models depends on local resources—for example, lower-cost labor, inexpensive land, and access to capital or intellectual property—that are difficult to replicate elsewhere. Take the case of mobile handsets: most Chinese manufacturers would be subject to significant intellectual property–driven licensing fees if they sold their products outside China.</p>
<h3 class="sm black">Successes in business to business</h3>
<p>Several Chinese B2B sectors are establishing a track record of innovation domestically and globally. The Chinese communications equipment industry, for instance, is a peer of developed-world companies in quality. Market acceptance has expanded well beyond the historical presence in emerging markets to include Europe’s most demanding customers, such as France Télécom and Vodafone.</p>
<p>Pharmaceuticals are another area where China has made big strides. In the 1980s and 1990s, the country was a bit player in the discovery of new chemical entities. By the next decade, however, China’s sophistication had grown dramatically. More than 20 chemical compounds discovered and developed in China are currently undergoing clinical trials.</p>
<img alt="China solar-cell factory" src="~/media/McKinsey/dotcom/Insights/Asia-Pacific/A CEOs guide to innovation in China/solar-cell.ashx?mw=510">
<p class="grayNote small">Workers produce solar-cell modules in a factory in China’s Jiangsu Province.<br>© Imaginechina/Corbis</p>
<p>China’s solar- and wind-power industries are also taking center stage. The country will become the world’s largest market for renewable-energy technology, and it already has some of the sector’s biggest companies, providing critical components for the industry globally. Chinese companies not only enjoy scale advantages but also, in the case of solar, use new manufacturing techniques to improve the efficiency of solar panels.</p>
<p>Success in B2B innovation has benefited greatly from friendly government policies, such as establishing market access barriers; influencing the nature of cross-border collaborations by setting intellectual-property requirements in electric vehicles, high-speed trains, and other segments; and creating domestic-purchasing policies that favor Chinese-made goods and services. Many view these policies as loading the dice in favor of Chinese companies, but multinationals should be prepared for their continued enforcement.</p>
<img alt="Wind Turbine" src="~/media/McKinsey/dotcom/Insights/Asia-Pacific/A CEOs guide to innovation in China/turbine.ashx?mw=510">
<p class="grayNote small">Wind turbine manufacturing in China’s Shandong Province.<br>
© Guo Xulei/Xinhua Press/Corbis</p>
<p>Despite recent setbacks, an interesting example of how the Chinese government has moved to build an industry comes from high-speed rail. Before 2004, China’s efforts to develop it had limited success. Since then, a mix of two policies—encouraging technology transfer from multinationals (in return for market access) and a coordinated R&D-investment effort—has helped China Railways’ high-speed trains to dominate the local industry. The multinationals’ revenue in this sector has remained largely unchanged since the early 2000s.</p>
<p>But it is too simplistic to claim that government support is the only reason China has had some B2B success. The strength of the country’s scientific and technical talent is growing, and local companies increasingly bring real capabilities to the table. What’s more, a number of government-supported innovation efforts have <i>not</i> been successful. Some notable examples include attempts to develop an indigenous 3G telecommunications protocol called TDS-CDMA and to replace the global Wi-Fi standard with a China-only Internet security protocol, WAPI.</p>
<h3 class="sm black">Advantage, multinationals?</h3>
<p>Simultaneously, multinationals have been shaping China’s innovation landscape by leveraging global assets. Consider, for example, the joint venture between General Motors and the Shanghai Automotive Industry Corporation, which adapted a US minivan (Buick’s GL8) for use in the Chinese market and more recently introduced a version developed in China, for China. The model has proved hugely popular among executives.</p>
<p>In fact, the market for vehicles powered by internal-combustion engines remains dominated by multinationals, despite significant incentives and encouragement from the Chinese government, which had hoped that some domestic automakers would emerge as leaders by now. The continued strength of multinationals indicates how hard it is to break through in industries with 40 or 50 years of intellectual capital. Transferring the skills needed to design and manufacture complex engineering systems has proved a significant challenge requiring mentorship, the right culture, and time.</p>
<p>We are seeing the emergence of similar challenges in electric vehicles, where early indications suggest that the balance is swinging toward the multinationals because of superior product quality. By relying less on purely indigenous innovation, China is trying to make sure the electric-vehicle story has an ending different from that of its telecommunications protocol efforts. The government’s stated aspiration of having more than five million plug-in hybrid and battery electric vehicles on the road by 2020 is heavily supported by a mix of extensive subsidies and tax incentives for local companies, combined with strict market access rules for foreign companies and the creation of new revenue pools through government and public fleet-purchase programs. But the subsidies and incentives may not be enough to overcome the technical challenges of learning to build these vehicles, particularly if multinationals decline to invest with local companies.</p>
<h3>Four priorities for innovators in China</h3>
<p>There’s no magic formula for innovation—and that goes doubly for China, where the challenges and opportunities facing domestic and multinational players are so different. Some of the priorities we describe here, such as instilling a culture of risk taking and learning, are more pressing for Chinese companies. Others, such as retaining local talent, may be harder for multinationals. Collectively, these priorities include some of the critical variables that will influence which companies lead China’s innovation revolution and how far it goes.</p>
<img alt="China high-speed train" src="~/media/McKinsey/dotcom/Insights/Asia-Pacific/A CEOs guide to innovation in China/ChinaTrain.ashx?mw=510">
<p class="grayNote small">A Chinese-built high-speed train at the Wuhan Railway Station, in Wuhan, China.<br>© Guo Xulei/Xinhua Press/Corbis</p><h3 class="sm black">Deeply understanding Chinese customers</h3>
<p>Alibaba’s Web-based trading platform, Taobao, is a great example of a product that emerged from deep insights into how customers were underserved and their inability to connect with suppliers, as well as a sophisticated understanding of the Chinese banking system. This dominant marketplace enables thousands of Chinese manufacturers to find and transact with potential customers directly. What looks like a straightforward eBay-like trading platform actually embeds numerous significant innovations to support these transactions, such as an ability to facilitate electronic fund transfers and to account for idiosyncrasies in the national banking system. Taobao wouldn’t have happened without Alibaba’s deep, analytically driven understanding of customers.</p>
<p>Few Chinese companies have the systematic ability to develop a deep understanding of customers’ problems. Domestic players have traditionally had a manufacturing-led focus on reapplying existing business models to deliver products for fast-growing markets. These “push” models will find it increasingly hard to unlock pockets of profitable growth. Shifting from delivery to creation requires more local research and development, as well as the nurturing of more market-driven organizations that can combine insights into detailed Chinese customer preferences with a clear sense of how the local business environment is evolving. Requirements include both research techniques relevant to China and people with the experience to draw out actionable customer insights.</p>
<p>Many multinationals have these capabilities, but unless they have been operating in China for some years, they may well lack the domestic-market knowledge or relationships needed to apply them effectively. The solution—building a true domestic Chinese presence rather than an outpost—sounds obvious, but it’s difficult to carry out without commitment from the top. Too many companies fail by using “fly over” management. But some multinationals appear to be investing the necessary resources; for example, we recently met (separately) with top executives of two big industrial companies who were being transferred from the West to run global R&D organizations from Shanghai. The idea is to be closer to Chinese customers and the network of institutions and universities from which multinationals source talent.</p>
<h3 class="sm black">Retaining local talent</h3>
<p>China’s universities graduate more than 10,000 science PhDs each year, and increasing numbers of Chinese scientists working overseas are returning home. Multinationals in particular are struggling to tap this inflow of researchers and managers. A recent survey by the executive-recruiting firm Heidrick & Struggles found that 77 percent of the senior executives from multinational companies responding say they have difficulty attracting managers in China, while 91 percent regard employee turnover as their top talent challenge.</p>
<p>Retention is more of an issue for multinationals than for domestic companies, but as big foreign players raise their game, so must local ones. Chinese companies, for example, excel at creating a community-like environment to build loyalty to the institution. That helps keep some employees in place when competing offers arise, but it may not always be enough.</p>
<p>Talented Chinese employees increasingly recognize the benefits of being associated with a well-known foreign brand and like the mentorship and training that foreign companies can provide. So multinationals that commit themselves to developing meaningful career paths for Chinese employees should have a chance in the growing fight with their Chinese competitors for R&D talent. Initiatives might include in-house training courses or apprenticeship programs, perhaps with local universities. General Motors sponsors projects in which professors and engineering departments at leading universities research issues of interest to the automaker. That helps it to develop closer relations with the institutions from which it recruits and to train students before they graduate.</p>
<p>Some multinationals energize Chinese engineers by shifting their roles from serving as capacity in a support of existing global programs to contributing significantly to new innovation thrusts, often aimed at the local market. This approach, increasingly common in the pharma industry, may hold lessons for other kinds of multinationals that have established R&D or innovation centers in China in recent years (read about AstraZeneca’s experience in “Three snapshots of Chinese innovation”). The keys to success include a clear objective— for instance, will activity support global programs or develop China-for-China innovations?—and a clear plan for attracting and retaining the talent needed to staff such centers. Too often, we visit impressive R&D facilities, stocked with the latest equipment, that are almost empty because staffing them has proved difficult.</p>
<h3 class="sm black">Instilling a culture of risk taking</h3>
<p>Failure is a required element of innovation, but it isn’t the norm in China, where a culture of obedience and adherence to rules prevails in most companies. Breaking or even bending them is not expected and rarely tolerated. To combat these attitudes, companies must find ways to make initiative taking more acceptable and better rewarded.</p>
<p>One approach we found, in a leading solar company, was to transfer risk from individual innovators to teams. Shared accountability and community support made increased risk taking and experimentation safer. The company has used these “innovation work groups” to develop everything from more efficient battery technology to new manufacturing processes. Team-based approaches also have proved effective for some multinationals trying to stimulate initiative taking (read about General Motors’ approach in “Three snapshots of Chinese innovation”).</p>
<p>How fast a culture of innovation takes off varies by industry. We see a much more rapid evolution toward the approach of Western companies in the way Chinese high-tech enterprises learn from their customers and how they apply that learning to create new products made for China (read a perspective on the evolution of its semiconductor sector in “Thee snapshots of Chinese innovation”). That approach is much less common at state-owned enterprises, since they are held back by hierarchical, benchmark-driven cultures.</p>
<h3 class="sm black">Promoting collaboration</h3>
<p>One area where multinationals currently have an edge is promoting collaboration and the internal collision of ideas, which can yield surprising new insights and business opportunities. In many Chinese companies, traditional organizational and cultural barriers inhibit such exchanges.</p>
<p>Although a lot of these companies have become more professional and adept at delivering products in large volumes, their ability to scale up an organization that can work collaboratively has not kept pace. Their rigorous, linear processes for bringing new products to market ensure rapid commercialization but create too many hand-offs where insights are lost and trade-offs for efficiency are promoted.</p>
<p>One Chinese consumer electronics company has repeatedly tried to improve the way it innovates. Senior management has called for new ideas and sponsored efforts to create new best-in-class processes, while junior engineers have designed high-quality prototypes. Yet the end result continues to be largely undifferentiated, incremental improvements. The biggest reason appears to be a lack of cross-company collaboration and a reliance on processes designed to build and reinforce scale in manufacturing. In effect, the technical and commercial sides of the business don’t cooperate in a way that would allow some potentially winning ideas to reach the market. As Chinese organizations mature, stories like this one may become rarer.</p>
<div class="articleBreak"></div>
<p>China hasn’t yet experienced a true innovation revolution. It will need time to evolve from a country of incremental innovation based on technology transfers to one where breakthrough innovation is common. The government will play a powerful role in that process, but ultimately it will be the actions of domestic companies and multinationals that dictate the pace of change—and determine who leads it.</p>
<div class="about-authors">
<h3 class="sm black">About the authors</h3>
<p><b>Gordon Orr</b> is a director in McKinsey’s Shanghai office, where <b>Erik Roth</b> is a principal.</p>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>IP Title</title>
      <description>descriptino</description>
      <link>http://www.mckinsey.com/insights/manufacturing/ip_article_testing</link>
      <guid>http://www.mckinsey.com/insights/manufacturing/ip_article_testing</guid>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Jul 2013 11:47:49 GMT</pubDate>
      <ID>3de1a048-04b3-47d3-b4c2-9dee7b03522b</ID>
      <category>Manufacturing</category>
      <dc:creator><![CDATA[authors]]></dc:creator>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<a href="~/media/30975660DA5C4C0D800900F1357D37A9.ashx">A_Winning_30_trillion_decathlon_intro</a>]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The value of China's emerging middle class</title>
      <description />
      <link>http://www.mckinsey.com/insights/china/copy_of_the_value_of_emerging_middle_class_in_china</link>
      <guid>http://www.mckinsey.com/insights/china/copy_of_the_value_of_emerging_middle_class_in_china</guid>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Jul 2013 17:02:47 GMT</pubDate>
      <ID>64af21ee-797e-4384-bf62-980dda096f3b</ID>
      <category>China</category>
      <dc:creator><![CDATA[Diana Farrell, Ulrich A. Gersch, and Elizabeth Stephenson]]></dc:creator>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>As global companies entered China, many focused mainly on serving China’s urban affluent consumers. However, if they continue this strategy of simply skimming the cream from the top, they risk missing the real opportunity–the emerging middle class.</p>

<p>During the next 20 years, a huge middle class with enormous spending power will emerge in China’s cities. As incomes increase, the spending patterns of this group of consumers will evolve, fueling various levels of growth across consumption categories. </p>
<p>Though the potential benefits are enormous, serving this middle class has unique challenges and companies will need to think creatively to succeed.</p>
<ul class="raqs">
    <li><a href="https://www.mckinseyquarterly.com/Economic_Studies/Productivity_Performance/The_value_of_Chinas_emerging_middle_class_1798?gp=1" target="_blank"><span class="ico sprite raquoIco"></span><span class="txtLg">Read more on the <em>McKinsey Quarterly</em> site</span> </a></li>
</ul>
<p> </p>]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Sample Article: An interview with a US Defense Department agency director</title>
      <description>David Fisher talks about his experiences after he went from the private sector to the biggest organization in the US government.</description>
      <link>http://www.mckinsey.com/insights/business_technology/br_sample_code</link>
      <guid>http://www.mckinsey.com/insights/business_technology/br_sample_code</guid>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 May 2013 22:14:08 GMT</pubDate>
      <ID>e53697a7-7602-4b6a-b006-933d282a01fd</ID>
      <category>Business  Technology</category>
      <dc:creator><![CDATA[James M. Kaplan and Kreg Nichols]]></dc:creator>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><strong>Public-sector entities,</strong> like many commercial ones, are increasingly undertaking large transformation programs to streamline and improve their core operations. Nowhere is this task more challenging than in the US Department of Defense (DoD), which is committed to transforming its business practices to support faster and more agile operations. This multiyear mission will touch all aspects of the DoD, which has annual net operating costs exceeding $620 billion—including more than $30 billion for technology—2.9 million people, and a supply chain involving 5.2 million items.</p>
<p>[[exhibit exhibit 3]]</p>
<p>
In 2005, the DoD established the Business Transformation Agency (BTA) to help guide transformation efforts throughout the department. The BTA’s responsibilities include deploying enterprise IT systems, publishing the Business Enterprise Architecture, and helping to carry out investment decisions. The agency, for example, oversees programs that manage pay and travel for the armed services, makes proposals to organizations such as the army and the navy (called “components” inside the Pentagon) about how they can transform themselves most effectively, and encourages standardization throughout the department.</p>

    <h4>Slideshow</h4>
    <div id="V2">
    <a id="interactive" onclick="newwindow=window.open ('http://www.mckinsey.com/tools/Wrappers/Wrapper.aspx?sid={E883F46C-3948-4DE2-8A0B-FA4BA2EE4956}&amp;pid={E53697A7-7602-4B6A-B006-933D282A01FD}','WrapperWindow','toolbar=no, location=no, directories=no, resizable=yes, status=no,titlebar = no,scrollbars=yes, top=0,width=750,height=550'); newwindow.focus();return false;"><h3></h3></a>
    <p>Explore, track, and customize four years of survey results on how businesses use new Web technologies and tools. - desc</p>
    <div>
      <a id="interactive" onclick="newwindow=window.open ('http://www.mckinsey.com/tools/Wrappers/Wrapper.aspx?sid={E883F46C-3948-4DE2-8A0B-FA4BA2EE4956}&pid={E53697A7-7602-4B6A-B006-933D282A01FD}','WrapperWindow','toolbar=no, location=no, directories=no, resizable=yes, status=no,titlebar = no,scrollbars=yes, top=0,width=1000,height=680'); newwindow.focus();return false;">
        <img id="svgImage" width="510" data-nosvg="http://www.mckinsey.com/~/media/McKinsey/dotcom/Insights/Business Technology/Business and Web 20 An interactive feature/Business and Web 20 An interactive feature_interactive.ashx" src="http://www.mckinsey.com/~/media/McKinsey/dotcom/Insights/Business Technology/Business and Web 20 An interactive feature/Business and Web 20 An interactive feature_interactive.ashx" style="border-width:0px;"/>
      </a>
    </div></div>
<p>
Few people have as good a position to reflect upon the DoD’s transformation as David Fisher, the BTA’s first official director. Fisher joined the DoD from Silicon Valley, where as a consultant he helped private-sector companies to implement large enterprise systems. As a special assistant to the deputy undersecretary of defense for financial management, Fisher helped guide an enterprise-level business transformation and served on the team that launched the BTA. McKinsey’s James Kaplan and Kreg Nichols met with him in his office, in Arlington, Virginia, near Washington, DC, to discuss the differences between public- and private-sector transformations, as well as what he has learned about managing megaprojects.</p>

     <p>
    <details>
    <summary><strong>Biography of David Fisher, director of the Department of Defense’s Business Transformation Agency</strong></summary>
    <figure>
      <table  cellspacing="0" cellpadding="1" border="1">
        <tr><td><p>David Fisher</p><p><img src='http://www.mckinsey.com/~/media/McKinsey/dotcom/Insights/Business Technology/Boosting performance in public-sector IT An interview with a US Defense Depart/spot_bope08.ashx' alt='David Fisher'/></p><p><B> Test Description </b> <i> for David Fisher</i></p></td></tr>
      </table>
    </figure>
    </details></p>
    
<p><strong>The <em>Quarterly</em>:</strong> Coming from Silicon Valley, how similar do you think the public and private sectors are?</p>
<p><strong>David Fisher:</strong> While the mission may be different, many of the business challenges are the same—for example, tracking supply chains or making certain that people are paid correctly and on time. But the public sector differs in some significant ways. For example, the scale is very different. The size and scope of the Department of Defense are challenging. The best way to think about our size is to take a look at our budget. In all, last year we had gross costs of over $600 billion, more than the sum of the revenues of, say, Wal-Mart, GE, and IBM. It’s enormous, and there’s nothing comparable to it in the private sector.</p>

<p>
Also, our leadership changes regularly—at least every eight years, when presidential administrations turn over, and generally more often. This is a challenge when you consider that huge organizations in the public and private sectors work at transformations for a long time, sometimes up to ten years, before really starting to reap the benefits. Paul Brinkley, the deputy undersecretary of defense for business transformation, reminds us that IBM was undergoing transformation for ten years before the company really started to reap the benefits of overhauling the supply chain, for example. Even in the best situations, transformations take a long time to accomplish. We look to commercial business for an indicative timeline, but you’d have to combine four or five of the Fortune 10 to get the scale of the DoD.</p>

    <h4>Interactive 2</h4>
    <div id="V2">
    <a id="interactive" onclick="newwindow=window.open ('http://www.mckinsey.com/tools/Wrappers/Wrapper.aspx?sid={638F4209-0F53-4138-AB2E-55E8F645DA14}&amp;pid={E53697A7-7602-4B6A-B006-933D282A01FD}','WrapperWindow','toolbar=no, location=no, directories=no, resizable=yes, status=no,titlebar = no,scrollbars=yes, top=0,width=750,height=550'); newwindow.focus();return false;"><h3>The worlds new growth frontier - 2</h3></a>
    <p>Explore, track, and customize four years of survey results on how businesses use new Web technologies and tools - 2</p>
    <div>
      <a id="interactive" onclick="newwindow=window.open ('http://www.mckinsey.com/tools/Wrappers/Wrapper.aspx?sid={638F4209-0F53-4138-AB2E-55E8F645DA14}&pid={E53697A7-7602-4B6A-B006-933D282A01FD}','WrapperWindow','toolbar=no, location=no, directories=no, resizable=yes, status=no,titlebar = no,scrollbars=yes, top=0,width=1000,height=680'); newwindow.focus();return false;">
        <img id="svgImage" width="510" data-nosvg="http://www.mckinsey.com/~/media/test/MoF_AsianFIG_ex1svg.ashx" src="http://www.mckinsey.com/~/media/test/MoF_AsianFIG_ex1svg.ashx" style="border-width:0px;"/>
      </a>
    </div></div>
<p><strong>The <em>Quarterly</em>:</strong> What have you been able to use from your commercial-sector experience?</p>
<p><strong>David Fisher:</strong> My experience working with large companies helped prepare me for this type of role by giving me a willingness to buck the cultural trend and to suggest new ways of doing business. The BTA has been trying to apply the best practices from the commercial world, especially about how we govern and manage IT investments. If there are processes that we can streamline to help programs deliver capabilities faster, without getting bogged down in some of the administrative activities, we try to do that.</p>

<p>
This can be hard to do in a complex, hierarchical environment like the Department of Defense. Fortunately, many people around me, who have more experience within the government culture, have proved to be tremendously valuable at identifying constraints we face in public projects—constraints that just wouldn’t be there in the private sector.</p>
<p>
The department has been trying to modernize the way it does business for a long time, and we still have a long way to go. Every administration tries, and I’m sure we make some progress each time. But on the whole, we’re not where we want to be—or where we need to be. We want to build on the good work that’s been done before us, but we also need to question previous actions that weren’t successful and to offer new solutions.</p>
<p><strong>The <em>Quarterly</em>:</strong> What are the goals of your transformation efforts?</p>
<p><strong>David Fisher:</strong> Our overall objective is to guide business transformation efforts at the enterprise level of the Department of Defense in order to improve the DoD’s ability to perform its mission. We do that sometimes directly, sometimes indirectly. The BTA has a combination of operational and technical roles to play—for example, we manage the systems that handle travel and payroll for about 1.5 million employees of the DoD. But a big part of our role is to identify skill sets that are scattered throughout the DoD and unite them so that its components can work better together. For example, we bring the functional people and the technical people together so that a set of data standards affecting multiple areas can be agreed on.</p>
<p>
Successful coordination among the components doesn’t come from exercising authority but rather from exerting influence. People in the components don’t have to open the door to us, and I’m not empowered to make them open the door. But if I can demonstrate value, they’re going to open the door to me, whether I’m empowered or not. It’s all about adding value. There are certain things that we have authority for, but even in an environment where you have authority, your authority will only carry you so far in the effort to move things forward in a positive direction.</p>
<p><strong>The <em>Quarterly</em>:</strong> What are the main challenges in deploying technology to support the transformation?</p>
<p><strong>David Fisher:</strong> We spend about $2 billion each year on IT business transformation, half of it on enterprise resource planning systems throughout the Department of Defense. Much of the work for these ERP systems focuses on deciding what should be centralized, at the DoD enterprise level, and what should be managed by components—the military services, defense agencies, combatant commands, and military health services. As in any large organization, the people at the enterprise level are consumers of information. As long as information in different systems can be aggregated in a standard way, these people can do their jobs. On the other hand, some decision making is distributed, occurring within organizations that make up the DoD. The challenge lies in the gray area. Where is it more effective to have a single system at the center as opposed to multiple versions that adhere to common standards?</p>
<p>
[video Sample Chaptered video]
We have 27 systems in our enterprise portfolio today, and many of these are centralized only because the components did not have the ability to run their own when these systems were implemented years ago. As the capabilities of the components mature, we must ask if there are more efficient and effective ways to complete those transactions while still providing the members of our cross-component community with the information they need to do their jobs.</p>
<p><strong>The <em>Quarterly</em>:</strong> How do you manage such a large-scale transformation?</p>
<p><strong>David Fisher:</strong> Much depends on governance and on discipline in setting and implementing standards. Consider our experience implementing a set of standards for financial data. Initially, the reaction in the field was that this would cost too much to embed in individual IT systems, so we came up with a two-pronged approach.</p>
<p>
In the short term, we agreed to create a bridge system to the components’ legacy accounting systems, to save costs. It wasn’t a perfect solution, but it moved us toward interoperable data at a relatively low cost in a short time frame. Our longer-term challenge involved integrating these standards into various ERP systems. It was critical to get this right, from the beginning. Again, the components’ managers were concerned that this would be expensive and difficult to integrate with their SAP and Oracle systems. So we deployed ERP experts among the components who worked with teams there to identify ways to configure the ERP systems so they could work with standardized data. It’s been very successful.</p>
<p><strong>The <em>Quarterly</em>:</strong> How do you keep people motivated and set performance measures?</p>
<p><strong>David Fisher:</strong> When I left the commercial environment, I thought one of the great things about leaving was putting behind me the need to meet quarterly profit-and-loss targets and to deal with the short-term decision making that results from a quarterly focus. But now that I don’t have those constraints, I miss having the motivation to hit quarterly numbers. So you have to look for different kinds of motivators to keep projects on time.</p>
<p>
The people who go into public service are unbelievably passionate about what they do. There is a tangible internal motivation about doing public service that is different from what you find in the commercial marketplace. It’s not something you can necessarily put your finger on, but it’s real. We appreciate that. It’s very important. That said, we have to find ways to measure accountability. In the commercial world, there’s the P&L—you’re held accountable for the numbers. We are always in search of ways to hold people accountable, not least because if you succeed at something, you want to be recognized for it.</p>
<p>
We and the rest of the Defense Department have recently begun to move away from an old tenure-based performance model to a new system—the National Security Personnel System—that is closer to pay for performance. This is the type of system that’s familiar to commercial enterprises, but it’s new to this public environment, so we had to spend some time explaining that the goals had to be objective, measurable, time constrained. It’s been somewhat controversial because not everyone likes this shift. But as a manager, I have found it a positive shift, especially in terms of getting people to think about time. Sometimes, impatience is exactly right because within the public sector, things do tend to run on for a while. We need to build in that internal motivator that makes people ask, what did I get done today?</p>
<p>
In the end, however, while people care about their compensation, just as they should, it’s a small part of what motivates people here. It’s about the contribution to public service. One of the things that rallies the passion of these folks is seeing that they’re making a difference on a national security–related issue that helps the people on the ground.</p>
<p><strong>The <em>Quarterly</em>:</strong> With such large-scale technology deployments, what have you learned about managing megaprojects?</p>
<p><strong>David Fisher:</strong> Many of the things that would portend a successful ERP implementation of small to medium size would portend success for the large programs at the DoD. We’ve looked at the top reasons ERP implementations fail. Many failures come down to governance, change management, requirements management, customization, the skill sets of the people involved, and testing. Those concepts are immutable, regardless of size and scale. Our challenge with these immense projects is that implementation takes such a long time, spanning several generations of IT development. That can be problematic and leave an opportunity for endless analysis and debate.</p>
<p>
It’s also important to clarify what we’re trying to optimize, since one person’s definition of the enterprise may be different from another’s. From my perspective, the enterprise is the Department of Defense. But if I go to the army or navy, they might define the enterprise differently; if they’re trying to optimize the army or navy as opposed to the DoD, we end up with different solutions.</p>
<p>
Let me give you one example of how the BTA’s involvement helped the army reexamine the scope of some of its systems to good effect. The army had three big ERP systems—one that handled finance and two for logistics (a more tactical system for the front end and a more wholesale system for the back end). All three systems were operating fairly independently. Our observation was that, although these independent systems may be optimizing the parts, they were suboptimizing the whole in terms of business processes, management, and the utilization of technology.</p>
[video Sample Video]
<p>
Through some pretty heavy engagements—some well received, others not—we were able to demonstrate that there was a better way to use technology to reduce risks the army would face in the way the systems communicated, reconciled data, and otherwise performed together. We recommended that the army connect the three systems more closely because, for example, each of the logistics transactions was eventually going to be a financial transaction. If you look at things that way from the beginning, it fosters an environment where you look at the business from end to end. The army has now adopted some of those concepts and has a cross-domain governance model. So we got the conversation going and it’s had this positive impact. We weren’t empowered to do any of that by our authority. We were passionate about it, and we were able to convince the army to let us in on the dialogue and help them come to decisions that represented a change for the better.</p>
<p><strong>The <em>Quarterly</em>:</strong> Any other big lessons to pass along?</p>
<p><strong>David Fisher:</strong> Question every assumption. We often assume that we have to do something in a certain way because it’s the policy or the way we’ve done it before. Question that assumption, and if it doesn’t make sense, find out who owns the policy or who owns the way it was done before. Even laws change. Sometimes the answer is no, and that’s it. But if you have a case that helps everyone to agree that the old way doesn’t make sense and that there’s a better way, a transformational way, of doing things, question the old way.  </p>
<div class="about-authors">
<h3 class="sm black">About the authors</h3>
<p><strong>James Kaplan</strong> is a principal in McKinsey’s New York office, and <strong>Kreg Nichols</strong> is an associate principal in the Atlanta office.</p>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Exploding the myths of offshoring</title>
      <description />
      <link>http://www.mckinsey.com/insights/employment_and_growth/exploding_the_myths_of_offshoring</link>
      <guid>http://www.mckinsey.com/insights/employment_and_growth/exploding_the_myths_of_offshoring</guid>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Apr 2013 08:30:46 GMT</pubDate>
      <ID>ac79713e-1645-4593-bf10-82206a72ec81</ID>
      <category>Employment and growth</category>
      <dc:creator><![CDATA[Martin N. Baily, Diana Farrell]]></dc:creator>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>With the digital revolution and the dramatic fall in international telecommunications costs comes the prospect that white-collar jobs—once insulated from global competition—can be performed offshore, in low-wage nations such as India, where labor can be hired for as little as one-tenth its cost in the United States. Call-center agents, data processors, medical technicians, and software programmers could all find their jobs at risk from the nation's growing trade in services with emerging markets. In fact, offshoring is frequently blamed for the agonizingly slow pace of job growth in the United States, despite a recovering economy.</p>
<p>Even free traders have wavered in their beliefs. Critics warn that millions of people in the United States will become jobless. The response from Congress has been to include in a fiscal 2004 spending bill a provision prohibiting federal agencies from outsourcing some kinds of work to private companies that use workers in foreign countries. Indeed, 23 states are considering similar restrictions; 4 have already passed them. Jobs and trade have become the hot-button issues of the 2004 presidential election race.</p>
<p>The current debate is misplaced, however, because the problem is neither trade itself nor globalization more broadly but rather the question of how the country should allocate the benefits of global trade. Trade in services, like other forms of international trade, benefits the United States as a whole by making the economic pie bigger and raising the standard of living. Outsourcing jobs abroad can help keep companies profitable, thereby preserving other US jobs. The cost savings can be used to lower prices and to offer consumers new and better types of services. By raising productivity, offshoring enables companies to invest more in the next-generation technologies and business ideas that create new jobs. And with the world's most flexible and innovative economy, the United States is uniquely positioned to benefit from the trend. After all, despite a large overall trade deficit, the country has consistently run a surplus in its international trade in services.</p>
<ul class="raqs">
    <li><a href="https://www.mckinseyquarterly.com/Operations/Exploding_the_myths_of_offshoring_1453" target="_blank"><span class="ico sprite raquoIco"></span><span class="txtLg">Read more on the <em>McKinsey Quarterly</em> site</span> </a></li>
</ul>]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Exploding the myths about offshoring</title>
      <description />
      <link>http://www.mckinsey.com/insights/employment_and_growth/exploding_the_myths_about_offshoring</link>
      <guid>http://www.mckinsey.com/insights/employment_and_growth/exploding_the_myths_about_offshoring</guid>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Apr 2013 08:30:46 GMT</pubDate>
      <ID>2029f949-1f6d-4aca-9168-752d3dd74379</ID>
      <category>Employment and growth</category>
      <dc:creator><![CDATA[Martin N. Baily, Diana Farrell]]></dc:creator>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>In this essay, Martin Baily, a Senior Fellow at the Institute for International Economics and a Senior Advisor to the McKinsey Global Institute (MGI), and Diana Farrell, Director, MGI, reflect on the current heated debate about offshoring and put the issue in perspective. The authors cite MGI research that demonstrates the sizeable benefits the US stands to gain from offshoring through corporate savings, additional exports, repatriated profits, greater productivity, and new jobs.</p>
<p>While free trade creates wealth and improves a nation's standard of living, not all groups reap the same benefits, particularly in the short term. The reality of the emerging global economy is that the workforce is experiencing higher turnover than ever before. The challenge is how to make that inevitable process less painful and share more of the wealth being created.</p>
<p>Baily and Farrell cite concrete options for political and business leaders to help workers make the transition. Developing countries on their end must open their economies to attain the full benefits that free trade makes possible. Case evidence from MGI's research demonstrates how developing countries benefit from foreign direct investment. By resisting further liberalization, developing economies risk missing out on tremendous growth opportunities. </p>]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
