<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:itunes="http://www.itunes.com/dtds/podcast-1.0.dtd" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:georss="http://www.georss.org/georss" xmlns:fh="http://purl.org/syndication/history/1.0">
  <channel>
    <title>McKinsey Insights &amp; Publications</title>
    <link>http://www.mckinsey.com/en/insights</link>
    <description>McKinsey Insights &amp; Publications RSS Feeds</description>
    <language>en</language>
    <managingEditor>test@mckinsey.com (DotCom Team)</managingEditor>
    <webMaster>web@mckinsey.com (DotCom Team)</webMaster>
    <pubDate>Fri, 20 Sep 2013 20:03:09 GMT</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 26 Sep 2013 12:03:30 GMT</lastBuildDate>
    <category domain="Syndic8">Business</category>
    <ttl>5</ttl>
    <skipDays>
      <day>Monday</day>
      <day>Tuesday</day>
      <day>Sunday</day>
    </skipDays>
    <image>
      <url>http://www.mckinsey.com/~/media/McKinsey/dotcom/Global/logo_mckinsey-quarterly.ashx</url>
      <title>McKinsey Insights &amp; Publications</title>
    </image>
    <fh:incremental>false</fh:incremental>
    <atom:link rel="hub" href="http://pubsubhubbub.appspot.com" />
    <atom:link rel="self" href="http://cssrefactoring.mckinsey.com/insights/flipboardrss" />
    <copyright>Copyright (c) McKinsey &amp; Company. All rights reserved. Reprinted by permission.</copyright>
    <generator>Sitecore CMS: http://www.sitecore.net. Sitecore RSS module: McKinsey.RSS, Version=1.3.2.31452, Culture=neutral, PublicKeyToken=null</generator>
    <item>
      <title>A new world disorder</title>
      <description>Political-risk consultant Ian Bremmer discusses how the downturn is reshaping globalization.</description>
      <link>http://www.mckinsey.com/en/insights/globalization/a_new_world_disorder</link>
      <guid>http://www.mckinsey.com/en/insights/globalization/a_new_world_disorder</guid>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 May 2012 05:09:55 GMT</pubDate>
      <id>982a8a8e-e7f1-47b0-94b7-bc9fc17feb9a</id>
      <category>Globalization</category>
      <dc:creator><![CDATA[Mckinsey]]></dc:creator>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><strong>In this video interview, Ian Bremmer</strong> explains how a move away from globalization towards state-directed economic activity—as spurred by the downturn—will impact the geopolitical landscape and usher onto the world stage a new lineup of “winners and losers.” McKinsey’s director of publishing, Rik Kirkland, conducted this interview with Ian Bremmer in March 2009 in the New York office of Eurasia Group, the political-risk consultancy of which Bremmer is the president and founder.</p><p>
Watch the video, or read the transcript below.</p> <p><strong>Rik Kirkland:</strong> Hi, I’m Rik Kirkland, director of publishing at McKinsey & Company.  We’re here today with Ian Bremmer, president and founder of Eurasia Group, a leading political-risk consultancy. We’ve been in this era of open markets and rising globalization.  Is there something different now, in the wake of the crisis? Do you think that this has become a bigger issue?</p><p><strong>Ian Bremmer:</strong> Over the course of the last 20 years, as an investor, there was one thing you could not afford to get wrong, and that was globalization—that, increasingly, multinational corporations were becoming the most important global economic actors. They were taking advantage of global economies of scale. They were looking to maximize profitability—sometimes long term, sometimes short term.  But that process was inexorable. </p><p>
What we have seen over the course of the past six months is that that process has turned on its head; now globalization is no longer on an expansionist track; that states are becoming much more important in terms of their impact on the global market. So, it’s changed.</p><p>
The second point is that we now have been living in a much more global economy for a while. And so, as a consequence, we’ve come to rely on the fact that we will have access to these markets. During the period of the cold war, if the United States suddenly didn’t have access to the Soviet Union, it wasn’t a problem. If the Soviet Union had fallen apart or had perpetuated itself for another two, three, four decades, it wasn’t going to have a tremendous impact on the US economy. </p><p>
That’s not true today. The United States and China are married. They’ve got kids. They need each other. And, if the United States doesn’t have the same level of access to China’s markets, if the US doesn’t have the same level of access to Chinese surpluses—in terms of purchasing US Treasuries—the US has a serious problem, and so does the rest of the developed world. So, a move away from globalization toward state-directed economic activity has much greater impact now than at any point in the postwar period.</p><p><strong>Rik Kirkland:</strong> Let me ask you here to make a prediction. How would you describe the era you think we’re moving into over the next 5, 10, 15 years?</p><p><strong>Ian Bremmer:</strong> Well, I think that there are two different major trends that we’ll see over the coming years. The first is that state capitalism will increasingly prove a greater challenge to globalization. We will see it with the increasing power of national oil corporations, as opposed to multinationals; with state-owned enterprises in emerging markets becoming increasingly powerful, particularly in countries like China and Russia, also in the Gulf states; with the growth of sovereign wealth funds as increasingly important in the international investment climate; and, also, with the extraordinary impact of stimulus packages, which, you know, we may see as a stimulus, but other countries will see as protectionist and vice versa, regulatory frameworks and the rest.</p><p>
So, that is the first major development. The second major development is, we’ve been living in a world over the course of the past generation where the United States has been seen as the world’s singular, unipolar state. And we’re moving away from that, because the United States has neither the same political capital nor the political willingness to provide that heavy lifting, to ensure the provision of public goods on a whole host of different topics—whether we’re talking about nuclear proliferation or climate change or collective security in Iraq and Afghanistan or financial architecture globally. </p><p>
But as we move away from a US-led unipolar system, we’re moving toward a nonpolar system. Not a multipolar system—where different countries have strong interests, sometimes competing, in what the world will look like—but a nonpolar system, where there’s a greater abdication of global leadership.</p><p><strong>Rik Kirkland:</strong> No new power rising up to try to replace the US role, in other words.  </p><p><strong>Ian Bremmer:</strong> It’s not that there aren’t other countries that aren’t prepared to take leadership, but they’re not prepared to take <em>global</em> leadership. And so, what I think you’re seeing is that, you know, there clearly will be areas of regional leadership that will become stronger.</p><p>
But, these two major trends—the move to state capitalism and the move to nonpolarity—as we look out over the next 5, 10, 15 years, the most important point I can make is that they are not equilibrium states. They will create their own indigenous shocks. These global challenges that I talked about—the nuclear proliferation, the collective insecurity, climate change—these things aren’t going away. And in the absence of global leadership, we will see greater shocks to the system until we are jarred into a new geopolitical balance.  </p><p><strong>Rik Kirkland:</strong> You have a whole set of categories for best bets and authoritarian globalizers and others. Could you kind of take us on a little tour of the world, if you could?</p><p><strong>Ian Bremmer:</strong> I see sort of three big winners out there, over the medium to long term. First, there is the Chinese model. Their ability to stimulate the economy—in terms of infrastructure spending, in terms of creation of social safety net, in terms of pushing consumer spending—is vastly greater than anybody else out there.</p><p><strong>Rik Kirkland:</strong> So you’re not in the camp that thinks that the rise in unemployment or some of the social strains will put extraordinary pressure on the [Chinese] government or cause it to fracture in some way?</p><p><strong>Ian Bremmer:</strong> I do believe it’s putting pressure on the government, but I think the government is extremely well placed to deal with it. I certainly don’t believe it’ll cause it to fracture. They have built up an enormous store of political capital and support from Chinese citizens. Now, Chinese citizens are angry about the downturn—but they’re not blaming Beijing, they’re blaming the West. And I think the Chinese government is likely to make use of that. We already saw it recently with Chinese leaders definitively saying that the American political model is not for them.</p><p>
I don’t think those two things are a coincidence. And so we’re definitely going to see a more difficult environment for us to make money out of China. Maybe a more difficult environment for us to secure Chinese lending for American treasuries. But I think China, itself, will be resilient.</p><p>
 I like the Persian Gulf. A lot of political stability in those countries. Oil prices, of course, are lower, and they may drop lower still.</p><p><strong>Rik Kirkland:</strong> You’re talking about the Emirates and the Gulf [Cooperation] Council?</p><p><strong>Ian Bremmer:</strong> I am. In particular, I’m talking about Saudi Arabia, with only 25 million people, with very strong popularity of their king, Abdullah; with a succession model that looks much more stable and able to get through than a lot of people had feared before. [The country is] starting to unlock the untapped potential of women as employees within their country—50 percent of potential productivity that no one’s ever bothered with. Recently, now, they’re starting to. Over 50 percent of incoming university students in Saudi Arabia are women—one of the extraordinary stories there. And the fact that they are starting to look to really diversify their economy. But I also like Qatar; I like Kuwait; I like Bahrain.  I think the Gulf, in general, taking a longer-term view, will be able to get through this crisis relatively well. </p><p>
And then I’d say Brazil. Brazil’s changed. Lula’s changed. The political spectrum has really consolidated around the center. They’ve built a middle class that supports growth, that supports the creation of entrepreneurship in Brazil. They also are the Saudi Arabia of biofuels, and they have some of the world’s largest untapped oil reserves just to boot, off shore. Put all that together, Brazil looks very strong to me. And so, in this incredibly volatile environment, we do need to recognize there are some countries out there that are clearly going to outperform. And there are places that will be very attractive.</p><p><strong>Rik Kirkland:</strong> We have a G-20<a class='link-footnote' rel='#footnote1' href='#' onclick='return false;'><sup>1</sup></a> <span id='footnote1' class='tooltip' style='display:none;'><span class='footnote-content'><span class='footnote-number'>1.</span><span class='footnote-text'>
Group of 20. Comprises Argentina, Australia, Brazil, Canada, China, the European Union, France, Germany, India, Indonesia, Italy, Japan, Mexico, Russia, Saudi Arabia, South Africa, South Korea, Turkey, the United Kingdom, and the United States.</span><span class='clear'></span> </span><span class='footnote-bottom'></span></span> [summit] coming up. What are you hoping for? What do you think is going to happen?</p><p><strong>Ian Bremmer:</strong> I think that it’s likely that the G-20 is going to have a very strong statement of principles: free trade, no protectionism, need for coordination, importance of and recognition of the severity of the crisis. Beyond that, I do not expect that we’re going to see fundamentally new financial architecture, Bretton Woods II.  </p><p><strong>Rik Kirkland:</strong> Are we going to see a coordinated stimulus?</p><p><strong>Ian Bremmer:</strong> No. No, we’re not going to see coordinated stimulus, because stimulus is all about domestic politics—you go through legislatures; you’re dealing with domestic issues. </p><p>
Now, that does not mean we’re not going to see more stimulus that will <em>look</em> like it comes out of the G-20. We’re going to see more stimulus come out of Japan. If the G-20 can ride that wave and say, “We were a part of this,” God bless ’em. I think there will be some of that, and I think that will be seen as positive. I think what we will see will be expanded cash for the IMF<a class='link-footnote' rel='#footnote2' href='#' onclick='return false;'><sup>2</sup></a> <span id='footnote2' class='tooltip' style='display:none;'><span class='footnote-content'><span class='footnote-number'>2.</span><span class='footnote-text'>
International Monetary Fund.</span><span class='clear'></span> </span><span class='footnote-bottom'></span></span> for bailouts. And I think that that will not just be IMF as usual, I think, because a lot of that money will be coming out of the emerging economies, particularly out of Asia. I think there’s going to have to be some sort of agreement and movement on voting rights within the IMF.</p><p><strong>Rik Kirkland:</strong> Changing the weighting toward more developing countries?</p><p><strong>Ian Bremmer:</strong> I think so. I think that we’re going to see an evolution, which will be the beginning of a geopolitical shift to recognize this very, very quickly evolving geoeconomic change in the world.</p><p><strong>Rik Kirkland:</strong> One of the points you make is that a major strategic shift, or dislocation, in the world has been happening pretty much once a decade. So what are you looking at as you candidate for the next decade?</p><p><strong>Ian Bremmer:</strong> I’m looking at major discontinuities because the system is not in equilibrium. Now, I don’t know which of these discontinuities will hit. Could it be climate change? And not only climate change on a global scale, but, for example, China just through industrialization and growth, growth, growth, systematically destroying its own environment, water table, air, soil, to the degree that the country just collapses in on itself, social dissent becomes too great? I wouldn’t say 5 years, but 10, 15, 20 years? We could imagine that as one.</p><p>
Another one would be the fact that, as more countries go nuclear, some of these countries have connections to rogue organizations that have engaged in terrorist activities. Were we to see that over the next 10, 15, 20 years, that would dramatically change the way we think about sovereignty and the way we think about collective security and the international system.</p><p>
So, we can point to different sort of shocks becoming sufficiently large that they jar the system out of this absence of leadership and individual governments increasingly controlling economic transactions. That’s the environment we’ll be in.  </p><p><strong>Rik Kirkland:</strong> Ian Bremmer, thank you very much.  </p>]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Sample Article: An interview with a US Defense Department agency director</title>
      <description>David Fisher talks about his experiences after he went from the private sector to the biggest organization in the US government.</description>
      <link>http://www.mckinsey.com/en/insights/business_technology/br_sample_code</link>
      <guid>http://www.mckinsey.com/en/insights/business_technology/br_sample_code</guid>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 May 2013 12:44:08 GMT</pubDate>
      <id>e53697a7-7602-4b6a-b006-933d282a01fd</id>
      <category>Business  Technology</category>
      <dc:creator><![CDATA[James M. Kaplan and Kreg Nichols]]></dc:creator>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><strong>Public-sector entities,</strong> like many commercial ones, are increasingly undertaking large transformation programs to streamline and improve their core operations. Nowhere is this task more challenging than in the US Department of Defense (DoD), which is committed to transforming its business practices to support faster and more agile operations. This multiyear mission will touch all aspects of the DoD, which has annual net operating costs exceeding $620 billion—including more than $30 billion for technology—2.9 million people, and a supply chain involving 5.2 million items.</p>
<p>[[exhibit exhibit 3]]</p>
<p>
In 2005, the DoD established the Business Transformation Agency (BTA) to help guide transformation efforts throughout the department. The BTA’s responsibilities include deploying enterprise IT systems, publishing the Business Enterprise Architecture, and helping to carry out investment decisions. The agency, for example, oversees programs that manage pay and travel for the armed services, makes proposals to organizations such as the army and the navy (called “components” inside the Pentagon) about how they can transform themselves most effectively, and encourages standardization throughout the department.</p>

    <h4>Slideshow</h4>
    <div id="V2">
    <a id="interactive" onclick="newwindow=window.open ('http://www.mckinsey.com/tools/Wrappers/Wrapper.aspx?sid={E883F46C-3948-4DE2-8A0B-FA4BA2EE4956}&amp;pid={E53697A7-7602-4B6A-B006-933D282A01FD}','WrapperWindow','toolbar=no, location=no, directories=no, resizable=yes, status=no,titlebar = no,scrollbars=yes, top=0,width=750,height=550'); newwindow.focus();return false;"><h3></h3></a>
    <p>Explore, track, and customize four years of survey results on how businesses use new Web technologies and tools. - desc</p>
    <div>
      <a id="interactive" onclick="newwindow=window.open ('http://www.mckinsey.com/tools/Wrappers/Wrapper.aspx?sid={E883F46C-3948-4DE2-8A0B-FA4BA2EE4956}&pid={E53697A7-7602-4B6A-B006-933D282A01FD}','WrapperWindow','toolbar=no, location=no, directories=no, resizable=yes, status=no,titlebar = no,scrollbars=yes, top=0,width=1000,height=680'); newwindow.focus();return false;">
        <img id="svgImage" width="510" data-nosvg="http://www.mckinsey.com/~/media/1E03AFEB2E49453D9ADA376489CB3944.ashx" src="http://www.mckinsey.com/~/media/1E03AFEB2E49453D9ADA376489CB3944.ashx" style="border-width:0px;"/>
      </a>
    </div></div>
<p>
Few people have as good a position to reflect upon the DoD’s transformation as David Fisher, the BTA’s first official director. Fisher joined the DoD from Silicon Valley, where as a consultant he helped private-sector companies to implement large enterprise systems. As a special assistant to the deputy undersecretary of defense for financial management, Fisher helped guide an enterprise-level business transformation and served on the team that launched the BTA. McKinsey’s James Kaplan and Kreg Nichols met with him in his office, in Arlington, Virginia, near Washington, DC, to discuss the differences between public- and private-sector transformations, as well as what he has learned about managing megaprojects.</p>

     <p>
    <details>
    <summary><strong>Biography of David Fisher, director of the Department of Defense’s Business Transformation Agency</strong></summary>
    <figure>
      <table  cellspacing="0" cellpadding="1" border="1">
        <tr><td><p>David Fisher</p><p><img src='http://www.mckinsey.com/~/media/70C89718799A45DF99AAF4309261A337.ashx' alt='david'/></p><p><B> Test Description </b> <i> for David Fisher</i></p><p><p>Born in 1965, in San Francisco, California</p></p><p><p>Graduated with BA in communication in 1987 from Stanford University  </p><p>Earned MBA in 1998 from Leavey School of Business, Santa Clara University</p></p><p><p><strong>Department of Defense</strong></p><ul class="leftContentUL"><li><p>Director of Business Transformation Agency (2006–present) </p></li><li><p>Director, Transformation Planning and Performance (2005–06) </p></li></ul><p><strong>BearingPoint</strong></p><ul class="leftContentUL"><li><p>Managing director (2000–05)</p></li></ul></p><p><ul class="leftContentUL"><li><p>Author of <em>Optimize Now (or else!): How to Leverage Processes and Information to Achieve Enterprise Optimization (and Avoid Enterprise Extinction)</em></p></li><li><p>Speaker on business process optimization at conferences </p></li></ul></p></td></tr>
      </table>
    </figure>
    </details></p>
    
<p><strong>The <em>Quarterly</em>:</strong> Coming from Silicon Valley, how similar do you think the public and private sectors are?</p>
<p><strong>David Fisher:</strong> While the mission may be different, many of the business challenges are the same—for example, tracking supply chains or making certain that people are paid correctly and on time. But the public sector differs in some significant ways. For example, the scale is very different. The size and scope of the Department of Defense are challenging. The best way to think about our size is to take a look at our budget. In all, last year we had gross costs of over $600 billion, more than the sum of the revenues of, say, Wal-Mart, GE, and IBM. It’s enormous, and there’s nothing comparable to it in the private sector.</p>

<p>
Also, our leadership changes regularly—at least every eight years, when presidential administrations turn over, and generally more often. This is a challenge when you consider that huge organizations in the public and private sectors work at transformations for a long time, sometimes up to ten years, before really starting to reap the benefits. Paul Brinkley, the deputy undersecretary of defense for business transformation, reminds us that IBM was undergoing transformation for ten years before the company really started to reap the benefits of overhauling the supply chain, for example. Even in the best situations, transformations take a long time to accomplish. We look to commercial business for an indicative timeline, but you’d have to combine four or five of the Fortune 10 to get the scale of the DoD.</p>

    <h4>Interactive 2</h4>
    <div id="V2">
    <a id="interactive" onclick="newwindow=window.open ('http://www.mckinsey.com/tools/Wrappers/Wrapper.aspx?sid={638F4209-0F53-4138-AB2E-55E8F645DA14}&amp;pid={E53697A7-7602-4B6A-B006-933D282A01FD}','WrapperWindow','toolbar=no, location=no, directories=no, resizable=yes, status=no,titlebar = no,scrollbars=yes, top=0,width=750,height=550'); newwindow.focus();return false;"><h3>The worlds new growth frontier - 2</h3></a>
    <p>Explore, track, and customize four years of survey results on how businesses use new Web technologies and tools - 2</p>
    <div>
      <a id="interactive" onclick="newwindow=window.open ('http://www.mckinsey.com/tools/Wrappers/Wrapper.aspx?sid={638F4209-0F53-4138-AB2E-55E8F645DA14}&pid={E53697A7-7602-4B6A-B006-933D282A01FD}','WrapperWindow','toolbar=no, location=no, directories=no, resizable=yes, status=no,titlebar = no,scrollbars=yes, top=0,width=1000,height=680'); newwindow.focus();return false;">
        <img id="svgImage" width="510" data-nosvg="http://www.mckinsey.com/~/media/1E03AFEB2E49453D9ADA376489CB3944.ashx" src="http://www.mckinsey.com/~/media/1E03AFEB2E49453D9ADA376489CB3944.ashx" style="border-width:0px;"/>
      </a>
    </div></div>
<p><strong>The <em>Quarterly</em>:</strong> What have you been able to use from your commercial-sector experience?</p>
<p><strong>David Fisher:</strong> My experience working with large companies helped prepare me for this type of role by giving me a willingness to buck the cultural trend and to suggest new ways of doing business. The BTA has been trying to apply the best practices from the commercial world, especially about how we govern and manage IT investments. If there are processes that we can streamline to help programs deliver capabilities faster, without getting bogged down in some of the administrative activities, we try to do that.</p>

<p>
This can be hard to do in a complex, hierarchical environment like the Department of Defense. Fortunately, many people around me, who have more experience within the government culture, have proved to be tremendously valuable at identifying constraints we face in public projects—constraints that just wouldn’t be there in the private sector.</p>
<p>
The department has been trying to modernize the way it does business for a long time, and we still have a long way to go. Every administration tries, and I’m sure we make some progress each time. But on the whole, we’re not where we want to be—or where we need to be. We want to build on the good work that’s been done before us, but we also need to question previous actions that weren’t successful and to offer new solutions.</p>
<p><strong>The <em>Quarterly</em>:</strong> What are the goals of your transformation efforts?</p>
<p><strong>David Fisher:</strong> Our overall objective is to guide business transformation efforts at the enterprise level of the Department of Defense in order to improve the DoD’s ability to perform its mission. We do that sometimes directly, sometimes indirectly. The BTA has a combination of operational and technical roles to play—for example, we manage the systems that handle travel and payroll for about 1.5 million employees of the DoD. But a big part of our role is to identify skill sets that are scattered throughout the DoD and unite them so that its components can work better together. For example, we bring the functional people and the technical people together so that a set of data standards affecting multiple areas can be agreed on.</p>
<p>
Successful coordination among the components doesn’t come from exercising authority but rather from exerting influence. People in the components don’t have to open the door to us, and I’m not empowered to make them open the door. But if I can demonstrate value, they’re going to open the door to me, whether I’m empowered or not. It’s all about adding value. There are certain things that we have authority for, but even in an environment where you have authority, your authority will only carry you so far in the effort to move things forward in a positive direction.</p>
<p><strong>The <em>Quarterly</em>:</strong> What are the main challenges in deploying technology to support the transformation?</p>
<p><strong>David Fisher:</strong> We spend about $2 billion each year on IT business transformation, half of it on enterprise resource planning systems throughout the Department of Defense. Much of the work for these ERP systems focuses on deciding what should be centralized, at the DoD enterprise level, and what should be managed by components—the military services, defense agencies, combatant commands, and military health services. As in any large organization, the people at the enterprise level are consumers of information. As long as information in different systems can be aggregated in a standard way, these people can do their jobs. On the other hand, some decision making is distributed, occurring within organizations that make up the DoD. The challenge lies in the gray area. Where is it more effective to have a single system at the center as opposed to multiple versions that adhere to common standards?</p>
<p>
[video Sample Chaptered video]
We have 27 systems in our enterprise portfolio today, and many of these are centralized only because the components did not have the ability to run their own when these systems were implemented years ago. As the capabilities of the components mature, we must ask if there are more efficient and effective ways to complete those transactions while still providing the members of our cross-component community with the information they need to do their jobs.</p>
<p><strong>The <em>Quarterly</em>:</strong> How do you manage such a large-scale transformation?</p>
<p><strong>David Fisher:</strong> Much depends on governance and on discipline in setting and implementing standards. Consider our experience implementing a set of standards for financial data. Initially, the reaction in the field was that this would cost too much to embed in individual IT systems, so we came up with a two-pronged approach.</p>
<p>
In the short term, we agreed to create a bridge system to the components’ legacy accounting systems, to save costs. It wasn’t a perfect solution, but it moved us toward interoperable data at a relatively low cost in a short time frame. Our longer-term challenge involved integrating these standards into various ERP systems. It was critical to get this right, from the beginning. Again, the components’ managers were concerned that this would be expensive and difficult to integrate with their SAP and Oracle systems. So we deployed ERP experts among the components who worked with teams there to identify ways to configure the ERP systems so they could work with standardized data. It’s been very successful.</p>
<p><strong>The <em>Quarterly</em>:</strong> How do you keep people motivated and set performance measures?</p>
<p><strong>David Fisher:</strong> When I left the commercial environment, I thought one of the great things about leaving was putting behind me the need to meet quarterly profit-and-loss targets and to deal with the short-term decision making that results from a quarterly focus. But now that I don’t have those constraints, I miss having the motivation to hit quarterly numbers. So you have to look for different kinds of motivators to keep projects on time.</p>
<p>
The people who go into public service are unbelievably passionate about what they do. There is a tangible internal motivation about doing public service that is different from what you find in the commercial marketplace. It’s not something you can necessarily put your finger on, but it’s real. We appreciate that. It’s very important. That said, we have to find ways to measure accountability. In the commercial world, there’s the P&L—you’re held accountable for the numbers. We are always in search of ways to hold people accountable, not least because if you succeed at something, you want to be recognized for it.</p>
<p>
We and the rest of the Defense Department have recently begun to move away from an old tenure-based performance model to a new system—the National Security Personnel System—that is closer to pay for performance. This is the type of system that’s familiar to commercial enterprises, but it’s new to this public environment, so we had to spend some time explaining that the goals had to be objective, measurable, time constrained. It’s been somewhat controversial because not everyone likes this shift. But as a manager, I have found it a positive shift, especially in terms of getting people to think about time. Sometimes, impatience is exactly right because within the public sector, things do tend to run on for a while. We need to build in that internal motivator that makes people ask, what did I get done today?</p>
<p>
In the end, however, while people care about their compensation, just as they should, it’s a small part of what motivates people here. It’s about the contribution to public service. One of the things that rallies the passion of these folks is seeing that they’re making a difference on a national security–related issue that helps the people on the ground.</p>
<p><strong>The <em>Quarterly</em>:</strong> With such large-scale technology deployments, what have you learned about managing megaprojects?</p>
<p><strong>David Fisher:</strong> Many of the things that would portend a successful ERP implementation of small to medium size would portend success for the large programs at the DoD. We’ve looked at the top reasons ERP implementations fail. Many failures come down to governance, change management, requirements management, customization, the skill sets of the people involved, and testing. Those concepts are immutable, regardless of size and scale. Our challenge with these immense projects is that implementation takes such a long time, spanning several generations of IT development. That can be problematic and leave an opportunity for endless analysis and debate.</p>
<p>
It’s also important to clarify what we’re trying to optimize, since one person’s definition of the enterprise may be different from another’s. From my perspective, the enterprise is the Department of Defense. But if I go to the army or navy, they might define the enterprise differently; if they’re trying to optimize the army or navy as opposed to the DoD, we end up with different solutions.</p>
<p>
Let me give you one example of how the BTA’s involvement helped the army reexamine the scope of some of its systems to good effect. The army had three big ERP systems—one that handled finance and two for logistics (a more tactical system for the front end and a more wholesale system for the back end). All three systems were operating fairly independently. Our observation was that, although these independent systems may be optimizing the parts, they were suboptimizing the whole in terms of business processes, management, and the utilization of technology.</p>
[video Sample Video]
<p>
Through some pretty heavy engagements—some well received, others not—we were able to demonstrate that there was a better way to use technology to reduce risks the army would face in the way the systems communicated, reconciled data, and otherwise performed together. We recommended that the army connect the three systems more closely because, for example, each of the logistics transactions was eventually going to be a financial transaction. If you look at things that way from the beginning, it fosters an environment where you look at the business from end to end. The army has now adopted some of those concepts and has a cross-domain governance model. So we got the conversation going and it’s had this positive impact. We weren’t empowered to do any of that by our authority. We were passionate about it, and we were able to convince the army to let us in on the dialogue and help them come to decisions that represented a change for the better.</p>
<p><strong>The <em>Quarterly</em>:</strong> Any other big lessons to pass along?</p>
<p><strong>David Fisher:</strong> Question every assumption. We often assume that we have to do something in a certain way because it’s the policy or the way we’ve done it before. Question that assumption, and if it doesn’t make sense, find out who owns the policy or who owns the way it was done before. Even laws change. Sometimes the answer is no, and that’s it. But if you have a case that helps everyone to agree that the old way doesn’t make sense and that there’s a better way, a transformational way, of doing things, question the old way.  </p>
<div class="about-authors">
<h3 class="sm black">About the authors</h3>
<p><strong>James Kaplan</strong> is a principal in McKinsey’s New York office, and <strong>Kreg Nichols</strong> is an associate principal in the Atlanta office.</p>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How chief strategy officers think about their role: A roundtable</title>
      <description>Chief strategy officers from several high-profile companies discuss the complexities and challenges of the role.</description>
      <link>http://www.mckinsey.com/en/insights/strategy/copy_of_how_chief_strategy_officers_think_about_their_role_a_roundtable</link>
      <guid>http://www.mckinsey.com/en/insights/strategy/copy_of_how_chief_strategy_officers_think_about_their_role_a_roundtable</guid>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 Sep 2013 09:18:22 GMT</pubDate>
      <id>96e4e63a-3d55-420b-9ad4-2cf6f0ffaa75</id>
      <category>Strategy</category>
      <dc:creator><![CDATA[Renée Dye]]></dc:creator>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><strong>As companies struggle</strong> to meet the challenges of today’s complex business environment by developing short- and long-term strategic visions, the role of chief strategy officer (CSO) has become increasingly prominent. Although CEOs remain ultimately responsible for strategic decisions, they regularly look to the CSO to craft and implement successful strategies. But the role’s relative novelty raises critical questions about its function and the degree of ownership it carries.</p><p>
McKinsey recently brought together CSOs from several high-profile companies to discuss the challenges of the job—starting with its definition and what it entails. The panel included Edward C. Arditte, senior vice president of strategy and investor relations at the multi-industry company Tyco International; Stuart Grief, vice president of strategy and business development at the aircraft, industrial, and finance group Textron; Marius A. Haas, senior vice president of strategy and corporate development at the technology company HP; Dan Simpson, vice president, office of the chairman, at the cleaning-products group Clorox; Annabel Spring, managing director in charge of strategy and execution at the investment bank Morgan Stanley; and J. F. Van Kerckhove, vice president of corporate strategy at the e-commerce company eBay.</p><p>
Some of the panelists say that they have one foot in the corporate suite and the other deep in the business units. Others believe that while communication with the business units is very important, a CSO’s primary concern is the development of high-level strategy. In that capacity, CSOs grapple with the challenge of balancing short- and long-term goals: handling the multifaceted demands of an increasingly global business environment, they strive to focus on growth without losing sight of productivity. All panel members agree that a close relationship with the CEO is vital for instigating change, but they voice different views on other issues, such as how to interact with the finance function. Renée Dye, a consultant based in McKinsey’s Atlanta office, moderated the panel discussion.</p><p><strong>The <em>Quarterly</em>:</strong> How well defined is the role of the CSO?</p><p><strong>Dan Simpson:</strong> The role of the CSO is poorly defined, much like the discipline of strategy itself. Most other C-level executives have high levels of control over their disciplines, fairly clear ownership, and a large staff. But that isn’t true for the CSO. Many things affect the role, from the nature of the industry or company to the CSO’s reporting relationship. But the biggest factor is the style of the CEO, the true chief strategy officer.</p>
     <p>
    <details>
    <summary><strong>At the table</strong></summary>
    <figure>
      <table  cellspacing="0" cellpadding="1" border="1">
        <tr><td><p><img src='http://www.mckinsey.com/~/media/AE908AA9E367411695F9F6775C8DCF69.ashx' alt=''/></p><p><strong>Dan Simpson</strong>, vice president, office of the chairman, at Clorox, was head of strategy and planning for 16 years. Since joining Clorox, in 1979, he has had experience in brand management, finance, M&amp;A, and new-business development. </p><p><img src='http://www.mckinsey.com/~/media/FD362360F8D94F93A31A7CF0ED1469B5.ashx' alt=''/></p><p><strong>Stuart Grief</strong>, vice president of strategy and business development at Textron (2005–present), works closely with the senior leadership to create and implement strategies for the corporation and its business units. He is also a corporate officer and a member of Textron’s transformation leadership team.</p><p><img src='http://www.mckinsey.com/~/media/32081440B96B4797B08EC6BD3AAD88B5.ashx' alt=''/></p><p><strong>J. F. Van Kerckhove</strong>, vice president of corporate strategy at eBay (2007–present), is responsible for the strategic-planning and development process across eBay, Paypal, and Skype. Before joining eBay, he was an associate principal at McKinsey (1999–2005), where he specialized in product strategies for corporations and business units.</p><p><img src='http://www.mckinsey.com/~/media/86B3E0A800834134A24DC7F388F03E02.ashx' alt=''/></p><p><strong>Annabel Spring</strong>, managing director of Morgan Stanley (1994–present), is head of the firm’s strategy and execution group, which works directly with senior management to drive strategy, planning, and principal transactions.</p><p><img src='http://www.mckinsey.com/~/media/8A5076621B1245EC9CCF275FD6345D9F.ashx' alt=''/></p><p><strong>Marius A. Haas</strong>, senior vice president in the office of strategy and corporate development at HP (2002–present), leads the strategy and corporate development team, whose focus includes driving the strategy and planning processes, as well as managing new strategic initiatives.</p><p><img src='http://www.mckinsey.com/~/media/EE7CB5D5E81341A09A8B4677A1E8734F.ashx' alt=''/></p><p><strong>Edward C. Arditte</strong> is senior vice president of strategy and investor relations at Tyco International (2003–present), where he oversees strategic planning, investor relations, and external communications.</p></td></tr>
      </table>
    </figure>
    </details></p>
    <p><strong>Stuart Grief:</strong> The CEO makes the ultimate decisions, but it’s our job to explore the facts and alternatives around an issue. We make sure CEOs have a clear understanding of the implications of various choices so that they can make informed decisions. </p><p><strong>J. F. Van Kerckhove:</strong> The CEO is the ultimate owner of corporate strategy. A good strategy process finds the right balance between top-down and bottom-up engagement in developing strategy, building on the collective wisdom, and exposing its main assumptions. While the formulation of strategy often goes through specific planning milestones, its development is ongoing—at times explicit and at times not. The CSO plays an important role in helping to coordinate and inject knowledge in the more formal strategy process, as well as fostering an environment for more spontaneous strategy creation. The latter often finds its roots in a close collaboration with the business units or field operations at the forefront of experimentation and learning. In a fast-paced industry like ours, the ability to rapidly learn from the field is a true competitive advantage.</p><p><strong>Ed Arditte:</strong> That depends on your organizational structure and how many lines of business you have. In a more monolithic type of company, it’s easier to identify issues around which people can rally. For more diversified companies, like Tyco, strategy is driven by the businesses, with appropriate input and guidance from the corporate center. That has proved to be a better approach for us than approaching it from the center outward.</p><p><strong>Annabel Spring:</strong> I absolutely agree. Our role is to get feedback from the business units, overlay the global trends, and make sure that everybody has identified the right issues. We then prioritize the opportunities across the business units and provide a strategic element for that prioritization. Feedback from the business units is also critical for maintaining that entrepreneurial edge. Morgan Stanley is so specialized and yet complex and global, which is hard to balance.</p><p><strong>Marius Haas:</strong> The CSO’s role is dependent on CEOs not only because they have the final sign-off on strategy decisions but also because of their skill sets, tendencies, and way of managing the business. The question becomes: how do you complement the CEO’s strengths and weaknesses? My job at HP is to lay out the key initiatives we need to focus on in order to execute the plan. What are the initiatives that could build extra capacity, enhance our plan, or bring incremental operating profits or revenues? We go through those questions to get a sense of which ones need to mature and which ones are clearer from an execution standpoint.</p><p><strong>Annabel Spring:</strong> The market also affects the CSO’s role. When the market is up, the role addresses long-term vision and investment. When the market is down, it requires restructuring strategy. You have to be able to move with the market and with the CEO.</p><p><strong>Dan Simpson:</strong> Is it your role per se that varies according to market conditions, or does the difference lie more in the issues you address?</p><p><strong>Annabel Spring:</strong> “Role” is somewhat of an amorphous word. When the market is growing, it’s easier to see the big picture, sit back, and prioritize across opportunities. In a market downturn, it is very much a tighter, hand-holding role with the business units, and a much more operational one.</p><p><strong>Stuart Grief:</strong> I find Textron going in the opposite position, which may highlight the difference between industrial and financial companies. When the company is struggling, there’s a need to step back and reexamine things. When the company performs very well, people sometimes believe the good times will continue forever.</p><p><strong>The <em>Quarterly</em>:</strong> How does a company’s performance modify what the CSO does?</p><p><strong>Dan Simpson:</strong> Performance changes the issue set, not the role. During performance shortfalls, consistency and conviction become more important—horizons are closer and you focus all the water on short-term fires. But it’s not uncommon for short-term fixes to create long-term problems. A downward spiral develops momentum and becomes harder to turn around. While nearly everyone focuses on the near term, a CSO must be an advocate for long-term health.</p><p><strong>Marius Haas:</strong> That makes sense, but in our situation at HP, when the company wasn’t performing well, the solution required restructuring. The people running the business were so close to the business that they weren’t able to think outside of the box. The fundamental pieces were broken. We felt that driving for operational excellence was going to deliver more value for us in that period of time.</p><p><strong>Stuart Grief:</strong> If a company’s doing poorly, one of the first worthwhile diagnoses is an assessment of the quality of the strategy and its execution. If you’re happy with the strategy, you just need to focus operationally to get it done. I wasn’t at Textron at the time, but in 2000 and 2001, the leadership realized, “We’ve got a dead business model. We have to rebuild the company and transform it fundamentally.” It was a strategic issue in need of rewriting.</p><p><strong>Marius Haas:</strong> I was in a corporate-strategy team at Compaq about eight years ago, where the team spent way too much time focusing on the strategic, long-term view. The CEO liked this model, but none of the other executives felt there was any deliverable value. When I got into the role of CSO, I tried to build a bridge between the CEO and the executives in the business units. I wanted a model that pulled from all of them. You need to be able to dive into a business unit and become a core part of its strategy-setting and operational-excellence initiatives.</p><p><strong>The <em>Quarterly</em>:</strong> How do you ensure that strategy is executed well?</p><p><strong>Ed Arditte:</strong> At Tyco, it’s very clear. It is the responsibility of the businesses to act upon the plan, and it’s our responsibility, at the corporate center, to challenge and evaluate the plan. Once it’s approved, our job is to watch it and make sure the right people are being put on the bigger issues.</p><p><strong>The <em>Quarterly</em>:</strong> When we surveyed 800 executives on strategic planning in 2006, one of the most striking results was that only 36 percent of them said that the strategic plan was meaningfully integrated with human-resources processes—incentive, evaluation, and compensation systems. Does strategy play a role in evaluations?</p><p><strong>Ed Arditte:</strong> The responsibility is both in the short and long-term results. There has to be a balance, but there’s never a perfect answer for how you balance them. You need a dialogue that aligns resource allocation, people, and money with both the short and the long term.</p><p><strong>Stuart Grief:</strong> Balancing the short versus the long term is the biggest challenge we have. How do you balance the trade-off between the short-term compensation lift from near-term performance and the investments—and therefore the depressed economics, short term—that make the long-term strategies pay off?</p><p><strong>Marius Haas:</strong> An implementation plan that has clear milestones and owners is a must. Execution sits in the business units. At HP, we won’t make the hand-off until the business owner understands, accepts ownership, and acknowledges the need to deliver. As to the strategic plan as a whole, we’ve gotten a lot more disciplined. Now we can say, “Here are the levers within our plan that we need to execute in order to deliver. We know the plan, the capacity, and what we can do incrementally. If you’re going to show me a number, you’ve got to tell me how you’re going to get there.” Management has changed how people’s performance was going to be measured at a granular level.</p><p><strong>The <em>Quarterly</em>:</strong> What’s the dialogue like, though, when a business unit presents a plan that doesn’t have steadily increasing margins, because the unit wants to make a long-term investment that won’t pay off until beyond the current planning period?</p><p><strong>Marius Haas:</strong> We ask the business unit heads to build capacity in the plan and then reinvest that into areas they believe will be longer-term growth areas. Most of them have now divvied up their portfolios into three areas: emerging market opportunities and initiatives, mature but current businesses, and investments that help generate the required cash flow. We constantly look at that life cycle to see if those investments are in the right areas to generate longer-term growth. </p><p><strong>The <em>Quarterly</em>:</strong> Is there any advantage to having a closer relationship with the finance function?</p><p><strong>Annabel Spring:</strong> I think there is a significant advantage to being close to the CFO. I understand the budgeting and am involved in the process, both within the business units and at the corporate level. I’m part of the dialogue—which is critical for credibility and understanding the business. For Morgan Stanley in particular, being close to the CFO is important, given the number of transactions we do for the firm on a principal basis, because you need that back-and-forth relationship in order to be effective.</p><p><strong>Ed Arditte:</strong> There’s always a debate about who owns the strategy process—accountants, financial-planning people, or business people? But it shouldn’t be a question of where it’s owned, but of who is involved in the process. Do they work together? Are they able to achieve alignment? Alignment is key to the process: it defines what you want to do and, more important, makes sure that everybody understands the priorities. Then you can allocate the resources, evaluate the progress regularly, and provide support when necessary.</p><p><strong>Dan Simpson:</strong> People commonly confuse strategy and planning. Planning is primarily internal resource allocation and budgeting, which is clearly tied to finance. Resource allocation has to be driven by strategy but isn’t strategy in and of itself. Strategy should be focused on the marketplace and on customers and consumers. You must improve your position in the marketplace and have a clear idea about why people choose your products or services over someone else’s. At Clorox, we try to separate those conversations. One of the things we’ve done in the past is to bar financial components and exhibits from the first rounds of strategy meetings. That way, the discussion focuses on market competitiveness rather than on internal resource allocation.</p><p><strong>Stuart Grief:</strong> One of the challenges we used to face at Textron, though, was that without finance being deeply involved in the strategic discussions early on, we risked the CFO undoing the strategy three months down the road. A personal relationship with the CFO is really critical—more than reporting to the CFO. Alignment is vital on the road to execution.</p><p><strong>Marius Haas:</strong> Our plans require three things to be aligned: efficiency productivity, accelerating growth, and capital strategy, both financial and human. We’ve often taken resources out of the capital strategy to tackle inefficiency, generating capacity so we can invest in growth. In those cases, the triangulation of those key areas has been critical.</p><p><strong>Dan Simpson:</strong> Execution problems are often symptoms of trouble upstream in the strategy-development process—the strategy process has failed to realistically assess current reality, to honestly understand organizational capabilities, to align key players with those who do real work, or, at the end of the day, to create a compelling, externally driven vision of success.</p><p><strong>Ed Arditte:</strong> It depends on your organization and how centralized it is, but the more a strategic initiative is owned by the business units, the greater the chance of success. Many great corporate ideas fail in the business units because of a lack of ownership.</p><p><strong>The <em>Quarterly</em>:</strong> What are the most important issues facing strategists today?</p><p><strong>Stuart Grief:</strong> An important challenge is engaging with the businesses to think differently about what they do by helping them consider different business models, challenging the status quo, and avoiding complacency. It’s hard but necessary in an environment where competitors are more aggressive and diverse than ever.</p><p><strong>Marius Haas:</strong> The biggest challenge for us is transitioning from an efficiency–productivity focus to a growth focus without dropping the ball on the execution of the efficiency–productivity side. The second challenge lies in migrating external influences and forces to our mainstream thinking. If the customer and technology are evolving, we’re facing an environment of accelerated consolidation in the competitive landscape. Getting ahead of the pack and being the ones consolidating—versus having to react to actions taken by our competitors—is very important.</p><p><strong>Annabel Spring:</strong> I would echo the short-term versus long-term balance issues but add a layer of globalization. Short-term profit opportunities are abundant in the developed world, as long-term opportunities are in the developing world. You have to do both to get the continuous-growth profile we all need, but managing the timing is a very tricky thing—not to mention a core component of our role in terms of project prioritization, resource allocation, and long-term strategy.</p><p><strong>J. F. Van Kerckhove:</strong> Given rising customer expectations for the online experience, the high pace of innovation, and the emergence of new business models, we need to sharpen our game continuously and faster than ever, as well as assess what elements of our past success we need to strengthen and from which we need to depart. In that context, our main challenge is strengthening our core business while rapidly scaling our new growth platforms and developing new operational and organizational muscles for our future success. Just as our company has grown rapidly, so has its organizational complexity. We are focusing on simplifying how we do business, creating alignment behind a few clear priorities, and stepping up our organizational agility and effectiveness. </p><p><strong>Ed Arditte:</strong> As is probably true for everyone here, our businesses are exceedingly complex and growing more so every day. It doesn’t matter if this is driven by developed markets, emerging markets, financial markets, or technology—there are so many changes, and the pace has gotten much faster over the years. Taking a complex set of business issues and simplifying them is a key part of this role. We can’t do it individually, but we have to be facilitators of that process and get alignment around the truly important issues that will drive performance.</p><p><strong>Dan Simpson:</strong> Externally, our toughest strategic issue at Clorox is the consolidation and globalization of both the upstream cost structure and the downstream retail trade, offset by extreme fragmentation in the media environment. Change in the last 20 years has been extraordinary, and the implications for brand equity and value creation and distribution are profound.</p><div class="articleBreak"></div><p>
Internally, the toughest issues are exposing orthodoxies that constrain our thinking and options, as well as spreading priorities and resources across time horizons and business unit boundaries. Part of strategy’s role is to define external imperatives at a higher level so that investments spanning different time horizons or organizational units actually reinforce each other. </p><div class="about-authors"><h3 class="sm black">About the author</h3><p><strong>Renée Dye</strong> is a consultant in McKinsey’s Atlanta office.</p><p>The author wishes to thank Brock Anderson for his many contributions to this article. </p></div>]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Another oil shock?</title>
      <description>It’s possible, though far from certain, that oil prices will spike in the years ahead. Here’s why—and how you can prepare.
</description>
      <link>http://www.mckinsey.com/en/insights/energy_resources_materials/copy_of_another_oil_shock</link>
      <guid>http://www.mckinsey.com/en/insights/energy_resources_materials/copy_of_another_oil_shock</guid>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 Sep 2013 06:27:43 GMT</pubDate>
      <id>61019051-fb04-4c96-914e-aae67938d530</id>
      <category>Energy, Resources &amp; Materials</category>
      <dc:creator><![CDATA[Tom Janssens, Scott Nyquist, and Occo Roelofsen]]></dc:creator>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><strong>It’s been a while</strong> since the world has been truly preoccupied with the threat of sustained high oil prices. The global economic recovery has been muted, and a double-dip recession remains possible.</p>
<p>But that dour prospect shouldn’t make executives sanguine about the risk of another oil shock. Emerging markets are still in the midst of a historic transition toward greater energy consumption. When global economic performance becomes more robust, oil demand is likely to grow faster than supply capacity can. As that happens, at some point before too long supply and demand could collide—gently or ferociously.</p>
<p>The case for the benign scenario rests on a steady evolution away from oil consumption in areas such as transportation, chemical production, power, and home heating. Moves by many major economies to impose tougher automotive fuel efficiency standards are a step in this direction. However, fully achieving the needed transition will take more stringent regulation, such as the abolition of fuel subsidies in oil-producing countries, Asia, and elsewhere, as well as widespread consumer behavior changes. And historically, governments, companies, and consumers have been disinclined to tackle tough policy choices or make big changes until their backs are against the wall. </p>
<!--roadblock-->
<p>This inertia suggests another scenario—one that’s sufficiently plausible and underappreciated that we think it’s worth exploring: the prospect that within this decade, the world could experience a period of significant volatility, with oil prices leaping upward and oscillating between $125 and $175 a barrel (or higher) for some time. The resulting economic pain would be significant. Economic modeling by our colleagues suggests that by 2020, global GDP would be about $1.5 trillion smaller than expected, if oil prices spiked and stayed high for several years. </p>
<p>But like any difficult transition, this one also would create major opportunities—for consumers of energy to differentiate their cost structures from competitors that aren’t prepared and for a host of energy innovators to create substitutes for oil and tap into new sources of supply. Furthermore, if we endured a period of high and volatile prices that lasted for two or three years, by 2020 or so oil could face real competition from other energy sources. </p>

     <p>
    <details>
    <summary><strong>The automotive sector’s road to greater fuel efficiency</strong></summary>
    <figure>
      <table  cellspacing="0" cellpadding="1" border="1">
        <tr><td><p><b>Russel Hensley and Andreas Zielke</b></p><p><strong>Regulatory standards already in place</strong> should dramatically enhance the efficiency of autos around the world. The European Union’s carbon emissions rules, for example, require annual improvements of 6 percent a year between 2015 and 2020. This implies, according to our analysis, that new cars driving on European roads will consume 40 to 50 percent less fuel in 2020 than they did in 2010. Regulators in China, Japan, and the United States are also eyeing ambitious rates of improvement, albeit from different starting points. US fuel economy levels in 2020—at around 40 miles a gallon—would lag behind China’s in that year and simply match Europe’s 2010 levels. </p><p>
The automotive industry, boxed in by fierce global competition and flat prices, has responded in the past by pushing design improvements and productivity gains that make room for costly new content, including technology required for meeting regulatory standards. Here’s one example: if you adjust for inflation the cost of a 2001 Toyota Camry, you see that by 2010, the price of the car to US consumers had actually dropped by $2,500 in real terms—although the 2010 Camry was better equipped and 10 percent more fuel efficient. As automakers work hard to meet new and tougher fuel economy standards, they are likely to follow the same playbook. The starting point: improving internal-combustion engines, which still offer significant opportunities to enhance efficiency and emissions performance. On the other hand, high battery costs would be likely to require automakers to raise prices, making a sweeping shift to electric vehicles more difficult between now and, say, 2020. </p><p>
A sustained oil price spike could well prompt regulators in mature economies to up the ante—for example, by increasing support for electric vehicles—and speed a broader adoption of tougher standards in developing economies, which will represent most of the new demand for transportation fuel going forward. This would create additional momentum for change.</p><p>
Still, for a major shift in the global automotive stock to occur within the decade, consumer behavior or technology would need to change in dramatic and currently unforeseen ways. One possibility would be for a higher proportion of car buyers to begin prioritizing fuel economy. While the importance of this factor varies around the world, our consumer research suggests that in two major car markets, Germany and the United States, car buyers rank this attribute outside the top ten they consider when buying a new car.<a class='link-footnote' rel='#footnote4' href='#' onclick='return false;'><sup>1</sup></a> <span id='footnote4' class='tooltip' style='display:none;'><span class='footnote-content'><span class='footnote-number'>1.</span><span class='footnote-text'>
We conducted online interviews with 2,200 new-vehicle buyers in Germany and the United States. The sample included purchasers of cars, trucks, flex-fuel vehicles, and diesel vehicles, weighted to match the demographic characteristics and brand and power train preferences of each national market. Consumer rankings of attributes, derived through conjoint analysis, represented the implied importance attached to them by buyers. Implied importance often differs from stated importance but can be more accurate because it is less likely to reflect respondents’ beliefs about the answers they are “expected” to provide. 
</span><span class='clear'></span> </span><span class='footnote-bottom'></span></span></p><p>Significant consumer change is likely to require compelling economics that don’t take many years of ownership to realize. Comparing Europe and the United States highlights the magnitude of the challenge: although gasoline prices are twice as high in the former, the share of autos running on oil-based derivatives (gasoline and diesel) and alternative fuels is roughly the same in both. For the economics to become more appealing, advanced technology, especially electric-vehicle batteries, would need to come down the cost curve faster than expected while oil and gasoline prices crossed some new threshold of pain.</p><div class="about-authors"><h3 class="sm black">About the authors</h3><p><b>Russell Hensley</b> is a principal in McKinsey’s Detroit office, and <b>Andreas Zielke</b> is a director in the Berlin office.</p></div></td></tr>
      </table>
    </figure>
    </details></p>
    
<p>To paint a clearer picture for senior executives of what such a world would mean for them—and how to prepare now—we asked several colleagues to join us in a thought experiment about the impact of a prolonged oil price spike. Russell Hensley and Andreas Zielke, from McKinsey’s automotive practice, explain how intensified regulation already is leading a transition toward greater fuel economy, as well as the potential for higher oil prices to reinforce that momentum (see sidebar “The automotive sector’s road to greater fuel efficiency”). Jonathan Ablett, Lowell Bryan, and Sven Smit, from McKinsey’s strategy practice, assess the global economic impact of an oil price spike and the strategic implications of a slower-growth environment (see sidebar “Anticipating economic headwinds”). Finally, Knut Alicke and Tobias Meyer, from McKinsey’s operations practice, describe energy-efficient supply chain strategies that some companies are already undertaking (see sidebar “Building a supply chain that can withstand high oil prices”). </p>

     <p>
    <details>
    <summary><strong>Anticipating economic headwinds</strong></summary>
    <figure>
      <table  cellspacing="0" cellpadding="1" border="1">
        <tr><td><p><i>High, volatile oil prices would place a premium on fine-grained growth approaches and dynamic management processes.</i></p><p><b>Jonathan Ablett, Lowell Bryan, and Sven Smit</b></p><p><strong>If crude-oil prices rose</strong> to $125 or $150 a barrel and stayed there long enough—for years, not months—global growth would undoubtedly suffer. Indeed, we estimate that this type of shock would drive down global growth by 0.6 to 0.9 percentage points in the first year.<a class='link-footnote' rel='#footnote5' href='#' onclick='return false;'><sup>1</sup></a> <span id='footnote5' class='tooltip' style='display:none;'><span class='footnote-content'><span class='footnote-number'>1.</span><span class='footnote-text'>
All GDP and growth estimates in this article are the result of economic analysis we and our colleagues in McKinsey’s strategy practice conducted using the firm’s global-growth model, a tool for long-term scenario planning. The model links energy and capital markets to output and highlights relationships between growth and structural factors such as urbanization, education, and industry structure shifts. It can generate globally consistent scenarios for 20 countries, nine regions, and the world as a whole.
</span><span class='clear'></span> </span><span class='footnote-bottom'></span></span> Over time, as economies adjusted to the new higher prices (and shifted to different types of fuel, technologies, and production techniques) the impact would diminish. But the rate of global GDP growth would be affected for years. By 2020, the global economy would be between $1.1 trillion and $1.7 trillion smaller than the baseline outlook: the equivalent of losing Spain’s or Italy’s output for a year.</p><p>
A sustained growth drag of that magnitude would be serious, particularly for Europe and the United States, which are already suffering from sluggish recoveries and lingering unemployment. It could contribute to a double-dip recession in those markets and to trouble in the global economy as a whole, which also is fragile and faces other potential shocks, including sovereign-debt defaults, inflation in emerging markets, and problems in the Chinese financial sector.</p><p>
Senior executives can reduce the odds of getting whipsawed by the impact of an oil price spike if they push their planning teams to evaluate, at a fairly granular level, the likely growth impact of surging energy prices. Where are customers most vulnerable to energy cost increases, and where would they be less significant? In fact, our modeling suggests that the country-level impact of spiking oil prices would be quite uneven—and not just because of differences in the energy efficiency of various economies. Even more important, our analysis indicates, are variations in the relative size of the industrial sector in different countries. That means export-oriented advanced manufacturing economies, such as Germany and Japan, are more vulnerable than their relative energy efficiency might indicate (exhibit).</p> [[exhibit 2]]<p>
In addition, business leaders should be preparing for a world in which energy-related growth slowdowns could occur in an oscillating and unpredictable manner. For example, oil prices might fly up to a point (far in excess of $125 a barrel) where global GDP growth completely stalled and new sources of energy supply rapidly became economic. That, in turn, might drive prices down somewhat, leading to a resumption of economic growth and a repetition of the cycle. In a world like that, management approaches that some companies experimented with during the financial crisis—such as shorter financial-planning cycles or even moving away from calendar-based approaches to budgeting and planning—may be important.<a class='link-footnote' rel='#footnote6' href='#' onclick='return false;'><sup>2</sup></a> <span id='footnote6' class='tooltip' style='display:none;'><span class='footnote-content'><span class='footnote-number'>2.</span><span class='footnote-text'>
For more on principles for managing in extreme uncertainty, see Lowell Bryan, “<a href='http://www.mckinseyquarterly.com/article_page.aspx?ar=2475'>Dynamic management: Better decisions in uncertain times</a>,” mckinseyquarterly.com, December 2009.
</span><span class='clear'></span> </span><span class='footnote-bottom'></span></span></p><p>
When you combine the likelihood of oil price volatility with related uncertainties—such as the potential for swings in the dollar versus other currencies and commodities as global economic activity rebalances from the developed world toward emerging markets—you may want to abandon any presumption that you can predict medium-term oil prices.<a class='link-footnote' rel='#footnote7' href='#' onclick='return false;'><sup>3</sup></a> <span id='footnote7' class='tooltip' style='display:none;'><span class='footnote-content'><span class='footnote-number'>3.</span><span class='footnote-text'>
For more on uncertainties related to global economic rebalancing, see Lowell Bryan, “<a href='http://www.mckinseyquarterly.com/article_page.aspx?ar=2624'>Globalization’s critical imbalances</a>,” mckinseyquarterly.com, June 2010.
</span><span class='clear'></span> </span><span class='footnote-bottom'></span></span> Indeed, it may be more fruitful to stress-test your financial plans and strategies for different oil (and currency) prices, see what happens to the plans at the extremes, and then prepare for contingencies. One example: if oil prices rose significantly, that would accelerate the accumulation of capital by sovereign-wealth funds in oil-producing countries, complicating financing decisions and raising the importance of building strong relationships with a diverse group of capital suppliers.<a class='link-footnote' rel='#footnote8' href='#' onclick='return false;'><sup>4</sup></a> <span id='footnote8' class='tooltip' style='display:none;'><span class='footnote-content'><span class='footnote-number'>4.</span><span class='footnote-text'>
For more on diversifying sources of financing, see Richard Dobbs, Susan Lund, and Andreas Schreiner, “<a href='http://www.mckinseyquarterly.com/article_page.aspx?ar=2715'>How the growth of emerging markets will strain global finance</a>,” mckinseyquarterly.com, December 2010.
</span><span class='clear'></span> </span><span class='footnote-bottom'></span></span> In general, using multiple scenarios for even base-case planning, and developing a portfolio of responses to each scenario, will enable you to act swiftly when you can see where prices are moving.</p><div class="about-authors"><h3 class="sm black">About the authors</h3><p><b>Jonathan Ablett</b> is a consultant in McKinsey’s Waltham Knowledge Center, <b>Lowell Bryan</b> is a director in McKinsey’s New York office, and <b>Sven Smit</b> is a director in the Amsterdam office.</p></div></td></tr>
      </table>
    </figure>
    </details></p>
    
<h3>A delicate balance</h3>
<p>The world is very far from running out of oil. By most estimates, at least a trillion barrels of conventional oil still reside beneath the earth’s surface, not to mention several trillion more barrels of oil or gas that could be extracted through unconventional sources, such as oil sands.</p>

     <p>
    <details>
    <summary><strong>Building a supply chain that can withstand high oil prices</strong></summary>
    <figure>
      <table  cellspacing="0" cellpadding="1" border="1">
        <tr><td><p><i>Opportunities abound to boost supply chain efficiency. Most are in the money today, and will become even more attractive if oil prices rise.</i></p>
<p><b>Knut Alicke and Tobias Meyer</b></p>
<p><strong>We don&rsquo;t need to look very hard</strong> for a live case study of what happens to global supply chains when oil prices spike. Just three years ago, when they shot up to $125 and beyond, it became painfully obvious to many companies that their supply chains were not viable at those levels.</p>
<p>Research we conducted at that time indicated that even if oil prices were as low as $40 a barrel, it would still make economic sense for companies to take a variety of actions that collectively would reduce the energy intensity of global supply chains by almost one-fourth. Energy intensity could be reduced by more than one-third if oil prices stayed above $100 a barrel for a prolonged period (exhibit). The potential would be even greater at higher prices. </p>
[[exhibit 3]]
<p>Here are some of the opportunities that farsighted companies are beginning to act on:</p>
<p><b>Utilizing space-saving packages.</b> A retailer and a wholesaler partnered to create a new, stackable format for milk containers. As a result, they no longer need traditional shipping crates for truck transport, thus freeing up additional space for other cargo and avoiding the need to haul back the empty crates.</p>
<p><b>Operating larger ships and trucks.</b> Vale, the Brazil-based miner, took delivery this year of its first new ultralarge ore carrier, with 400,000 deadweight tons of capacity&mdash;more than twice that of today&rsquo;s standard vessel on the most important trade routes&mdash;to ship iron ore from Brazil to China. Scale is important because doubling the capacity of a transport asset typically increases its energy efficiency by one-fourth. The same goes for trucks too. In emerging markets, where average truck size is less than half that in OECD<a href="#" class="link-footnote" onclick="return false;" rel="#footnote9"><sup>1</sup></a> <span class="tooltip" id="footnote9" style="display: none;"><span class="footnote-content"><span class="footnote-number">1.</span><span class="footnote-text"> Organisation for Economic Co-operation and Development. </span><span class="clear"></span></span><span class="footnote-bottom"></span></span>countries, partly because of poorer infrastructure and smaller retail outlets, every percentage point of average truck size would reduce fuel consumption per unit of capacity by about 0.4 to 0.6 points. </p>
<p><b>Combining new technologies.</b> Maersk, the Danish container liner, used most of the available technological advances when it placed orders for its new 400-meter-long vessels, each with space for 18,000 20-foot container units. These vessels set a new benchmark in maritime energy efficiency by virtue of their size, slower speed, design improvements, and a waste heat&ndash;recovery system that reduces the engine&rsquo;s fuel consumption.</p>
<p><b>Switching to alternative fuels.</b> A road transport company recently estimated that it would save &euro;15,000 a year per truck by converting its small fleet to run on vegetable oil rather than traditional diesel fuel. Because of North America&rsquo;s recent flood of supply of natural gas, companies could also convert fleets to run on liquified natural gas (LNG) instead of diesel. </p>
<p><b>Practicing smarter driving.</b> Examining data collected by onboard computers, a logistics company found significant differences in the driving patterns and fuel consumption of drivers. Shifting to best practice could shave 10 percent off its $4 million annual fuel bill, with onboard computers helping employees drive more economically. </p>
<p>Regulators also have a role to play. In the United States, the fuel efficiency gain of lowering the cap on truck speeds on highways could be 7 to 10 percent. Truck speeds are already capped to lower levels in Europe. But there are still opportunities&mdash;for instance, allowing longer (and potentially heavier) truck/trailer combinations in Europe&rsquo;s road transport market could reduce its use of diesel by around 15 percent. </p>
<p>These examples are just the tip of the iceberg. Further existing technological opportunities&mdash;such as trucks with better aerodynamics and ocean vessels with new, friction-reducing hull coatings&mdash;are economical at the $100-a-barrel prices that have prevailed recently. High prices also should induce companies to cut the distance products travel. Moving final assembly into regions of demand would make it sensible to manufacture less valuable components there, such as primary packaging, manuals, or power cables for electric goods. An alternative is to ship products with low value density by slow and more energy efficient modes of transport. </p>
<p>Optimizing the energy efficiency of a supply chain&rsquo;s production process, location footprint, transportation, and inventory is a complex task made harder by inevitable tensions between the supply chain group and functions such as sales, service, and product development. There are thorny trade-offs&mdash;for example, between service levels and the lower speed of energy-efficient transport. </p>
<p>Part of the answer will be creating nimbler supply chains&mdash;for example, by using slower, more energy-efficient modes (such as ocean freight) for the base load and reserving the faster, less energy-efficient modes (such as air freight) for peak demand. CEOs also will need to facilitate meaningful discussion of important cross-functional supply chain issues so that executives can collaborate to uphold a company&rsquo;s best interests.</p>
<div class="about-authors">
<h3 class="sm black">About the authors</h3>
<p><b>Knut Alicke</b> is a consultant in McKinsey&rsquo;s Stuttgart office, and <b>Tobias Meyer</b> is a principal in the Frankfurt office.</p>
</div></td></tr>
      </table>
    </figure>
    </details></p>
    
<p>More relevant for prices, though, is how much spare oil production capacity exists in the world. Three million or four million barrels a day typically represents a comfortable buffer when the global economy is healthy. If that buffer shrinks, and markets expect strong demand growth to continue, prices can rise—sometimes dramatically. That’s what happened prior to the 2008–09 financial crisis as surging emerging-market demand strained production capacity and prices approached $150 a barrel. This fly-up was short lived because the ensuing deep recession wiped out between three million and four million barrels a day of demand, sending oil prices sharply down. </p>
<p>During the sluggish recovery that followed, the global supply cushion shrank again, punctuated in the first half of 2011 by Libya’s civil war, which disrupted supplies from that country and knocked off a million barrels a day of global capacity. That tightness set the stage for price fly-ups to $120 a barrel in the first half of this year and underscores the strength of the pre-2008 fundamentals. </p>
<p>Going forward, barring prolonged economic stagnation, demand growth for liquids<a href="#" class="link-footnote" onclick="return false;" rel="#footnote1"><sup>1</sup></a> <span class="tooltip" id="footnote1" style="display: none;"><span class="footnote-content"><span class="footnote-number">1.</span><span class="footnote-text"> For the sake of simplicity, in most of this article we use the term “oil” as short-hand for “liquids,” which comprise all liquid fuels derived from crude oil, as well as liquid fuels from natural-gas liquids (NGLs), biofuels, gas to liquids (GTLs), and coal to liquids (CTLs). </span><span class="clear"></span></span><span class="footnote-bottom"></span></span>is likely to chug ahead at around 1.5 percent a year. The pace would be even faster without the steady improvements in energy efficiency that we and other energy analysts foresee, particularly for cars and trucks as a result of technology improvements and stiffening regulatory standards that are already on the books.</p>
<p>Could supply growth accelerate to keep pace? Many industry analysts and our own supply model suggest that it won’t be easy. Despite high oil prices for much of the past decade and surging investment outlays by many major private and national oil companies alike, capacity has risen by only slightly more than 1 percent a year during that time. The logistics, supply systems, and political alignment needed to extract new oil supplies make that a complex, expensive, and time-consuming business. And coaxing more output out of existing oil fields, which typically have high production-decline rates, also is costly and challenging. </p>
<p>Our current projections suggest that in a “business as usual” scenario,<a href="#" class="link-footnote" onclick="return false;" rel="#footnote2"><sup>2</sup></a> <span class="tooltip" id="footnote2" style="display: none;"><span class="footnote-content"><span class="footnote-number">2.</span><span class="footnote-text"> Our business-as-usual scenario assumes that between 2010 and 2020, the world economy will grow at the rate currently anticipated by many analysts (3.0 to 3.5 percent) and that oil prices won’t significantly exceed $100 a barrel during this period. </span><span class="clear"></span></span><span class="footnote-bottom"></span></span>the world could reach a realistic supply capacity of around 100 million barrels a day by 2020, up from 91 million or 92 million today. That, however, would barely suffice to meet the roughly 100 million barrels of liquids the world would consume each day in such a scenario, up from 88 million or 89 million today. </p>
<h3>When supply and demand collide</h3>
<p>Simple math suggests that at some point, something has to give. And when it does, the world will have to start taking steps away from today’s oil dependence. The question is how rapid and volatile that transition will be.</p>
<h3 class="sm black">The case for a gentle collision</h3>
<p>This critical shift could happen in an orderly fashion, without price spikes, if governments, companies, and consumers worked together to accelerate the adoption of measures that reduce demand. Indeed, a common denominator of current forecasts by industry analysts (including ourselves) is a gradual transition in most regions toward lower oil intensity in transportation, power, and residential heating. But according to our analysis, it would take more than current trends in oil conservation (spurred by existing legislation) for supply to meet demand if robust economic growth returned. </p>
<p>A few examples illustrate the scale and scope of the task facing the world if we are to realize a gentle transition. Governments would need to raise auto fuel efficiency standards further, and consumers would need to place greater emphasis on fuel economy when they bought new cars. Policy makers in several developing countries would need to abolish fuel subsidies so that consumers felt the real price of oil. Around the world, we’d need to see deeper reductions in the use of oil for heating, power generation, and chemical manufacturing. Some transport by ships and heavy trucks would need to start shifting toward more reliance on natural gas as a fuel.</p>
<p>Changes like these could push oil supply and demand roughly into balance. However, they would require new policies and significant changes in how consumers and businesses behave. What’s more, they would need to start now because it will take years before the changes required to constrain oil consumption begin to take effect. If we do not succeed in implementing these changes in a farsighted way, the system faces a risk of falling out of balance. </p>
<h3 class="sm black">Why the adjustment could be violent</h3>
<p>That brings us to a second scenario: it’s possible to imagine global supply and demand for oil colliding faster, and more ferociously, resulting in a price spike as the global capacity buffer melted away. As we’ve said, anticipated economic growth alone could cause demand to expand faster than supply. Another possible trigger: supply disruption, which does happen from time to time. The possibilities include an exceptionally severe hurricane in the Gulf of Mexico, violence in the Niger Delta, instability in Venezuela, and further tension in the Middle East.</p>
<p>If this new price spike took place, it could have a more significant impact on global consumption patterns than most executives expect (for audio commentary by Occo Roelofsen, see the interactive, “How might a sustained oil price spike affect demand?”). For starters, it would hit global growth, which in turn would immediately knock down oil demand. In addition, there would be some rapid behavioral effects, such as a reduction in car, air, and sea travel. If the spike lasted longer, it could cause several more structural shifts, such as prompting individuals to use different modes of transport or even to look for work closer to home, encouraging companies to reverse offshoring trends and bring supply chains closer to home, accelerating the substitution of videoconferences for air travel, and pushing the freight transport industry to adopt less oil-intensive modes. </p>

    <h4>Interactive</h4>
    <div id="V2">
    <a id="interactive" onclick="newwindow=window.open ('http://www.mckinsey.com/tools/Wrappers/Wrapper.aspx?sid={49E3A0B7-82AA-4341-BC1D-977F327909A5}&amp;pid={61019051-FB04-4C96-914E-AAE67938D530}','WrapperWindow','toolbar=no, location=no, directories=no, resizable=yes, status=no,titlebar = no,scrollbars=yes, top=0,width=750,height=550'); newwindow.focus();return false;"><h3>How might a sustained oil price spike affect demand?</h3></a>
    <p>Occo Roelofsen discusses demand during a sustained oil price spike, from both a general and sector-specific perspective.</p>
    <div>
      <a id="interactive" onclick="newwindow=window.open ('http://www.mckinsey.com/tools/Wrappers/Wrapper.aspx?sid={49E3A0B7-82AA-4341-BC1D-977F327909A5}&pid={61019051-FB04-4C96-914E-AAE67938D530}','WrapperWindow','toolbar=no, location=no, directories=no, resizable=yes, status=no,titlebar = no,scrollbars=yes, top=0,width=1000,height=680'); newwindow.focus();return false;">
        <img id="svgImage" width="510" data-nosvg="http://www.mckinsey.com/~/media/17FBD78DF5784921B387478CCC951194.ashx" src="http://www.mckinsey.com/~/media/17FBD78DF5784921B387478CCC951194.ashx" style="border-width:0px;"/>
      </a>
    </div></div>
<p>Because such shifts would take time, a high-price environment could last for years, not months, accelerating several other ongoing trends that, when combined, could lead to even further demand reductions. In other words, a sustained price spike could scare consumers, companies, and governments into more drastic responses—accelerating the transition to a less oil-dependent economy. A price spike of one to three years could be long enough to make governments raise standards for fuel efficiency at an accelerated pace and prompt automakers, reacting to regulatory changes, to modify their product-development road maps. Ultimately, all this would lead to more rapid efficiency gains and potentially to faster electric-vehicle penetration. </p>
<p>A prolonged price spike also could prompt investments in infrastructure needed to support the use of electric vehicles or other alternatives (such as natural gas and hydrogen) to traditional fuel sources. Such investments could have an impact on oil demand for trucking, light vehicles, and shipping. What’s more, very high oil prices would intensify energy efficiency efforts up and down the supply chain and reduce the amount of plastics used in packaging, thus shrinking demand for oil in chemicals. Additional government action, in the form of either more stringent regulation on the use of plastics or subsidized financing that reduced the up-front cost to consumers of switching away from fuel oil in residential heating, could play an important role in this transition. </p>
<p>All along the way, of course, these reactions, plus slower global growth, would do their part to exert some downward pressure on oil prices. Expanded supply would also play a role. From now to 2020, OPEC<a href="#" class="link-footnote" onclick="return false;" rel="#footnote3"><sup>3</sup></a> <span class="tooltip" id="footnote3" style="display: none;"><span class="footnote-content"><span class="footnote-number">3.</span><span class="footnote-text"> Organization of the Petroleum Exporting Countries. </span><span class="clear"></span></span><span class="footnote-bottom"></span></span>could increase its capacity by, say, two million barrels a day above currently assumed increases, and new investments in mature assets could slow decline rates, leading to an additional one million to two million barrels of daily production. Furthermore, additional investments in unconventional oil sources, such as oil sands, could increase supply by, say, one million to two million barrels a day. Biofuels, too, would have room to grow. But given the time it would take to pursue some of the available opportunities—and the danger that they could quickly become uneconomic once oil prices fell—the supply response is likely to be slower and more muted than that of demand. </p>
<p>In the end, once all the efficiency gains and supply expansions described above kicked in, the world could again wind up in balance and with significant excess capacity, so that eventually—perhaps by 2020, perhaps later—prices fell below the $80 to $100 range. Until then, however, given how slowly many of the demand changes would unfold, it’s only prudent to imagine the possibility that the world could experience a prolonged period of both significant volatility and generally much higher prices. </p>
<h3>Preparing for the unexpected</h3>
<p>If the shock scenario outlined above unfolded, sustained high oil prices would challenge the top and bottom lines of many companies. However, high prices also could create opportunities for companies to differentiate themselves from competitors whose cost structures and operating approaches were ill suited to the new environment. And for companies on the front lines of the resource productivity revolution, a prolonged oil price increase would be beneficial. Providers of a range of new technologies—from car batteries for electric vehicles, to horizontal drilling and other tools for unconventional oil extraction, to biofuel production techniques, to electricity cogeneration equipment for manufacturers—would see their businesses grow, faster, than they would in a world of lower oil prices. </p>
<p>In many cases, these companies would be supplying or partnering with more established firms: oil companies in need of unconventional extraction technologies, auto manufacturers trying to create the winning vehicle of the future, and chemical companies hoping to take advantage of new feedstock sources, for example. From a strategic perspective, the interesting question is who would grab the most profitable positions in the new energy ecosystem.</p>
<p>No less fascinating are the managerial implications of the second-order and feedback effects that would occur as this ferocious collision played itself out. For example, our analysis suggests that even if prices subsequently fell, companies that pursued strategies for reducing their dependence on oil would be unlikely to regret it. One reason is that many strategies are already “in the money” at today’s prices. If prices got high enough, they would concentrate the attention of consumers, businesses, and governments sufficiently to promote many positive-return investments that haven’t been implemented so far, because of behavioral inertia. This development would accelerate the changes in our capital stock, while leaving them economically viable even if prices fell again. </p>
<p>Furthermore, many technologies could become significantly cheaper as demand for them increased and their providers went down learning curves. Examples include batteries for vehicles, highly efficient internal-combustion engines, and certain biofuel technologies, such as those that are cellulosic or perhaps even based on algae. In a high-price environment, more capital would flow into these technologies, enabling them to scale up. The time needed for them to become economically attractive would fall by five or even ten years compared with the time frame if oil prices stayed at lower levels, potentially making these technologies economically viable even if oil prices subsequently fell.</p>
<p>Indeed, a striking and often-underestimated feature of energy price shocks is the nonlinearity of their impact. Take electric vehicles. The market for car batteries would likely be about five or ten times larger if oil prices stayed for a considerable period at $150 a barrel than it would be at $100 a barrel. Few corporate-planning processes, however, place sufficient emphasis on extremes like this—even though these are precisely the scenarios that produce many of the most interesting opportunities and powerful threats for a business. Building corporate processes and skills that enable thoughtful reflection on a wider, more volatile range of outcomes could be a significant competitive differentiator in the years to come.</p>
<div class="articleBreak"></div>
<p>In the long run, these structural changes could well be a positive development for the world—resulting in more predictable and sustainable energy supplies and prices. But navigating the transition would be challenging and would reward the well prepared. The time is now for companies to start planning for the possibility of another price shock and a powerful market response.</p>
<div class="about-authors">
<h3 class="sm black">About the authors</h3>
<p><b>Tom Janssens</b> is a principal in McKinsey’s Houston office, where <b>Scott Nyquist</b> is a director; <b>Occo Roelofsen</b> is a principal in the Amsterdam office.</p>
<p>The authors wish to acknowledge the contributions of Tim Fitzgibbon, Pedro Haas, Yousuf Habib, Matt Rogers, Valerie Tann, and Koen Vermeltfoort to the development of this article.</p>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A CEO’s guide to innovation in China in master</title>
      <description>Dynamic domestic players and focused multinationals are helping China churn out a growing number of innovative products and services. Intensifying competition lies ahead; here’s a road map for navigating it.</description>
      <link>http://www.mckinsey.com/en/insights/asia-pacific/a_ceos_guide_to_innovation_in_china</link>
      <guid>http://www.mckinsey.com/en/insights/asia-pacific/a_ceos_guide_to_innovation_in_china</guid>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 May 2012 05:01:04 GMT</pubDate>
      <id>47c928e1-e242-41cc-988c-f62fa6655c03</id>
      <category>Asia-Pacific</category>
      <dc:creator><![CDATA[Gordon Orr and Erik Roth]]></dc:creator>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><strong>China is innovating.</strong> Some of its achievements are visible: a doubling of the global percentage of patents granted to Chinese inventors since 2005, for example, and the growing role of Chinese companies in the wind- and solar-power industries. Other developments—such as advances by local companies in domestically oriented consumer electronics, instant messaging, and online gaming—may well be escaping the notice of executives who aren’t on the ground in China.</p>
<p>As innovation gains steam there, the stakes are rising for domestic and multinational companies alike. Prowess in innovation will not only become an increasingly important differentiator inside China but should also yield ideas and products that become serious competitors on the international stage.</p>
<!--roadblock-->
<p>Chinese companies and multinationals bring different strengths and weaknesses to this competition. The Chinese have traditionally had a bias toward innovation through commercialization—they are more comfortable than many Western companies are with putting a new product or service into the market quickly and improving its performance through subsequent generations. It is common for products to launch in a fraction of the time that it would take in more developed markets. While the quality of these early versions may be variable, subsequent ones improve rapidly.<a href="#" class="link-footnote" onclick="return false;" rel="#footnote1"><sup>1</sup></a> <span class="tooltip" id="footnote1" style="display: none;"><span class="footnote-content"><span class="footnote-number">1.</span><span class="footnote-text"> Commercialization differs from <i>shanzhai</i>, or “copycat innovation.” Many executives in the developed world misunderstand <i>shanzhai</i>, believing that it is purely the replication of an innovation developed in another market. Although this does occur, products developed through the <i>shanzhai</i> approach incorporate features specifically for the Chinese market. <i>Shanzhai</i> is quite prevalent in consumer products categories such as packaged goods and electronics. It can also be found in the business-to-business domain, where local companies produce knockoffs of successful foreign products or business models. </span><span class="clear"></span></span><span class="footnote-bottom"></span></span></p>
<p>Chinese companies also benefit from their government’s emphasis on indigenous innovation, underlined in the latest five-year plan. Chinese authorities view innovation as critical both to the domestic economy’s long-term health and to the global competitiveness of Chinese companies. China has already created the seeds of 22 Silicon Valley–like innovation hubs within the life sciences and biotech industries. In semiconductors, the government has been consolidating innovation clusters to create centers of manufacturing excellence.</p>
<p>But progress isn’t uniform across industries, and innovation capabilities vary significantly: several basic skills are at best nascent within a typical Chinese enterprise. Pain points include an absence of advanced techniques for understanding—analytically, not just intuitively—what customers really want, corporate cultures that don’t support risk taking, and a scarcity of the sort of internal collaboration that’s essential for developing new ideas.</p>

     <p>
    <details>
    <summary><strong>Improving the patent process</strong></summary>
    <figure>
      <table  cellspacing="0" cellpadding="1" border="1">
        <tr><td><p>
In innovative sectors such as biotechnology, electric vehicles, pharmaceuticals, and solar energy, the number of patent applications from Chinese companies is rising. In fact, Huawei and ZTE ranked among the world’s top five corporate patent registrants by volume in 2010. Intensifying patent activity reflects a growing recognition that intellectual property is essential to value. As this mentality takes hold, domestic innovators may pressure the government to create a more modern intellectual-property system.</p><p>
Currently, China recognizes three categories of patents: invention (what most people elsewhere think of as worthy of a patent), utility (a new use for something that already exists), and design. Invention patents run for 20 years, the others only for 10. Patent reform—such as reducing the duration of design or utility patents and raising the bar for what can be registered in those categories—would be a powerful way for the Chinese government to signal its seriousness about promoting indigenous innovation. If China decides to move ahead with patent reform, a desire for global consistency could well make it a high-priority multilateral issue.</p><p>Without patent reform, companies must rely on one of two strategies for protecting intellectual property. The first is to continue to outrun the competition by developing increasingly innovative solutions or building in protection through complex integration that is difficult to reverse-engineer. The second is to create easily identifiable technology “signatures” that would be hard to refute in legal proceedings.</p></td></tr>
      </table>
    </figure>
    </details></p>
    
<p>Multinationals are far stronger in these areas but face other challenges, such as high attrition among talented Chinese nationals that can slow efforts to create local innovation centers. Indeed, the contrasting capabilities of domestic and multinational players, along with the still-unsettled state of intellectual-property protection (see sidebar, “Improving the patent process”), create the potential for topsy-turvy competition, creative partnerships, and rapid change. This article seeks to lay out the current landscape for would-be innovators and to describe some of the priorities for domestic and multinational companies that hope to thrive in it.</p>
<h3>China’s innovation landscape</h3>
<p>Considerable innovation is occurring in China in both the business- to-consumer and business-to-business sectors. Although breakthroughs in either space generally go unrecognized by the broader global public, many multinational B2B competitors are acutely aware of the innovative strides the Chinese are making in sectors such as communications equipment and alternative energy. Interestingly, even as multinationals struggle to cope with Chinese innovation in some areas, they seem to be holding their own in others.</p>
<h3 class="sm black">The business-to-consumer visibility gap</h3>
<p>When European and US consumers think about what China makes, they reflexively turn to basic items such as textiles and toys, not necessarily the most innovative products and rarely associated with brand names.</p>
<p>In fact, though, much product innovation in China stays there. A visit to a shop of the Suning Appliance chain, the large Chinese consumer electronics retailer, is telling. There, you might find an Android-enabled television complete with an integrated Internet-browsing capability and preloaded apps that take users straight to some of the most popular Chinese Web sites and digital movie-streaming services. Even the picture quality and industrial design are comparable to those of high-end televisions from South Korean competitors.</p>
<p>We observe the same home-grown innovation in business models. Look, for example, at the online sector, especially Tencent’s QQ instant-messaging service and the Sina Corporation’s microblog, Weibo. These models, unique to China, are generating revenue and growing in ways that have not been duplicated anywhere in the world. QQ’s low, flat-rate pricing and active marketplace for online games generate tremendous value from hundreds of millions of Chinese users.</p>
<p>What’s keeping innovative products and business models confined to China? In general, its market is so large that domestic companies have little incentive to adapt successful products for sale abroad. In many cases, the skills and capabilities of these companies are oriented toward the domestic market, so even if they want to expand globally, they face high hurdles. Many senior executives, for example, are uncomfortable doing business outside their own geography and language. Furthermore, the success of many Chinese models depends on local resources—for example, lower-cost labor, inexpensive land, and access to capital or intellectual property—that are difficult to replicate elsewhere. Take the case of mobile handsets: most Chinese manufacturers would be subject to significant intellectual property–driven licensing fees if they sold their products outside China.</p>
<h3 class="sm black">Successes in business to business</h3>
<p>Several Chinese B2B sectors are establishing a track record of innovation domestically and globally. The Chinese communications equipment industry, for instance, is a peer of developed-world companies in quality. Market acceptance has expanded well beyond the historical presence in emerging markets to include Europe’s most demanding customers, such as France Télécom and Vodafone.</p>
<p>Pharmaceuticals are another area where China has made big strides. In the 1980s and 1990s, the country was a bit player in the discovery of new chemical entities. By the next decade, however, China’s sophistication had grown dramatically. More than 20 chemical compounds discovered and developed in China are currently undergoing clinical trials.</p>
<img alt="China solar-cell factory" src="~/media/McKinsey/dotcom/Insights/Asia-Pacific/A CEOs guide to innovation in China/solar-cell.ashx?mw=510">
<p class="grayNote small">Workers produce solar-cell modules in a factory in China’s Jiangsu Province.<br>© Imaginechina/Corbis</p>
<p>China’s solar- and wind-power industries are also taking center stage. The country will become the world’s largest market for renewable-energy technology, and it already has some of the sector’s biggest companies, providing critical components for the industry globally. Chinese companies not only enjoy scale advantages but also, in the case of solar, use new manufacturing techniques to improve the efficiency of solar panels.</p>
<p>Success in B2B innovation has benefited greatly from friendly government policies, such as establishing market access barriers; influencing the nature of cross-border collaborations by setting intellectual-property requirements in electric vehicles, high-speed trains, and other segments; and creating domestic-purchasing policies that favor Chinese-made goods and services. Many view these policies as loading the dice in favor of Chinese companies, but multinationals should be prepared for their continued enforcement.</p>
<img alt="Wind Turbine" src="~/media/McKinsey/dotcom/Insights/Asia-Pacific/A CEOs guide to innovation in China/turbine.ashx?mw=510">
<p class="grayNote small">Wind turbine manufacturing in China’s Shandong Province.<br>
© Guo Xulei/Xinhua Press/Corbis</p>
<p>Despite recent setbacks, an interesting example of how the Chinese government has moved to build an industry comes from high-speed rail. Before 2004, China’s efforts to develop it had limited success. Since then, a mix of two policies—encouraging technology transfer from multinationals (in return for market access) and a coordinated R&D-investment effort—has helped China Railways’ high-speed trains to dominate the local industry. The multinationals’ revenue in this sector has remained largely unchanged since the early 2000s.</p>
<p>But it is too simplistic to claim that government support is the only reason China has had some B2B success. The strength of the country’s scientific and technical talent is growing, and local companies increasingly bring real capabilities to the table. What’s more, a number of government-supported innovation efforts have <i>not</i> been successful. Some notable examples include attempts to develop an indigenous 3G telecommunications protocol called TDS-CDMA and to replace the global Wi-Fi standard with a China-only Internet security protocol, WAPI.</p>
<h3 class="sm black">Advantage, multinationals?</h3>
<p>Simultaneously, multinationals have been shaping China’s innovation landscape by leveraging global assets. Consider, for example, the joint venture between General Motors and the Shanghai Automotive Industry Corporation, which adapted a US minivan (Buick’s GL8) for use in the Chinese market and more recently introduced a version developed in China, for China. The model has proved hugely popular among executives.</p>
<p>In fact, the market for vehicles powered by internal-combustion engines remains dominated by multinationals, despite significant incentives and encouragement from the Chinese government, which had hoped that some domestic automakers would emerge as leaders by now. The continued strength of multinationals indicates how hard it is to break through in industries with 40 or 50 years of intellectual capital. Transferring the skills needed to design and manufacture complex engineering systems has proved a significant challenge requiring mentorship, the right culture, and time.</p>
<p>We are seeing the emergence of similar challenges in electric vehicles, where early indications suggest that the balance is swinging toward the multinationals because of superior product quality. By relying less on purely indigenous innovation, China is trying to make sure the electric-vehicle story has an ending different from that of its telecommunications protocol efforts. The government’s stated aspiration of having more than five million plug-in hybrid and battery electric vehicles on the road by 2020 is heavily supported by a mix of extensive subsidies and tax incentives for local companies, combined with strict market access rules for foreign companies and the creation of new revenue pools through government and public fleet-purchase programs. But the subsidies and incentives may not be enough to overcome the technical challenges of learning to build these vehicles, particularly if multinationals decline to invest with local companies.</p>
<h3>Four priorities for innovators in China</h3>
<p>There’s no magic formula for innovation—and that goes doubly for China, where the challenges and opportunities facing domestic and multinational players are so different. Some of the priorities we describe here, such as instilling a culture of risk taking and learning, are more pressing for Chinese companies. Others, such as retaining local talent, may be harder for multinationals. Collectively, these priorities include some of the critical variables that will influence which companies lead China’s innovation revolution and how far it goes.</p>
<img alt="China high-speed train" src="~/media/McKinsey/dotcom/Insights/Asia-Pacific/A CEOs guide to innovation in China/ChinaTrain.ashx?mw=510">
<p class="grayNote small">A Chinese-built high-speed train at the Wuhan Railway Station, in Wuhan, China.<br>© Guo Xulei/Xinhua Press/Corbis</p><h3 class="sm black">Deeply understanding Chinese customers</h3>
<p>Alibaba’s Web-based trading platform, Taobao, is a great example of a product that emerged from deep insights into how customers were underserved and their inability to connect with suppliers, as well as a sophisticated understanding of the Chinese banking system. This dominant marketplace enables thousands of Chinese manufacturers to find and transact with potential customers directly. What looks like a straightforward eBay-like trading platform actually embeds numerous significant innovations to support these transactions, such as an ability to facilitate electronic fund transfers and to account for idiosyncrasies in the national banking system. Taobao wouldn’t have happened without Alibaba’s deep, analytically driven understanding of customers.</p>
<p>Few Chinese companies have the systematic ability to develop a deep understanding of customers’ problems. Domestic players have traditionally had a manufacturing-led focus on reapplying existing business models to deliver products for fast-growing markets. These “push” models will find it increasingly hard to unlock pockets of profitable growth. Shifting from delivery to creation requires more local research and development, as well as the nurturing of more market-driven organizations that can combine insights into detailed Chinese customer preferences with a clear sense of how the local business environment is evolving. Requirements include both research techniques relevant to China and people with the experience to draw out actionable customer insights.</p>
<p>Many multinationals have these capabilities, but unless they have been operating in China for some years, they may well lack the domestic-market knowledge or relationships needed to apply them effectively. The solution—building a true domestic Chinese presence rather than an outpost—sounds obvious, but it’s difficult to carry out without commitment from the top. Too many companies fail by using “fly over” management. But some multinationals appear to be investing the necessary resources; for example, we recently met (separately) with top executives of two big industrial companies who were being transferred from the West to run global R&D organizations from Shanghai. The idea is to be closer to Chinese customers and the network of institutions and universities from which multinationals source talent.</p>
<h3 class="sm black">Retaining local talent</h3>
<p>China’s universities graduate more than 10,000 science PhDs each year, and increasing numbers of Chinese scientists working overseas are returning home. Multinationals in particular are struggling to tap this inflow of researchers and managers. A recent survey by the executive-recruiting firm Heidrick & Struggles found that 77 percent of the senior executives from multinational companies responding say they have difficulty attracting managers in China, while 91 percent regard employee turnover as their top talent challenge.</p>
<p>Retention is more of an issue for multinationals than for domestic companies, but as big foreign players raise their game, so must local ones. Chinese companies, for example, excel at creating a community-like environment to build loyalty to the institution. That helps keep some employees in place when competing offers arise, but it may not always be enough.</p>
<p>Talented Chinese employees increasingly recognize the benefits of being associated with a well-known foreign brand and like the mentorship and training that foreign companies can provide. So multinationals that commit themselves to developing meaningful career paths for Chinese employees should have a chance in the growing fight with their Chinese competitors for R&D talent. Initiatives might include in-house training courses or apprenticeship programs, perhaps with local universities. General Motors sponsors projects in which professors and engineering departments at leading universities research issues of interest to the automaker. That helps it to develop closer relations with the institutions from which it recruits and to train students before they graduate.</p>
<p>Some multinationals energize Chinese engineers by shifting their roles from serving as capacity in a support of existing global programs to contributing significantly to new innovation thrusts, often aimed at the local market. This approach, increasingly common in the pharma industry, may hold lessons for other kinds of multinationals that have established R&D or innovation centers in China in recent years (read about AstraZeneca’s experience in “Three snapshots of Chinese innovation”). The keys to success include a clear objective— for instance, will activity support global programs or develop China-for-China innovations?—and a clear plan for attracting and retaining the talent needed to staff such centers. Too often, we visit impressive R&D facilities, stocked with the latest equipment, that are almost empty because staffing them has proved difficult.</p>
<h3 class="sm black">Instilling a culture of risk taking</h3>
<p>Failure is a required element of innovation, but it isn’t the norm in China, where a culture of obedience and adherence to rules prevails in most companies. Breaking or even bending them is not expected and rarely tolerated. To combat these attitudes, companies must find ways to make initiative taking more acceptable and better rewarded.</p>
<p>One approach we found, in a leading solar company, was to transfer risk from individual innovators to teams. Shared accountability and community support made increased risk taking and experimentation safer. The company has used these “innovation work groups” to develop everything from more efficient battery technology to new manufacturing processes. Team-based approaches also have proved effective for some multinationals trying to stimulate initiative taking (read about General Motors’ approach in “Three snapshots of Chinese innovation”).</p>
<p>How fast a culture of innovation takes off varies by industry. We see a much more rapid evolution toward the approach of Western companies in the way Chinese high-tech enterprises learn from their customers and how they apply that learning to create new products made for China (read a perspective on the evolution of its semiconductor sector in “Thee snapshots of Chinese innovation”). That approach is much less common at state-owned enterprises, since they are held back by hierarchical, benchmark-driven cultures.</p>
<h3 class="sm black">Promoting collaboration</h3>
<p>One area where multinationals currently have an edge is promoting collaboration and the internal collision of ideas, which can yield surprising new insights and business opportunities. In many Chinese companies, traditional organizational and cultural barriers inhibit such exchanges.</p>
<p>Although a lot of these companies have become more professional and adept at delivering products in large volumes, their ability to scale up an organization that can work collaboratively has not kept pace. Their rigorous, linear processes for bringing new products to market ensure rapid commercialization but create too many hand-offs where insights are lost and trade-offs for efficiency are promoted.</p>
<p>One Chinese consumer electronics company has repeatedly tried to improve the way it innovates. Senior management has called for new ideas and sponsored efforts to create new best-in-class processes, while junior engineers have designed high-quality prototypes. Yet the end result continues to be largely undifferentiated, incremental improvements. The biggest reason appears to be a lack of cross-company collaboration and a reliance on processes designed to build and reinforce scale in manufacturing. In effect, the technical and commercial sides of the business don’t cooperate in a way that would allow some potentially winning ideas to reach the market. As Chinese organizations mature, stories like this one may become rarer.</p>
<div class="articleBreak"></div>
<p>China hasn’t yet experienced a true innovation revolution. It will need time to evolve from a country of incremental innovation based on technology transfers to one where breakthrough innovation is common. The government will play a powerful role in that process, but ultimately it will be the actions of domestic companies and multinationals that dictate the pace of change—and determine who leads it.</p>
<div class="about-authors">
<h3 class="sm black">About the authors</h3>
<p><b>Gordon Orr</b> is a director in McKinsey’s Shanghai office, where <b>Erik Roth</b> is a principal.</p>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A CEO’s guide to innovation in China in master</title>
      <description>Dynamic domestic players and focused multinationals are helping China churn out a growing number of innovative products and services. Intensifying competition lies ahead; here’s a road map for navigating it.</description>
      <link>http://www.mckinsey.com/en/insights/asia-pacific/copy_of_a_ceos_guide_to_innovation_in_china</link>
      <guid>http://www.mckinsey.com/en/insights/asia-pacific/copy_of_a_ceos_guide_to_innovation_in_china</guid>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Jul 2013 02:23:23 GMT</pubDate>
      <id>2cbefcae-1fad-40a9-9438-1f536de7e419</id>
      <category>Asia-Pacific</category>
      <dc:creator><![CDATA[Gordon Orr and Erik Roth]]></dc:creator>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><strong>China is innovating.</strong> Some of its achievements are visible: a doubling of the global percentage of patents granted to Chinese inventors since 2005, for example, and the growing role of Chinese companies in the wind- and solar-power industries. Other developments—such as advances by local companies in domestically oriented consumer electronics, instant messaging, and online gaming—may well be escaping the notice of executives who aren’t on the ground in China.</p>
<p>As innovation gains steam there, the stakes are rising for domestic and multinational companies alike. Prowess in innovation will not only become an increasingly important differentiator inside China but should also yield ideas and products that become serious competitors on the international stage.</p>
<!--roadblock-->
<p>Chinese companies and multinationals bring different strengths and weaknesses to this competition. The Chinese have traditionally had a bias toward innovation through commercialization—they are more comfortable than many Western companies are with putting a new product or service into the market quickly and improving its performance through subsequent generations. It is common for products to launch in a fraction of the time that it would take in more developed markets. While the quality of these early versions may be variable, subsequent ones improve rapidly.<a href="#" class="link-footnote" onclick="return false;" rel="#footnote1"><sup>1</sup></a> <span class="tooltip" id="footnote1" style="display: none;"><span class="footnote-content"><span class="footnote-number">1.</span><span class="footnote-text"> Commercialization differs from <i>shanzhai</i>, or “copycat innovation.” Many executives in the developed world misunderstand <i>shanzhai</i>, believing that it is purely the replication of an innovation developed in another market. Although this does occur, products developed through the <i>shanzhai</i> approach incorporate features specifically for the Chinese market. <i>Shanzhai</i> is quite prevalent in consumer products categories such as packaged goods and electronics. It can also be found in the business-to-business domain, where local companies produce knockoffs of successful foreign products or business models. </span><span class="clear"></span></span><span class="footnote-bottom"></span></span></p>
<p>Chinese companies also benefit from their government’s emphasis on indigenous innovation, underlined in the latest five-year plan. Chinese authorities view innovation as critical both to the domestic economy’s long-term health and to the global competitiveness of Chinese companies. China has already created the seeds of 22 Silicon Valley–like innovation hubs within the life sciences and biotech industries. In semiconductors, the government has been consolidating innovation clusters to create centers of manufacturing excellence.</p>
<p>But progress isn’t uniform across industries, and innovation capabilities vary significantly: several basic skills are at best nascent within a typical Chinese enterprise. Pain points include an absence of advanced techniques for understanding—analytically, not just intuitively—what customers really want, corporate cultures that don’t support risk taking, and a scarcity of the sort of internal collaboration that’s essential for developing new ideas.</p>

     <p>
    <details>
    <summary><strong>Improving the patent process</strong></summary>
    <figure>
      <table  cellspacing="0" cellpadding="1" border="1">
        <tr><td><p>
In innovative sectors such as biotechnology, electric vehicles, pharmaceuticals, and solar energy, the number of patent applications from Chinese companies is rising. In fact, Huawei and ZTE ranked among the world’s top five corporate patent registrants by volume in 2010. Intensifying patent activity reflects a growing recognition that intellectual property is essential to value. As this mentality takes hold, domestic innovators may pressure the government to create a more modern intellectual-property system.</p><p>
Currently, China recognizes three categories of patents: invention (what most people elsewhere think of as worthy of a patent), utility (a new use for something that already exists), and design. Invention patents run for 20 years, the others only for 10. Patent reform—such as reducing the duration of design or utility patents and raising the bar for what can be registered in those categories—would be a powerful way for the Chinese government to signal its seriousness about promoting indigenous innovation. If China decides to move ahead with patent reform, a desire for global consistency could well make it a high-priority multilateral issue.</p><p>Without patent reform, companies must rely on one of two strategies for protecting intellectual property. The first is to continue to outrun the competition by developing increasingly innovative solutions or building in protection through complex integration that is difficult to reverse-engineer. The second is to create easily identifiable technology “signatures” that would be hard to refute in legal proceedings.</p></td></tr>
      </table>
    </figure>
    </details></p>
    
<p>Multinationals are far stronger in these areas but face other challenges, such as high attrition among talented Chinese nationals that can slow efforts to create local innovation centers. Indeed, the contrasting capabilities of domestic and multinational players, along with the still-unsettled state of intellectual-property protection (see sidebar, “Improving the patent process”), create the potential for topsy-turvy competition, creative partnerships, and rapid change. This article seeks to lay out the current landscape for would-be innovators and to describe some of the priorities for domestic and multinational companies that hope to thrive in it.</p>
<h3>China’s innovation landscape</h3>
<p>Considerable innovation is occurring in China in both the business- to-consumer and business-to-business sectors. Although breakthroughs in either space generally go unrecognized by the broader global public, many multinational B2B competitors are acutely aware of the innovative strides the Chinese are making in sectors such as communications equipment and alternative energy. Interestingly, even as multinationals struggle to cope with Chinese innovation in some areas, they seem to be holding their own in others.</p>
<h3 class="sm black">The business-to-consumer visibility gap</h3>
<p>When European and US consumers think about what China makes, they reflexively turn to basic items such as textiles and toys, not necessarily the most innovative products and rarely associated with brand names.</p>
<p>In fact, though, much product innovation in China stays there. A visit to a shop of the Suning Appliance chain, the large Chinese consumer electronics retailer, is telling. There, you might find an Android-enabled television complete with an integrated Internet-browsing capability and preloaded apps that take users straight to some of the most popular Chinese Web sites and digital movie-streaming services. Even the picture quality and industrial design are comparable to those of high-end televisions from South Korean competitors.</p>
<p>We observe the same home-grown innovation in business models. Look, for example, at the online sector, especially Tencent’s QQ instant-messaging service and the Sina Corporation’s microblog, Weibo. These models, unique to China, are generating revenue and growing in ways that have not been duplicated anywhere in the world. QQ’s low, flat-rate pricing and active marketplace for online games generate tremendous value from hundreds of millions of Chinese users.</p>
<p>What’s keeping innovative products and business models confined to China? In general, its market is so large that domestic companies have little incentive to adapt successful products for sale abroad. In many cases, the skills and capabilities of these companies are oriented toward the domestic market, so even if they want to expand globally, they face high hurdles. Many senior executives, for example, are uncomfortable doing business outside their own geography and language. Furthermore, the success of many Chinese models depends on local resources—for example, lower-cost labor, inexpensive land, and access to capital or intellectual property—that are difficult to replicate elsewhere. Take the case of mobile handsets: most Chinese manufacturers would be subject to significant intellectual property–driven licensing fees if they sold their products outside China.</p>
<h3 class="sm black">Successes in business to business</h3>
<p>Several Chinese B2B sectors are establishing a track record of innovation domestically and globally. The Chinese communications equipment industry, for instance, is a peer of developed-world companies in quality. Market acceptance has expanded well beyond the historical presence in emerging markets to include Europe’s most demanding customers, such as France Télécom and Vodafone.</p>
<p>Pharmaceuticals are another area where China has made big strides. In the 1980s and 1990s, the country was a bit player in the discovery of new chemical entities. By the next decade, however, China’s sophistication had grown dramatically. More than 20 chemical compounds discovered and developed in China are currently undergoing clinical trials.</p>
<img alt="China solar-cell factory" src="~/media/McKinsey/dotcom/Insights/Asia-Pacific/A CEOs guide to innovation in China/solar-cell.ashx?mw=510">
<p class="grayNote small">Workers produce solar-cell modules in a factory in China’s Jiangsu Province.<br>© Imaginechina/Corbis</p>
<p>China’s solar- and wind-power industries are also taking center stage. The country will become the world’s largest market for renewable-energy technology, and it already has some of the sector’s biggest companies, providing critical components for the industry globally. Chinese companies not only enjoy scale advantages but also, in the case of solar, use new manufacturing techniques to improve the efficiency of solar panels.</p>
<p>Success in B2B innovation has benefited greatly from friendly government policies, such as establishing market access barriers; influencing the nature of cross-border collaborations by setting intellectual-property requirements in electric vehicles, high-speed trains, and other segments; and creating domestic-purchasing policies that favor Chinese-made goods and services. Many view these policies as loading the dice in favor of Chinese companies, but multinationals should be prepared for their continued enforcement.</p>
<img alt="Wind Turbine" src="~/media/McKinsey/dotcom/Insights/Asia-Pacific/A CEOs guide to innovation in China/turbine.ashx?mw=510">
<p class="grayNote small">Wind turbine manufacturing in China’s Shandong Province.<br>
© Guo Xulei/Xinhua Press/Corbis</p>
<p>Despite recent setbacks, an interesting example of how the Chinese government has moved to build an industry comes from high-speed rail. Before 2004, China’s efforts to develop it had limited success. Since then, a mix of two policies—encouraging technology transfer from multinationals (in return for market access) and a coordinated R&D-investment effort—has helped China Railways’ high-speed trains to dominate the local industry. The multinationals’ revenue in this sector has remained largely unchanged since the early 2000s.</p>
<p>But it is too simplistic to claim that government support is the only reason China has had some B2B success. The strength of the country’s scientific and technical talent is growing, and local companies increasingly bring real capabilities to the table. What’s more, a number of government-supported innovation efforts have <i>not</i> been successful. Some notable examples include attempts to develop an indigenous 3G telecommunications protocol called TDS-CDMA and to replace the global Wi-Fi standard with a China-only Internet security protocol, WAPI.</p>
<h3 class="sm black">Advantage, multinationals?</h3>
<p>Simultaneously, multinationals have been shaping China’s innovation landscape by leveraging global assets. Consider, for example, the joint venture between General Motors and the Shanghai Automotive Industry Corporation, which adapted a US minivan (Buick’s GL8) for use in the Chinese market and more recently introduced a version developed in China, for China. The model has proved hugely popular among executives.</p>
<p>In fact, the market for vehicles powered by internal-combustion engines remains dominated by multinationals, despite significant incentives and encouragement from the Chinese government, which had hoped that some domestic automakers would emerge as leaders by now. The continued strength of multinationals indicates how hard it is to break through in industries with 40 or 50 years of intellectual capital. Transferring the skills needed to design and manufacture complex engineering systems has proved a significant challenge requiring mentorship, the right culture, and time.</p>
<p>We are seeing the emergence of similar challenges in electric vehicles, where early indications suggest that the balance is swinging toward the multinationals because of superior product quality. By relying less on purely indigenous innovation, China is trying to make sure the electric-vehicle story has an ending different from that of its telecommunications protocol efforts. The government’s stated aspiration of having more than five million plug-in hybrid and battery electric vehicles on the road by 2020 is heavily supported by a mix of extensive subsidies and tax incentives for local companies, combined with strict market access rules for foreign companies and the creation of new revenue pools through government and public fleet-purchase programs. But the subsidies and incentives may not be enough to overcome the technical challenges of learning to build these vehicles, particularly if multinationals decline to invest with local companies.</p>
<h3>Four priorities for innovators in China</h3>
<p>There’s no magic formula for innovation—and that goes doubly for China, where the challenges and opportunities facing domestic and multinational players are so different. Some of the priorities we describe here, such as instilling a culture of risk taking and learning, are more pressing for Chinese companies. Others, such as retaining local talent, may be harder for multinationals. Collectively, these priorities include some of the critical variables that will influence which companies lead China’s innovation revolution and how far it goes.</p>
<img alt="China high-speed train" src="~/media/McKinsey/dotcom/Insights/Asia-Pacific/A CEOs guide to innovation in China/ChinaTrain.ashx?mw=510">
<p class="grayNote small">A Chinese-built high-speed train at the Wuhan Railway Station, in Wuhan, China.<br>© Guo Xulei/Xinhua Press/Corbis</p><h3 class="sm black">Deeply understanding Chinese customers</h3>
<p>Alibaba’s Web-based trading platform, Taobao, is a great example of a product that emerged from deep insights into how customers were underserved and their inability to connect with suppliers, as well as a sophisticated understanding of the Chinese banking system. This dominant marketplace enables thousands of Chinese manufacturers to find and transact with potential customers directly. What looks like a straightforward eBay-like trading platform actually embeds numerous significant innovations to support these transactions, such as an ability to facilitate electronic fund transfers and to account for idiosyncrasies in the national banking system. Taobao wouldn’t have happened without Alibaba’s deep, analytically driven understanding of customers.</p>
<p>Few Chinese companies have the systematic ability to develop a deep understanding of customers’ problems. Domestic players have traditionally had a manufacturing-led focus on reapplying existing business models to deliver products for fast-growing markets. These “push” models will find it increasingly hard to unlock pockets of profitable growth. Shifting from delivery to creation requires more local research and development, as well as the nurturing of more market-driven organizations that can combine insights into detailed Chinese customer preferences with a clear sense of how the local business environment is evolving. Requirements include both research techniques relevant to China and people with the experience to draw out actionable customer insights.</p>
<p>Many multinationals have these capabilities, but unless they have been operating in China for some years, they may well lack the domestic-market knowledge or relationships needed to apply them effectively. The solution—building a true domestic Chinese presence rather than an outpost—sounds obvious, but it’s difficult to carry out without commitment from the top. Too many companies fail by using “fly over” management. But some multinationals appear to be investing the necessary resources; for example, we recently met (separately) with top executives of two big industrial companies who were being transferred from the West to run global R&D organizations from Shanghai. The idea is to be closer to Chinese customers and the network of institutions and universities from which multinationals source talent.</p>
<h3 class="sm black">Retaining local talent</h3>
<p>China’s universities graduate more than 10,000 science PhDs each year, and increasing numbers of Chinese scientists working overseas are returning home. Multinationals in particular are struggling to tap this inflow of researchers and managers. A recent survey by the executive-recruiting firm Heidrick & Struggles found that 77 percent of the senior executives from multinational companies responding say they have difficulty attracting managers in China, while 91 percent regard employee turnover as their top talent challenge.</p>
<p>Retention is more of an issue for multinationals than for domestic companies, but as big foreign players raise their game, so must local ones. Chinese companies, for example, excel at creating a community-like environment to build loyalty to the institution. That helps keep some employees in place when competing offers arise, but it may not always be enough.</p>
<p>Talented Chinese employees increasingly recognize the benefits of being associated with a well-known foreign brand and like the mentorship and training that foreign companies can provide. So multinationals that commit themselves to developing meaningful career paths for Chinese employees should have a chance in the growing fight with their Chinese competitors for R&D talent. Initiatives might include in-house training courses or apprenticeship programs, perhaps with local universities. General Motors sponsors projects in which professors and engineering departments at leading universities research issues of interest to the automaker. That helps it to develop closer relations with the institutions from which it recruits and to train students before they graduate.</p>
<p>Some multinationals energize Chinese engineers by shifting their roles from serving as capacity in a support of existing global programs to contributing significantly to new innovation thrusts, often aimed at the local market. This approach, increasingly common in the pharma industry, may hold lessons for other kinds of multinationals that have established R&D or innovation centers in China in recent years (read about AstraZeneca’s experience in “Three snapshots of Chinese innovation”). The keys to success include a clear objective— for instance, will activity support global programs or develop China-for-China innovations?—and a clear plan for attracting and retaining the talent needed to staff such centers. Too often, we visit impressive R&D facilities, stocked with the latest equipment, that are almost empty because staffing them has proved difficult.</p>
<h3 class="sm black">Instilling a culture of risk taking</h3>
<p>Failure is a required element of innovation, but it isn’t the norm in China, where a culture of obedience and adherence to rules prevails in most companies. Breaking or even bending them is not expected and rarely tolerated. To combat these attitudes, companies must find ways to make initiative taking more acceptable and better rewarded.</p>
<p>One approach we found, in a leading solar company, was to transfer risk from individual innovators to teams. Shared accountability and community support made increased risk taking and experimentation safer. The company has used these “innovation work groups” to develop everything from more efficient battery technology to new manufacturing processes. Team-based approaches also have proved effective for some multinationals trying to stimulate initiative taking (read about General Motors’ approach in “Three snapshots of Chinese innovation”).</p>
<p>How fast a culture of innovation takes off varies by industry. We see a much more rapid evolution toward the approach of Western companies in the way Chinese high-tech enterprises learn from their customers and how they apply that learning to create new products made for China (read a perspective on the evolution of its semiconductor sector in “Thee snapshots of Chinese innovation”). That approach is much less common at state-owned enterprises, since they are held back by hierarchical, benchmark-driven cultures.</p>
<h3 class="sm black">Promoting collaboration</h3>
<p>One area where multinationals currently have an edge is promoting collaboration and the internal collision of ideas, which can yield surprising new insights and business opportunities. In many Chinese companies, traditional organizational and cultural barriers inhibit such exchanges.</p>
<p>Although a lot of these companies have become more professional and adept at delivering products in large volumes, their ability to scale up an organization that can work collaboratively has not kept pace. Their rigorous, linear processes for bringing new products to market ensure rapid commercialization but create too many hand-offs where insights are lost and trade-offs for efficiency are promoted.</p>
<p>One Chinese consumer electronics company has repeatedly tried to improve the way it innovates. Senior management has called for new ideas and sponsored efforts to create new best-in-class processes, while junior engineers have designed high-quality prototypes. Yet the end result continues to be largely undifferentiated, incremental improvements. The biggest reason appears to be a lack of cross-company collaboration and a reliance on processes designed to build and reinforce scale in manufacturing. In effect, the technical and commercial sides of the business don’t cooperate in a way that would allow some potentially winning ideas to reach the market. As Chinese organizations mature, stories like this one may become rarer.</p>
<div class="articleBreak"></div>
<p>China hasn’t yet experienced a true innovation revolution. It will need time to evolve from a country of incremental innovation based on technology transfers to one where breakthrough innovation is common. The government will play a powerful role in that process, but ultimately it will be the actions of domestic companies and multinationals that dictate the pace of change—and determine who leads it.</p>
<div class="about-authors">
<h3 class="sm black">About the authors</h3>
<p><b>Gordon Orr</b> is a director in McKinsey’s Shanghai office, where <b>Erik Roth</b> is a principal.</p>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Can Africa continue to grow?Upated</title>
      <description>A panel of regional business leaders discusses its prospects.</description>
      <link>http://www.mckinsey.com/en/insights/africa/copy_of_can_africa_continue_to_grow</link>
      <guid>http://www.mckinsey.com/en/insights/africa/copy_of_can_africa_continue_to_grow</guid>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Jul 2013 02:25:21 GMT</pubDate>
      <id>5525cbd6-93af-45bf-8f79-d9e6918640b1</id>
      <category>Africa</category>
      <dc:creator><![CDATA[Mckinsey]]></dc:creator>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><strong>Gross corruption,</strong> constant wars, and irrational economics long made Africa a poor, troubled continent where natural-resource companies were almost the only multinationals that dared or cared to do business. But in the 1990s, the picture improved. The wars started subsiding. Many governments balanced their budgets and created a better, safer environment for companies, both foreign and domestic. And the African consumer began to stir. Now 80 million households earn at least the equivalent of $5,000 annually, the point where discretionary spending commences—an increase of 80 percent in eight years. Meanwhile, the continent’s GDP has been rising steadily, at around 5 percent a year, for the past decade, reaching $1.6 trillion in 2008. Last year, Africa was one of just two regions (the other was Asia) where GDP rose. </p>
<p>Is all this good news sustainable? At the 2010 Fortune Global Forum, in Cape Town, South Africa, McKinsey Publishing’s Rik Kirkland spoke with Absa’s Maria Ramos, Coca-Cola’s Bill Egbe, and McKinsey’s Norbert Dörr to find the answer.</p>
<!--roadblock-->
<p>Watch the video, or <a href="~/media/50D1DB095F594BAD8EEACEE13B4CC99E.ashx">download a PDF</a> of the transcript.</p>
<figure>
    <h4>Video</h4>
    <div>
      <h3></h3>
      <p>A panel of regional business leaders discusses its prospects.</p>
    </div>
    <video width="" height="" controls poster="http://brightcove.vo.llnwd.net/e1/pd/1971571337001/1971571337001_2553694144001_ChinaTech-VideoStill-1024x576.jpg?pubId=1971571337001">
      <source src="http://brightcove.vo.llnwd.net/e1/uds/pd/1971571337001/1971571337001_2522840653001_Chinatech-full.mp4" />
		</video>
    </figure>]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Can Africa continue to grow 1234?</title>
      <description>A panel of regional business leaders discusses its prospects.</description>
      <link>http://www.mckinsey.com/en/insights/africa/can_africa_continue_to_grow</link>
      <guid>http://www.mckinsey.com/en/insights/africa/can_africa_continue_to_grow</guid>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 May 2012 05:00:47 GMT</pubDate>
      <id>6d8e6841-be20-4930-ad57-5146196cedf4</id>
      <category>Africa</category>
      <dc:creator><![CDATA[Test author]]></dc:creator>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><strong>Gross corruption,</strong> constant wars, and irrational economics long made Africa a poor, troubled continent where natural-resource companies were almost the only multinationals that dared or cared to do business. But in the 1990s, the picture improved. The wars started subsiding. Many governments balanced their budgets and created a better, safer environment for companies, both foreign and domestic. And the African consumer began to stir. Now 80 million households earn at least the equivalent of $5,000 annually, the point where discretionary spending commences—an increase of 80 percent in eight years. Meanwhile, the continent’s GDP has been rising steadily, at around 5 percent a year, for the past decade, reaching $1.6 trillion in 2008. Last year, Africa was one of just two regions (the other was Asia) where GDP rose. </p>
<p>Is all this good news sustainable? At the 2010 Fortune Global Forum, in Cape Town, South Africa, McKinsey Publishing’s Rik Kirkland spoke with Absa’s Maria Ramos, Coca-Cola’s Bill Egbe, and McKinsey’s Norbert Dörr to find the answer.</p>
<!--roadblock-->
<p>Watch the video, or <a href="~/media/50D1DB095F594BAD8EEACEE13B4CC99E.ashx">download a PDF</a> of the transcript.</p>
<figure>
    <h4>Video</h4>
    <div>
      <h3></h3>
      <p>A panel of regional business leaders discusses its prospects.</p>
    </div>
    <video width="" height="" controls poster="http://brightcove.vo.llnwd.net/e1/pd/1971571337001/1971571337001_2553694144001_ChinaTech-VideoStill-1024x576.jpg?pubId=1971571337001">
      <source src="http://brightcove.vo.llnwd.net/e1/uds/pd/1971571337001/1971571337001_2522840653001_Chinatech-full.mp4" />
		</video>
    </figure>]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The value of China's emerging middle class</title>
      <description />
      <link>http://www.mckinsey.com/en/insights/china/copy_of_the_value_of_emerging_middle_class_in_china</link>
      <guid>http://www.mckinsey.com/en/insights/china/copy_of_the_value_of_emerging_middle_class_in_china</guid>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Jul 2013 07:32:47 GMT</pubDate>
      <id>64af21ee-797e-4384-bf62-980dda096f3b</id>
      <category>China</category>
      <dc:creator><![CDATA[Diana Farrell, Ulrich A. Gersch, and Elizabeth Stephenson]]></dc:creator>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>As global companies entered China, many focused mainly on serving China’s urban affluent consumers. However, if they continue this strategy of simply skimming the cream from the top, they risk missing the real opportunity–the emerging middle class.</p>
<figure>
    <h4>Podcast</h4>
    <div>
      <h3></h3>
      <p>Get the key insights on China's consumer demand and its emerging middle class.</p>
    </div>
      <audio controls>
        <source src="http://www.mckinsey.com/assets/dotcom/mgi/interactives/China/MGI_Chinas_middle_class.mp3" />
			  </audio>
    </figure>
<p>During the next 20 years, a huge middle class with enormous spending power will emerge in China’s cities. As incomes increase, the spending patterns of this group of consumers will evolve, fueling various levels of growth across consumption categories. </p>
<p>Though the potential benefits are enormous, serving this middle class has unique challenges and companies will need to think creatively to succeed.</p>
<ul class="raqs">
    <li><a href="https://www.mckinseyquarterly.com/Economic_Studies/Productivity_Performance/The_value_of_Chinas_emerging_middle_class_1798?gp=1" target="_blank"><span class="ico sprite raquoIco"></span><span class="txtLg">Read more on the <em>McKinsey Quarterly</em> site</span> </a></li>
</ul>
<p> </p>]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>China’s confident consumers</title>
      <description>A survey highlights how fast the market is changing.
</description>
      <link>http://www.mckinsey.com/en/insights/asia-pacific/chinas_confident_consumers</link>
      <guid>http://www.mckinsey.com/en/insights/asia-pacific/chinas_confident_consumers</guid>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 May 2012 05:01:04 GMT</pubDate>
      <id>4df17165-34eb-4977-9e16-24434b7084a3</id>
      <category>Asia-Pacific</category>
      <dc:creator><![CDATA[Yuval Atsmon and Max Magni]]></dc:creator>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><strong>The Chinese</strong> have taken to consumerism with ease, embracing thousands of new products, services, and brands. But the flipside is that the Chinese market changes at a speed capable of leaving all but the nimblest of companies breathless, as McKinsey’s 2011 survey of Chinese consumers highlights.<a class='link-footnote' rel='#footnote1' href='#' onclick='return false;'><sup>1</sup></a> <span id='footnote1' class='tooltip' style='display:none;'><span class='footnote-content'><span class='footnote-number'>1.</span><span class='footnote-text'>
McKinsey’s 2011 survey of Chinese consumers was conducted between February and April of 2011 and is the sixth annual study on Chinese consumers’ shopping behavior. The survey interviewed 15,000 consumers in 49 cities, across four city tiers, six geographic regions, and 17 out of 22 city clusters that McKinsey defined. The survey covered consumers’ general attitudes, leisure-activity participation, and Internet usage, and dove deep into five categories, including apparel, automobile, consumer electronics, food and beverages, and home and personal care.
</span><span class='clear'></span> </span><span class='footnote-bottom'></span></span> Three findings stood out. Even in the face of rising inflation, Chinese consumers are more confident this year than in 2010 about their financial prospects. Among urban consumers, the number of first-time buyers—a group that has been a major driver of category growth in China—is declining. Finally, although brand awareness is rising, we see little sign that brand loyalty is following suit. In fact, more and more consumers choose among a growing number of favorite brands.</p><!--roadblock--><p>
These and other findings from this year’s survey have clear implications for companies seeking to capture the next wave of consumer-spending growth in China. Any broad-brush approach to winning consumers’ rising spending power will miss the mark.</p><h3>Consumers and inflation </h3><p>
At the end of 2010, annual inflation in China was 4.6 percent. By this August, it had reached 6.2 percent—close to its highest level in three years. This development is inevitably affecting real growth in consumption, which fell to 8.5 percent in 2010, from 9.4 percent in 2009. Still, our survey found that consumers are more confident about their financial future than they were last year, and this will probably affect their buying behavior. Fifty-eight percent of respondents said they expected their incomes to rise next year, compared with 39 percent in 2010.</p><p>
No doubt reflecting this confidence, the survey shows that the number of respondents who choose to spend more—buying in greater quantities, more frequently, or more expensive items in a given category—is holding firm. Whereas last year’s survey showed that consumers offset higher spending in some categories by spending less in others, this year there appears to be much less rebalancing.</p><p>
Also noteworthy is <i>how</i> consumers who spent more in 2010 than in 2009 account for their higher spending. On average across categories, some 50 percent of the survey participants identified inflation as the main reason. But of the remainder, 35 percent said they were trading up (buying more expensive goods in a given category), an increase from 26 percent in last year’s survey. Sixty percent said that buying in larger quantities or more frequently was the main reason for their higher spending, compared with 54 percent in last year’s survey. But only 5 percent of consumers said they were spending more because they were first-time buyers in certain product categories—down from 20 percent in last year’s survey—an indication of the growing maturity of many such categories.</p><h3>Consumers and category growth</h3><p>
A decade ago, most category growth came from first-time buyers. But this is changing, as so many products are now both available and within the financial reach of large numbers of consumers. Big variations in the importance of first-time buyers have opened up, depending on the category and geographic region. Take large personal-care categories such as skin care and hair care, for example. In personal care, only 3 percent of respondents who said they spent more on the category in the past year were first-time buyers. In less mature niche categories (deodorants, for example), first-time buyers remain more important, as they are for several big-ticket items. In personal digital gadgets, for example, 23 percent of respondents said they had bought such goods for the first time.</p><p>
At the geographic level, the penetration of certain goods may be high in China’s more economically developed regions, but plenty of consumer-conversion opportunities remain in less developed ones, which the government has targeted for higher economic growth. Again in personal care, the survey showed that 15 percent of consumers in the Chengdu cluster—the region that encompasses the western city of Chengdu, as well as the less developed surrounding cities of Mianyang and Neijiang—said they had started to use products in these categories only in the past year. Just 1 percent of consumers in the more developed Hangzhou cluster, which includes the cities of Hangzhou, Jinhua, and Linhai, gave that answer.<a class='link-footnote' rel='#footnote2' href='#' onclick='return false;'><sup>2</sup></a> <span id='footnote2' class='tooltip' style='display:none;'><span class='footnote-content'><span class='footnote-number'>2.</span><span class='footnote-text'>
In 2010, the Hangzhou cluster contributed 6.24 percent of urban GDP; the Chengdu cluster, 2.87 percent.
</span><span class='clear'></span> </span><span class='footnote-bottom'></span></span></p><h3>Consumers and brands</h3><p>
Our survey detects no letup in the influence of brands on Chinese consumers’ buying decisions. But neither does it indicate strong signs of increasing loyalty to any single brand.</p><p>
The survey shows the extent to which consumers value brands more than price or channel, largely because they believe that branded products are safer, of higher quality, and more reliable than nonbranded ones. But faith in brands still does not translate into brand loyalty. In fact, both the number of consumers who always choose from among a relatively small set of brands—whom we refer to as “repertoire loyalists”—and the number of brands in their repertoire continue to rise. The average Chinese consumer now chooses among three to five brands in any given category, compared with two to three brands two years ago. In some categories, such as apparel, where luxury brands have grown hugely popular, the contrast is sharper still.</p><p>
To succeed in this environment, executives will need to understand where the growth prospects lie, both at the category level and in different geographic regions. Only then will companies be able to prioritize resources and tailor strategies appropriately, to strike a balance between building mass appeal and meeting the needs of specific consumer groups, to focus on perceived value rather than absolute price, to modernize marketing tools for the Internet age, and to embrace rapidly growing online sales channels quickly. Companies must have both the flexibility to adapt and the skills to innovate to keep in step with the Chinese market’s exciting development.</p><p><div class="about-authors"><h3 class="sm black">About the authors</h3><p><b>Yuval Atsmon</b> and <b>Max Magni</b> are principals in McKinsey’s Shanghai and Hong Kong offices, respectively. This article is adapted from the McKinsey report <a href="http://csi.mckinsey.com/Home/Knowledge_by_region/Asia/China/2011_Annual_Chinese_Consumer_Survey.aspx"><i>2011 Annual Chinese Consumer Study—The New Frontiers of Growth</i></a> (October 2011), available on mckinsey.com.</p></div></p>]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Exploding the myths of offshoring</title>
      <description />
      <link>http://www.mckinsey.com/en/insights/employment_and_growth/exploding_the_myths_of_offshoring</link>
      <guid>http://www.mckinsey.com/en/insights/employment_and_growth/exploding_the_myths_of_offshoring</guid>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Apr 2013 23:00:46 GMT</pubDate>
      <id>ac79713e-1645-4593-bf10-82206a72ec81</id>
      <category>Employment and growth</category>
      <dc:creator><![CDATA[Martin N. Baily, Diana Farrell]]></dc:creator>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>With the digital revolution and the dramatic fall in international telecommunications costs comes the prospect that white-collar jobs—once insulated from global competition—can be performed offshore, in low-wage nations such as India, where labor can be hired for as little as one-tenth its cost in the United States. Call-center agents, data processors, medical technicians, and software programmers could all find their jobs at risk from the nation's growing trade in services with emerging markets. In fact, offshoring is frequently blamed for the agonizingly slow pace of job growth in the United States, despite a recovering economy.</p>
<p>Even free traders have wavered in their beliefs. Critics warn that millions of people in the United States will become jobless. The response from Congress has been to include in a fiscal 2004 spending bill a provision prohibiting federal agencies from outsourcing some kinds of work to private companies that use workers in foreign countries. Indeed, 23 states are considering similar restrictions; 4 have already passed them. Jobs and trade have become the hot-button issues of the 2004 presidential election race.</p>
<p>The current debate is misplaced, however, because the problem is neither trade itself nor globalization more broadly but rather the question of how the country should allocate the benefits of global trade. Trade in services, like other forms of international trade, benefits the United States as a whole by making the economic pie bigger and raising the standard of living. Outsourcing jobs abroad can help keep companies profitable, thereby preserving other US jobs. The cost savings can be used to lower prices and to offer consumers new and better types of services. By raising productivity, offshoring enables companies to invest more in the next-generation technologies and business ideas that create new jobs. And with the world's most flexible and innovative economy, the United States is uniquely positioned to benefit from the trend. After all, despite a large overall trade deficit, the country has consistently run a surplus in its international trade in services.</p>
<ul class="raqs">
    <li><a href="https://www.mckinseyquarterly.com/Operations/Exploding_the_myths_of_offshoring_1453" target="_blank"><span class="ico sprite raquoIco"></span><span class="txtLg">Read more on the <em>McKinsey Quarterly</em> site</span> </a></li>
</ul>]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Exploding the myths about offshoring</title>
      <description />
      <link>http://www.mckinsey.com/en/insights/employment_and_growth/exploding_the_myths_about_offshoring</link>
      <guid>http://www.mckinsey.com/en/insights/employment_and_growth/exploding_the_myths_about_offshoring</guid>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Apr 2013 23:00:46 GMT</pubDate>
      <id>2029f949-1f6d-4aca-9168-752d3dd74379</id>
      <category>Employment and growth</category>
      <dc:creator><![CDATA[Martin N. Baily, Diana Farrell]]></dc:creator>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>In this essay, Martin Baily, a Senior Fellow at the Institute for International Economics and a Senior Advisor to the McKinsey Global Institute (MGI), and Diana Farrell, Director, MGI, reflect on the current heated debate about offshoring and put the issue in perspective. The authors cite MGI research that demonstrates the sizeable benefits the US stands to gain from offshoring through corporate savings, additional exports, repatriated profits, greater productivity, and new jobs.</p>
<p>While free trade creates wealth and improves a nation's standard of living, not all groups reap the same benefits, particularly in the short term. The reality of the emerging global economy is that the workforce is experiencing higher turnover than ever before. The challenge is how to make that inevitable process less painful and share more of the wealth being created.</p>
<p>Baily and Farrell cite concrete options for political and business leaders to help workers make the transition. Developing countries on their end must open their economies to attain the full benefits that free trade makes possible. Case evidence from MGI's research demonstrates how developing countries benefit from foreign direct investment. By resisting further liberalization, developing economies risk missing out on tremendous growth opportunities. </p>]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>French employment 2020: Five priorities for action</title>
      <description />
      <link>http://www.mckinsey.com/en/insights/employment_and_growth/french_employment_2020</link>
      <guid>http://www.mckinsey.com/en/insights/employment_and_growth/french_employment_2020</guid>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Apr 2013 23:00:46 GMT</pubDate>
      <id>12b93c6f-ac06-4ae5-967e-57001fd73d69</id>
      <category>Employment and growth</category>
      <dc:creator><![CDATA[Eric Labaye, Charles Roxburgh, Clarisse Magnin, and Jan Mischke]]></dc:creator>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>France’s labor market has been relatively resilient in the face of the global financial crisis of 2008 and 2009 and of the sovereign-debt crisis, which gathered full force last year. But unemployment has begun to rise again. Achieving a considerable boost to employment is now critical because it is difficult to see how, without reversing this decline, France can sustain a social safety net that is already under significant strain.</p>
<p>Until the 1990s, France was among Europe’s leading economies in per capita GDP. By 2010, however, the country had dropped to 11th out of the EU-15. Low labor force participation of seniors and young people, as well as high unemployment rates are the main drivers of this per capita GDP gap. </p>
<p>A report from the McKinsey Global Institute finds that to meet even moderate ambitions for employment and prosperity, France must create more than twice as many net new jobs annually as it did during the past 20 years.</p>
<p>Unless France acts, by 2020 it may face a shortfall of 2.2 million highly skilled workers, and 2.3 million low-skilled workers will be unable to find jobs. Addressing this intensifying structural mismatch of skills is required to increase employment.</p>
<p style="margin-top: 30px;"><span class="mck_h6"><h6>Exhibit</span></h6></span>
<p><img width="510" height="426" style="margin-bottom: 30px;" alt="Projected 2020 employment in France" src="~/media/4306713F731F499DA582B1D20A50960A.ashx" /></p>
<p>Drawing on European best practices, the report recommends that France should set five priorities for its 2020 labor agenda:</p>
<ul class="bullListSep">
    <li>reform labor market conditions for seniors to increase their level of workforce participation </li>
    <li>boost the overall skills of students and workers and better adapt their skills to the knowledge economy’s market demands </li>
    <li>improve labor costs and the flexibility of the labor market </li>
    <li>support job-creating growth for the high- and low-skilled alike </li>
    <li>improve mechanisms to ensure that employment policies are effective and efficient </li>
</ul>]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Five myths about how to create jobs</title>
      <description />
      <link>http://www.mckinsey.com/en/insights/employment_and_growth/five_myths_about_how_to_create_jobs</link>
      <guid>http://www.mckinsey.com/en/insights/employment_and_growth/five_myths_about_how_to_create_jobs</guid>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Apr 2013 23:00:46 GMT</pubDate>
      <id>ba85a3f4-5667-414c-9c90-da625eee7dbd</id>
      <category>Employment and growth</category>
      <dc:creator><![CDATA[James Manyika and Byron Auguste]]></dc:creator>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The costly retirement of 76 million US baby boomers will swell the ranks of the elderly to more than 20 percent of the population of the United States during the next 20 years. In Europe and Japan, the elderly will come to account for more than 30 percent of the population during the same period. This transformation is about to create a new sense of urgency to get the most from every government dollar. Public services beyond health care and pensions for seniors will face epic squeezes, and officials will struggle to balance the needs of retirees and younger citizens while still holding taxes to politically acceptable levels. Boosting the government's performance will be an imperative no country can ignore.</p>
<p>To be sure, attempts have been made before. In the United States, former Vice President Al Gore's efforts to "reinvent government" in the early 1990s scored some successes. The administration of President George W. Bush has made efforts to reform civil service rules that inhibit some sensible management practices. The Government Accountability Office (formerly the General Accounting Office) has shown perennial leadership in prodding government departments to address their management challenges. In the United Kingdom, Peter Gershon's recent review of government efficiency1 has galvanized work to improve productivity across the public sector, with a target of £20 billion in savings by the end of 2008.</p>
<p>But veterans of reform efforts agree that they have barely begun to scratch the surface of the government's performance potential. One reason is that reforms take sustained attention—often rare when they become caught up in partisan or interest group politics. What's more, political cultures remain oriented to legislation, not to executing and managing programs. Few people make their name by improving the way government runs.</p>
<p>Nonetheless, the coming era's extraordinary fiscal pressures will force leaders to overcome these obstacles. In the developed world, the state commands a large share of the economy, so improving the performance of government departments can generate hundreds of billions of dollars of value. Our experience working with public institutions in 50 countries has shown us that the opportunity, though hard to capture, is large enough to take some of the sting out of the hard choices that aging societies face. With the first baby boomers becoming eligible for retiree health and pension benefits in just a few years, there is no time to lose.</p>
<ul class="raqs" sizset="78" sizcache="4">
    <li><a href="https://www.mckinseyquarterly.com/Five_myths_about_how_to_create_jobs_2526" target="_blank"><span class="ico sprite raquoIco"></span><span class="txtLg">Read more on the <em>McKinsey Quarterly</em> site</span> </a></li>
</ul>]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Beyond cheap labor: Lessons for developing economies</title>
      <description />
      <link>http://www.mckinsey.com/en/insights/employment_and_growth/beyond_cheap_labor</link>
      <guid>http://www.mckinsey.com/en/insights/employment_and_growth/beyond_cheap_labor</guid>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Apr 2013 23:00:46 GMT</pubDate>
      <id>436b15e3-29c3-4170-a0b9-1400099350bb</id>
      <category>Employment and growth</category>
      <dc:creator><![CDATA[Diana Farrell, Antonio Puron, and Jaana K. Remes]]></dc:creator>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Buoyed by the North American Free Trade Agreement (NAFTA), Mexico in the 1990s was the bustling factory floor of the Americas. But since 2000, as China rose to assume that role, more than 270,000 Mexicans have lost assembly jobs, hundreds of factories have closed their doors, and Mexico's trade deficit with China has grown to more than $5 billion. The ubiquitous "Made in China" stamp, found on everything from toys to textiles to statues of Our Lady of Guadalupe, has become the incarnation of the single greatest perceived threat to Mexico's economic prosperity—and a symbol of the pitfalls of globalization.</p>
<p>Mexico's fears are not unique. China's economic surge and its entry into the World Trade Organization have sparked alarm across the developing world. In middle-income countries such as Brazil, Poland, Portugal, and South Korea, a rising standard of living makes their position as low-wage producers and exporters increasingly tenuous.</p>
<p>Rather than fixating on jobs lost to China, these countries should remember a fact of economic life: no place can remain the world's low-cost producer forever—even China will lose that title one day. Instead of trying to defend low-wage assembly jobs, Mexico and other middle-income countries should focus on creating jobs that add higher value. Only if more productive companies with higher-value-added activities replace less productive ones can middle-income economies continue down the development path. Even so, being part of the global economy requires these countries, like Lewis Carroll's Alice in Through the Looking Glass, to do a lot of running just to stay in the same place. Unfortunately, for too many of them the focus on China—and, more broadly, political rhetoric against globalization—are blocking reform efforts.</p>
<p class="mck_h3_md"><h3>Blame China?</h3></p>
<p>To developing countries watching foreign investors head east, China's economic prowess might seem invincible, but history suggests otherwise. Only 20 years ago, for example, the United States was convinced that the superior business models and industrial policies of Germany and Japan would shutter every last domestic factory door. In the 1990s, the United States fretted about the threat from the high-tech industries of South Korea and Taiwan, while presidential candidates warned of the "giant sucking sound" made by the migration of jobs to Mexico under NAFTA. These days, the United States is more concerned about the effect of China's economy on its trade balance and employment rate.</p>
<p>Nearly all countries worry about jobs lost to others—a fact often exploited for political ends. The demagoguery obscures the fact that countries must evolve to meet the challenges presented by new competitors outside their borders.</p>
<p>Mexico is a case in point. Like most middle-income countries, it has grown more prosperous through freer trade and liberalization. Its average household income is now more than twice the level in China and other low-wage countries, and its manufacturing wage rates reflect this increasing prosperity. But the maquiladora assembly operations that line the US border—often the most visible face of Mexico's entry into the global economy—are only a small part of the cause. Since NAFTA came into effect, in 1994, the country has received upward of $170 billion in foreign direct investment—more than three times the amount that India attracted. Yet less than 15 percent of this investment has gone to the maquiladoras; the vast majority has been motivated by a desire to sell into Mexico's large domestic market, not to produce cheap goods for export. Our research shows that non-maquiladora investments have generated a wide range of benefits for Mexico's economy by creating jobs, boosting competition and productivity, lowering prices, and enhancing consumer choice. Consider the impact of foreign investment on Mexico's automobile market: consumers can now choose from dozens of models, compared with just a few of them before. In the retailing industry, the price of fresh food in Mexico City is 40 percent below its level in 1993, the year before NAFTA opened up the economy. The lesson for Mexico and for other countries where jobs are going offshore is this: don't overestimate the value of low-wage employment.</p>
<ul class="raqs">
    <li><a href="https://www.mckinseyquarterly.com/Economic_Studies/Country_Reports/Beyond_cheap_labor_Lessons_for_developing_economies_1545?gp=1#Exhibit1" target="_blank"><span class="ico sprite raquoIco"></span><span class="txtLg">Read more on the <em>McKinsey Quarterly</em> site</span> </a></li>
</ul>]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>An economy that works: Job creation and America's future</title>
      <description />
      <link>http://www.mckinsey.com/en/insights/employment_and_growth/an_economy_that_works_for_us_job_creation</link>
      <guid>http://www.mckinsey.com/en/insights/employment_and_growth/an_economy_that_works_for_us_job_creation</guid>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Apr 2013 23:00:46 GMT</pubDate>
      <id>754b2dd8-1b8d-4d88-be08-d6c15ae5a8fc</id>
      <category>Employment and growth</category>
      <dc:creator><![CDATA[James Manyika, Susan Lund, Byron Auguste, Lenny Mendonca, Tim Welsh, Sreenivas Ramaswamy]]></dc:creator>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>For the United States to return to full employment—finding work for the currently unemployed and accommodating new entrants into the labor force this decade—the US economy will need to create 21 million jobs by 2020, according to MGI's analysis.</p>
<p></p>
<p>To understand how this might happen, MGI launched a research project that combines extensive sector analysis, interviews with human resource executives, a proprietary survey of 2,000 business leaders, and our own scenario analysis and modeling.</p>
<p>The research analyzes the causes of slow job creation in the period before the recession and during the recovery and the implications of these forces for future job growth. The research projects how the US labor force will evolve over the next ten years and creates different scenarios for job growth based on extensive analysis of sector trends. MGI's central finding is that a return to full employment will occur in only the most optimistic job-growth scenario. This will require not only a robust economic recovery but also a concerted effort to address other factors that impede employment, including growing gaps in skill and education.</p>
<p>The report offers a range of illustrative solutions based on lessons from US states and other countries that MGI hopes will add to the national conversation on jobs.</p>
<p class="mck_h3_md"><h3>Findings include:</h3></p>
<p></p>
<ul class="bullListSep">
    <li>Recoveries are increasingly becoming "jobless" due to firm restructuring, skill and geographic mismatches between workers and jobs, and sharp decline in new start-ups.</li>
    <li>The US needs to create 21 million new jobs by 2020 to regain full employment—and only achieves this in our most optimistic job-growth scenario.</li>
    <li>The US workforce will continue to grow until 2020, but under current trends, many workers will not have the right skills for the available jobs. Technology is changing the nature of work: Jobs are being disaggregated into tasks, work is becoming virtual, and firms are relying on flexible labor (temporary, contract workers). These trends offer new opportunities for creating jobs in the United States, a trend that some companies do not fully appreciate.</li>
    <li>Progress in four dimensions will be essential for reviving the US job-creation machine: Develop the US workforce-skill to better match what employers are looking for; expand US workers' share of global economic growth by attracting foreign investment and spurring exports; revive the nation's spark by supporting emerging industries, ensuring more of them scale up in the United States, and reviving new business start-ups; and speed up regulatory decision-making that blocks business expansion and new investment. </li>
</ul>
<p>The report is part of a series of MGI perspectives on the theme of US growth and renewal.</p>]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Employment performance</title>
      <description />
      <link>http://www.mckinsey.com/en/insights/employment_and_growth/employment_performance</link>
      <guid>http://www.mckinsey.com/en/insights/employment_and_growth/employment_performance</guid>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Apr 2013 23:00:46 GMT</pubDate>
      <id>63b5ed8b-2243-42d4-8c3e-1a601767a8c8</id>
      <category>Employment and growth</category>
      <dc:creator><![CDATA[Bill Lewis, Thomas Gerstner, René Limacher, Mike Longman, Mineki Toyama, Michele Appendino, Tomas Calleja, Michel Paulin, Kathy Huang, Eric Zitzewitz, et al.]]></dc:creator>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Unemployment is viewed as a serious problem in many industrial nations, but the reasons for it are not well understood. Among MGI's findings across seven industries is that Japan and the US have lower rates of unemploymen than European countries because they have created jobs in the market part of the economy. Differences in employment performance ultimately stem from differences in the rates at which industrial economies evolve.</p>
<p class="mck_h3_md"><h3>Synthesis</h3></p>
<p>In most of the countries studied, there were employment declines in three manufacturing industries. In market services, the general evidence points to increasing employment. The sizes of the increases in the service sector employment vary widely, with the US having the largest increase overall.</p>
<p class="mck_h3_md"><h3>Objectives and Approach</h3></p>
<p>There is no shortage of reports about employment but they all tend to focus on the issue from a macroeconomic perspective. MGI's work is based on the premise that understanding the causes of employment behavior at the industry level would allow us to determine the relative importance of particular labor, product, and capital market factors.</p>
<p class="mck_h3_md"><h3>Aggregate Analysis</h3></p>
<p>Four main factors effect the evolution of economies: productivity growth rates, innovation, trade and foreign direct investment, and consumption and investment patterns. MGI's fundamental hypothesis is that if there are barriers to the evolution of economies that prevent the transfer of resources into expanding firms and industries, then the result can be a slowing of overall job growth.</p>
<p class="mck_h3_md"><h3>Automotive Sector</h3></p>
<p>Intense competition in the 1980s increased cost pressures and triggered restructuring in automotive industries worldwide. Employment fared best in Japan where demand growth in the local market was combined with cost-driven improvements in trade performance.</p>
<p class="mck_h3_md"><h3>Computer Sector</h3></p>
<p>Despite being more innovative, the US computer industry did not create as many jobs as Japan. Earlier structural changes in the American industry explain much of this paradox.</p>
<p class="mck_h3_md"><h3>Furniture Sector</h3></p>
<p>As in most mature manufacturing sectors, the long-term employment trend in the furniture industry has been and will be downward. Innovation helped to slow this trend in the US, Italy, and Germany.</p>
<p class="mck_h3_md"><h3>Banking Sector</h3></p>
<p>Product, labor, and capital market barriers effected employment through changes in competitive intensity. The US, France, and Spain all experienced employment declines in traditional banking products as competitive intensity increased in the 1980s.</p>
<p class="mck_h3_md"><h3>Retailing Sector</h3></p>
<p>Retail is experiencing a structural shift as old formats disappear and new innovative ones offer more value to the customer and operate with greater efficiency. Rigidities in the product and labor markets retarded the emergence of high-value formats in France, Germany, and Japan, which in turn has led to lower overall employment.</p>
<p class="mck_h3_md"><h3>Film/TV/Video Sector</h3></p>
<p>In the high visibility film/TV/video sector, innovation is the driving force in both the creation and destruction of jobs. Slower employment growth in Europe can be explained by regulations that have inhibited the emergence of new segments.</p>
<p class="mck_h3_md"><h3>Construction Sector</h3></p>
<p>The myriad rules and regulations governing the construction sector in Europe and Japan provide an excellent example of how product market restrictions stifle output. Faster output growth - together with slower gains in productivity - resulted in better employment performance for the US.</p>
<p class="mck_h3_md"><h3>Implications</h3></p>
<p>Policymakers have numerous opportunities to encourage job creation by deregulating, particularly in the product market, which is the area of greatest opportunity as it could lead to job creation across the wage spectrum.</p>]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Changing the fortunes of America's workforce: A human-capital challenge</title>
      <description />
      <link>http://www.mckinsey.com/en/insights/employment_and_growth/changing_the_fortunes_of_us_workforce</link>
      <guid>http://www.mckinsey.com/en/insights/employment_and_growth/changing_the_fortunes_of_us_workforce</guid>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Apr 2013 23:00:46 GMT</pubDate>
      <id>deaaea6c-ca5e-410d-bba8-815c1f6b961f</id>
      <category>Employment and growth</category>
      <dc:creator><![CDATA[Diana Farrell, Martha Laboissiere, Imran Ahmed, Jan Peter aus dem Moore, Tilman Eichstadt, Lucia Fiorito, Alexander Grunewald, Jorge Hargrave, James Hoyt, Diana Kapsa, Tanya Khakbaz, Thomas Lamatsch, Dorothy Liao, Jenny Liao, Robin Matthias, Sara Parker, Ying Shi, Claudia Steinwender, Soyoko Umeno, Gina Campbell, and Katherine Hinkebein, et al.]]></dc:creator>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Rising income dispersion in the United States and other advanced nations has become a source of concern. Since the early 1970s, incomes for the highest US earners have raced ahead, while those at the bottom of the income distribution have stood still and those in the middle barely increased. Strikingly, even in the current recession, this underlying trend is not reversing. </p>
<p>In an effort to provide a comprehensive, well-founded explanation to policymakers and other interested parties, the McKinsey Global Institute and McKinsey Social Sector Office have conducted a study of changes in income dispersion and their causes from 1991 to 2005, the height of the economic cycle. The study analyzed a broader, deeper data set than previous research in the area, making it the first attempt to estimate the contribution to rising dispersion of fundamental changes in the US economy’s mix of industries and occupations. Its findings show that redeveloping America’s human capital should be the focus of labor market policy coming out of the recession. </p>
<p>Understanding the patchwork of the United States’ labor market is key to understanding what has happened to income growth. Labor income largely accounts for 75 to 85 percent of household pretax income across the income distribution, and the analysis shows that differential rates of growth in labor incomes were the most significant sources of the differential rates of household income growth across the income distribution. For this reason, the research takes as its starting point the labor market rather than household incomes as most previous studies have done, resulting in a more detailed picture than was previously available. </p>
<p>The report examines eight clusters of industry/occupation pairs or jobs in which employees experienced similar income levels, income growth, and employment growth over the period. The analysis reveals that 71 percent of  US workers are in jobs for which there has been a decrease in demand from employers, an increase in supply of eligible workers, or both.  </p>
<p>The research also analyzes nine possible drivers of changes in labor income. Incomes and employment for the top-earning 22 percent of workers grew fast, mostly because new technologies and new opportunities in global markets ramped up demand for advanced skills. </p>
<p>Education has played a critical role in giving workers access to higher-earning job clusters. Moreover, an undersupply of workers with the skills to fill the kinds of jobs fostered by new technologies in more complex organizations means that people with those skills have been able to win income premiums. Having the appropriate education or training is the ticket to higher-paid work. </p>
<p>The analysis showed that migration and deunionization depressed levels of compensation for labor in repetitive manual jobs and administrative support in the four lowest-earning clusters across all industries. </p>
<p>At a deeper structural level, global economic integration and technological advances have combined to produce permanent changes in the skill levels required to flourish in the US labor market, the research concludes. Unless the mass of America’s human capital can be developed fast, the nation risks another period in which growth resumes but income dispersion persists, with Americans in the bottom and middle-earning income clusters never really benefiting from the recovery.</p>
<p>While there is no single cause or “silver bullet” remedy for rising income dispersion, upgrading the productivity, skills, and rewards in the service sector is the key challenge.</p>]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Part III: The emerging global labor market: How supply and demand for offshore talent meet</title>
      <description />
      <link>http://www.mckinsey.com/en/insights/employment_and_growth/the_emerging_global_labor_market_supply_and_demand</link>
      <guid>http://www.mckinsey.com/en/insights/employment_and_growth/the_emerging_global_labor_market_supply_and_demand</guid>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Apr 2013 23:00:45 GMT</pubDate>
      <id>9b8b23ea-bfb1-4a1e-a27f-a51d8fd98adf</id>
      <category>Employment and growth</category>
      <dc:creator><![CDATA[Diana Farrell, Martha Laboissiére, Robert Pascal, Charles de Segundo, Jaeson Rosenfeld, Sascha Stürze, Fusayo Umezawa]]></dc:creator>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Global resourcing may raise wages in some occupations in the lowest cost supply countries, but the practice will not significantly impact wages or employment in developed countries. Of all the occupations, engineering has the lowest supply of suitable talent relative to demand.</p>
<p>At an aggregate level, the potential supply of suitable talent from the low-wage countries we studied exceeds the likely demand for it by two-fold. </p>
<p>In practice, companies hiring offshore tend to follow each other to locations that have a track record in providing offshore talent. The resulting agglomeration of companies in popular locations has some positive effects, such as accelerating improvements in infrastructure, communications and the business environment. But the pattern also leads to local wage inflation and high levels of attrition. MGI found that wages for engineers and generalists could double in the lowest wage countries, but will remain below 30 percent of the level of wages for engineers in the United States, or the current level of wages for these two occupations in Mexico and Brazil. In contrast, the effects of offshoring on employment and wages in developed countries will be negligible. </p>
<p>Companies can find more suitable locations offshore if they rationally analyze the factors that are most important to them, including their home market, their first language, what activity they want to outsource, the scale on which they want to offshore, and whether they want to outsource or set up a captive operation. That means different companies will assign different costs and benefits to the same location. </p>]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Part I: The emerging global labor market: The demand for offshore talent in services</title>
      <description />
      <link>http://www.mckinsey.com/en/insights/employment_and_growth/the_emerging_global_labor_market_demand_for_offshore_talent</link>
      <guid>http://www.mckinsey.com/en/insights/employment_and_growth/the_emerging_global_labor_market_demand_for_offshore_talent</guid>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Apr 2013 23:00:45 GMT</pubDate>
      <id>f3a22a07-6f0b-47b5-9736-b1f24631c1c3</id>
      <category>Employment and growth</category>
      <dc:creator><![CDATA[Diana Farrell, Martha Laboissiére, Robert Pascal, Jaeson Rosenfeld, Charles de Segundo, Sascha Stürze ]]></dc:creator>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Although 11 percent of the world's 1.46 billion service jobs can be theoretically performed remotely, the number of those jobs offshored by 2008 will remain modest. An estimated 1.1 percent of total demand for labor in services will go offshore due mainly to internal company barriers.</p>
<p></p>
<p>Only a small fraction of employment that could potentially go offshore will ever do so. </p>
<p>Eleven percent (161 million jobs) of the 1.46 billion service jobs worldwide could be performed remotely. As a rule, the more customer facing functions a sector has, the lower its potential to resource those functions remotely. Consequently, this potential varies depending on the industry. The lowest potential is in retail, for example, where 3 percent of employment may be globally resourced. Packaged software, however, could see 49 percent of its services work done remotely. </p>
<p>We estimate that total offshore employment amounted to about 1.7 million jobs in 2003. In 2008, total offshore employment will reach an estimated 1.1 percent of total demand for labor in services from developed countries, equivalent to 4.1 million employees. </p>
<p>Some occupations are also more amenable to remote employment than others. Engineering and finance and accounting occupations are the most amenable (52 percent and 31 percent, respectively), while generalist and support staff occupations are the least (9 percent and 3 percent, respectively) because of the close interactions they entail with customers or colleagues. However, because every industry employs many generalists and support staff, these occupations have the highest number of jobs that could be filled by remote talent — a combined total of 26 million positions. </p>
<p>The gap between the current and potential levels of adoption is mainly explained by internal company barriers rather than regulatory deterrents. Most notably operational issues, management attitudes to offshoring, and structural issues keeping companies from outsourcing services. </p>
<p>Offshore employment will grow gradually, making no sudden impact on labor markets overall in developed countries. In fact, its growth will have less impact on patterns of employment than the decline in manufacturing employment developed countries have already experienced. </p>]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
