<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="\rss\stylesheet.xsl"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:itunes="http://www.itunes.com/dtds/podcast-1.0.dtd" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:georss="http://www.georss.org/georss" xmlns:fh="http://purl.org/syndication/history/1.0">
  <channel>
    <title>McKinsey Insights &amp; Publications</title>
    <link>http://branch2.mckinsey.com/en/insights</link>
    <description>McKinsey Insights &amp; Publications RSS Feeds</description>
    <language>en</language>
    <managingEditor>test@mckinsey.com (DotCom Team)</managingEditor>
    <webMaster>web@mckinsey.com (DotCom Team)</webMaster>
    <pubDate>Fri, 20 Sep 2013 20:03:09 GMT</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 24 Sep 2013 06:41:09 GMT</lastBuildDate>
    <category domain="Syndic8">Business</category>
    <ttl>5</ttl>
    <rating>TO_BE_UPDATED</rating>
    <textInput>TO_BE_UPDATED</textInput>
    <cloud>TO_BE_UPDATED</cloud>
    <skipHours>
      <hour>1</hour>
      <hour>23</hour>
    </skipHours>
    <skipDays>
      <day>Saturday</day>
      <day>Sunday</day>
    </skipDays>
    <image>
      <url>http://branch2.mckinsey.com/~/media/McKinsey/dotcom/Global/logo_mckinsey-quarterly.ashx</url>
      <title>McKinsey Insights &amp; Publications</title>
    </image>
    <fh:incremental>false</fh:incremental>
    <atom:link rel="hub" href="http://pubsubhubbub.appspot.com" />
    <atom:link rel="self" href="http://67.214.133.121/test/rss_v32.xml" />
    <copyright>Copyright (c) McKinsey &amp; Company. All rights reserved. Reprinted by permission.</copyright>
    <generator>Sitecore CMS: http://www.sitecore.net. Sitecore RSS module: McKinsey.RSS, Version=1.3.2.21906, Culture=neutral, PublicKeyToken=null</generator>
    <item>
      <title>Managing when vendor and supplier risk becomes your own</title>
      <description>Financial institutions are being held accountable for the actions of their suppliers. A new approach can help to identify and manage sources of third-party risk.</description>
      <link>http://branch2.mckinsey.com/en/insights/risk_management/managing_when_vendor_and_supplier_risk_becomes_your_own</link>
      <guid>http://branch2.mckinsey.com/en/insights/risk_management/managing_when_vendor_and_supplier_risk_becomes_your_own</guid>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Aug 2013 00:03:48 GMT</pubDate>
      <ID>016bd1b3-a3dc-4de3-b8ab-b4bd8f3053f0</ID>
      <category>Risk Management</category>
      <dc:creator></dc:creator>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>
<strong>The rising tide</strong> of regulatory scrutiny stemming from the global financial crisis has now reached beyond banks, to the companies that supply them. Under the broad notion that activities can be outsourced, but responsibility can’t, the Consumer Financial Protection Bureau (CFPB) and other regulators are holding financial institutions responsible not only for their own actions but also for those of their vendors and suppliers. In the past year, for example, American Express, Capital One, and Discover Bank have paid a total of more than $530 million to settle complaints of deceptive selling and predatory behavior by their third-party suppliers.</p>
<p>
This new regulatory thrust poses a big challenge for financial institutions because some of them have a limited perspective on their suppliers’ interactions with customers. The largest banks and credit-card companies can have close to 50,000 suppliers. They are quite careful about some of these relationships and often have teams to manage large and midsize suppliers. Of course, many vendors provide paper, computers, and other innocuous goods and services. But a significant number of vendor relationships are not closely managed, and some carry hidden risks. A company that molds and prints credit cards, for example, is entrusted with customer data, and that poses any number of privacy and security risks.</p>
<p>
At many institutions, vendor-management programs have focused predominantly on risks to the bank and the financial system—specifically, on business continuity, financial strength, and credit risk. With the scope of regulatory oversight broadening to include the consumer, many firms are underprepared. But since financial institutions must bear the responsibility for their suppliers’ misdeeds, they must improve the way they manage these relationships.</p>
<p>
In response to the changes, financial firms are looking for new solutions to identify and manage third-party risk. A number of leading banks and credit-card companies are developing and embracing best practices. Our research and experience have helped us develop a comprehensive approach to managing third-party risk. It consists of six essential steps, some of which can be executed in parallel.</p>
<h3>1. A comprehensive inventory of third parties</h3>
<p>
Regulators now expect institutions to know their third parties, how each of them interacts with consumers, and what activities it performs. Many firms do not have this information readily available. Supplier databases can be incomplete, and some of the most sensitive risks can reside in relationships that are not found in them. Cobranded partnerships, joint ventures, sponsorships, and similar relationships can account for up to 80 percent of the spending that some business units assign to suppliers. But these relationships are often managed in ways that emphasize commercial goals, with only a secondary focus on risk. What’s more, in some firms individual business units have different ways of tracking their suppliers, making it difficult to compare and collate them across an entire organization.</p>
<p>
In our experience, an effective database of third parties includes all of them—that is, any noncustomer entity with which a financial institution has a business relationship. An enterprise-wide survey is a good way to get started.</p>
<h3>2. A comprehensive catalog of third-party risks</h3>
<p>
To monitor consumer risk successfully, firms must develop a comprehensive catalog of these risks, also known as breakpoints, which form the basis for scorecards, audit routines, and other monitoring activities. Consider one breakpoint for a third-party call center: if there is a risk that agents will misrepresent product information to customers, a bank may investigate this specific problem by having calls monitored and may request regular reports on their quality and on customer-escalation metrics (exhibit). Identifying the relevant breakpoints for each category of suppliers and determining the relative weight and importance of every breakpoint can be challenging. Building a master register of breakpoints and their associated risk weights for all of these categories can help. Although broadly relevant to most firms, the master register can be adapted to the particular circumstances of an individual organization and its unique third-party relationships. This process is essential, as it helps the firm identify the true drivers of its risks and guides its mitigation program.</p>
[[exhibit 1]]
<h3>3. A risk-based segmentation</h3>
<p>
Once a firm has a complete inventory of third-party suppliers and the risks they pose to customers, it can segment its suppliers by risk level. Even a simple system of high-, medium-, and low-risk categories can be useful. We have observed that most leading institutions have 200 to 300 high-risk relationships at a time, irrespective of the total number of third parties with which they contract. An effective segmentation can help a firm determine how to utilize its resources strategically. It may, for example, conduct additional due diligence on high-risk relationships and automate regular reviews of low-risk suppliers.</p>
<p>
In our experience, firms typically use either of two approaches to segment third-party suppliers. Companies that follow the score-based approach conduct due diligence across all dimensions and use the results to develop a composite risk score. Although very thorough, this approach can be onerous and resource intensive for many organizations. Using the rules-based approach, a firm identifies specific rules or criteria for each segment and thereby streamlines the process of assigning suppliers to risk categories. In fact, this approach is about 40 to 60 percent faster than the score-based one. Given the importance of an approach to segmentation, leading institutions tend to invest heavily in designing it. Typically, they appoint a core team of risk experts to lead the design, the fine-tuning, and the implementation.</p>
<h3>4. A rules-based due-diligence test</h3>
<p>
Today, firms are expected to expand their due-diligence efforts beyond the traditional assessments for supplier, operational, and IT-security risks. Regulators are increasingly sensitive to strategic and reputational risks that third parties can create for customers. Traditional approaches align specific due-diligence activities with the risk category identified by the risk-based segmentation; a supplier in the high-risk category is subject to all due-diligence investigations. Like the score-based segmentation approach, this one can be overly onerous and resource intensive. Here too the rules-based approach can be a better answer because it triggers an appropriate set of due-diligence activities for the risks identified. For example, even if a third party is deemed to pose a high risk, an information-security or data-privacy screening is unnecessary if the supplier does not hold information that personally identifies customers. We estimate that the rules-based approach can cut employee time by close to 40 percent.   </p>
<h3>5. A disciplined governance and escalation process</h3>
<p>
Organizational alignment is particularly important when decision-making rights are spread across a range of businesses and functions, such as procurement, compliance, and operational-risk management. By proactively establishing governance structures and processes to address misalignments, institutions can resolve challenges quickly.</p>
<p>
Governance can be centralized or decentralized; both models (and some hybrids) can be successful. In the centralized model, most major risk decisions reside within a single group, such as procurement or shared services. While the centralized model identifies a clear and accountable “owner,” it can sometimes lead to tension between the business unit that has a working relationship with a third party and the centralized body accountable for risk assessments.</p>
<p>
In the decentralized model, the business unit that owns the relationship also manages the risk. This arrangement can sometimes result in a duplication of resources: several business units may, for example, assess a major third-party supplier for similar contracts. In some cases, the application and alignment of risk standards can be inconsistent in a decentralized model: the groups managing, say, procurement and operational risk could have different perspectives. A hybrid approach, carefully tailored to the organizational context, can help mitigate challenges associated with the two models as long as risk ownership is clear.</p>
<p>
An escalation framework is critical to resolve issues—such as requests for exceptions and the resolution of third-party breaches—that exceed the decision-making limits set out in the governance structure. While most organizations have an operational-risk management group, its governance model and mandate might not be sufficient to address the additional volume of third-party issues. In our experience, leading financial institutions often choose to assign new responsibilities to standing committees rather than create new ones to support third-party escalations. Each organization must find an appropriate approach given its appetite for risk and its culture.</p>
<h3>6. An integrated management-reporting and workflow process and tools</h3>
<p>
Clear, actionable management reports and well-designed workflow systems are essential for accountability across the business units, compliance, and audit. To work well, these tools must track and monitor the relevant data. More important, they must aid the workflow within and across business units and give managers a clear picture of real-time risk, with actionable recommendations. In our experience, most organizations currently have tools that address one or two of these functional needs, but to our knowledge none has a single tool that performs all three.</p>
<p>
Building a new third-party risk application from scratch is a big undertaking; so too is enhancing a current risk tool to perform new functions. Some firms have turned to off-the-shelf workflow- and risk-management tools that can easily be customized to an organization’s specific needs.</p>
<div class="articleBreak"></div>
<p>
Risks from vendors and suppliers pose a significant challenge to financial institutions. A systematic approach to managing those risks can lower costs and help banks present a coherent approach to all key stakeholders, including regulators.</p>
<p>For more on this research, download the full report, <em><a href="~/media/C7D004EEEE304157B6EEE717B1B3638B.ashx" data-analytics="Managing third party risk in a changing regulatory environment>download>pdf>body">Managing third-party risk in a changing regulatory environment</a></em> (PDF–625KB).</p>
<div class="about-authors">
<h6>About the authors</h6>
<p>
<strong>Hamid Samandari</strong> is a director in McKinsey’s New York office, where <strong>Emily Yueh</strong> is a consultant; <strong>John Walsh</strong> is a senior expert in the Washington, DC, office.</p>
<p>
The authors would like to thank Dmitry Krivin for his contribution to the development of this article.</p>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Three snapshots from China’s next chapter</title>
      <description>A new middle class. An urban transformation. An e-tailing revolution. This slideshow details the key trends that will define a new China.</description>
      <link>http://branch2.mckinsey.com/en/insights/economic_studies/three_snapshots_from_chinas_next_chapter</link>
      <guid>http://branch2.mckinsey.com/en/insights/economic_studies/three_snapshots_from_chinas_next_chapter</guid>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Jul 2013 04:23:10 GMT</pubDate>
      <ID>2ea004fa-89a4-4621-9d9e-81cf94486c06</ID>
      <category>Economic Studies</category>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><strong>To fully grasp</strong> China’s future direction, it is essential to understand its new middle class. A huge wave of increasingly affluent consumers will constitute China’s urban majority in less than a decade. The rapid emergence of this prosperous, digitally savvy, individualistic, and sophisticated class of consumers is creating opportunities and challenges for the companies that serve them. This slideshow looks at this consumer and urbanization phenomenon by the numbers. To understand, for example, how Singles Day—China’s alternative to Valentine’s Day—dwarfs Cyber Monday in the United States in online sales revenue, look inside.</p>
[[Interactive slideshow]]]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Long-haul China</title>
      <description>This photo-essay offers a passenger-seat view of China’s long-haul trucking industry.</description>
      <link>http://branch2.mckinsey.com/en/insights/travel_transportation/long-haul_china</link>
      <guid>http://branch2.mckinsey.com/en/insights/travel_transportation/long-haul_china</guid>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Jul 2013 00:39:20 GMT</pubDate>
      <ID>135b1e52-f6e1-4e75-a565-a6de49e03bdb</ID>
      <category>Travel &amp; Transportation</category>
      <dc:creator><![CDATA[Rachel Katz]]></dc:creator>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><strong>Long-distance trucking</strong>  is the backbone of China’s economy, yet the industry is fragmented and inefficient—particularly in the country’s interior. These photos capture the spirit of this disorganized but vibrant sector, whose continued modernization is critical to China’s economic development.</p>
[[Interactive slideshow]]<br />
<div class="about-authors">
<h6>About the author</h6>
<p><strong>Rachel Katz</strong> is a consultant in McKinsey’s San Francisco office. As a Fulbright Scholar during 2011, she conducted research on China’s trucking sector. Highlights of her work, now available at <a href="http://longhaulchina.com/" target="_blank">longhaulchina.com</a>, will soon be published as a book.</p>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Africa at work: Job creation and inclusive growth</title>
      <description />
      <link>http://branch2.mckinsey.com/en/insights/africa/a_test</link>
      <guid>http://branch2.mckinsey.com/en/insights/africa/a_test</guid>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Jul 2013 02:25:22 GMT</pubDate>
      <ID>43d94db0-63eb-43f1-bae4-eb007f2ddf52</ID>
      <category>Africa</category>
      <dc:creator><![CDATA[David Fine, Arend van Wamelen, Susan Lund, Armando Cabral, Mourad Taoufiki, Norbert Dörr, Acha Leke, Charles Roxburgh, Jörg Schubert and Paul Cook]]></dc:creator>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Africa is the world’s second-fastest-growing region. Poverty is falling, and around 90 million of its households have joined the world’s consuming classes—an increase of 31 million in just over a decade. But a new McKinsey Global Institute report, <em>Africa at work: Job creation and inclusive growth</em>, shows that the continent must create wage-paying jobs more quickly to sustain these successes and ensure that growth benefits the majority of its people. </p>
<p>Despite the creation of 37 million new and stable wage-paying jobs over the past decade, only 28 percent of Africa’s labor force holds such positions. Instead, some 63 percent of the total labor force engages in some form of self-employment or “vulnerable” employment, such as subsistence farming or urban street hawking. If the trends of the past decade continue, Africa will create 54 million new, stable wage-paying jobs over the next ten years—but this will not be enough to absorb the 122 million new entrants into the labor force expected over the same period. However, by implementing a five-part strategy to accelerate the pace of job creation, we estimate that Africa could add as many as 72 million new wage-paying jobs over the next decade, raising the wage-earning share of the labor force to 36 percent. </p>
<p class="mck_h6">Exhibit</p>
<p class="mck_h6"><img width="510" height="472" alt="Africa at work: Job creation and inclusive growth - Job creation acceleration" src="~/media/AFE1ED372EA04D4F9CB639A9F1B27306.ashx" /></p>
<p><span class="mck_h3_sm">1. Identify one or more labor-intensive subsectors in which an African country has a global competitive advantage or could fill strong domestic demand.</span> Lesotho, for example, capitalized on the African Growth and Opportunity Act (2000), granting some African exports duty-free access to US markets. A landlocked nation surrounded entirely by South Africa, Lesotho developed industrial zones for the apparel industry and built rail links between them, offered incentives to foreign investors, and simplified the regulation of the sector. Today, Lesotho’s apparel exports to the United States are almost 100 times as large as South Africa’s on a per capita basis, and the sector is the single largest creator of jobs, employing about 40,000 people in 2008 in a country of just two million. </p>
<p><span class="mck_h3_sm">2. Improve access to finance in target sectors. Cape Verde, for instance, encouraged foreign direct investment to ease financial constraints on its tourism sector.</span> To capitalize on the country’s beautiful beaches, it offered investors a five-year tax holiday, exemption from import duties, and unrestricted expatriation of profits. Revenues generated by foreign tourism increased from $23 million in 1999 to $542 million in 2008, and the sector now employs 21 percent of Cape Verde’s workforce. </p>
<p><span class="mck_h3_sm">3. Build a suitable infrastructure. Countries that remove infrastructure constraints in target subsectors, particularly in export-oriented industries, can reap sizable benefits.</span> Mali’s exports of mangoes to the European Union, for example, grew sixfold between 2003 and 2008 after a concerted public–private program helped the country build integrated road, rail, and other infrastructure necessary to access export markets. These moves cut the transit time for shipments in half. </p>
<p><span class="mck_h3_sm">4. Cut unnecessary regulations. Removing needless red tape in certain sectors is also important.</span> In Rwanda, for instance, streamlining the procedures needed to open a business dramatically increased the number of new companies, from only 700 a year before the reform to 3,000 a year today. </p>
<p><span class="mck_h3_sm">5. Develop skills in target sectors. Around 40 percent of African workers now have at least some secondary education, and that share will rise to 48 percent by 2020.</span> Few employers in our survey of businesses in Egypt, Kenya, Nigeria, Senegal, and South Africa reported that a lack of skilled workers was a top barrier to growth. Still, Africa’s educational attainment lags behind that of other regions, and the continent would undoubtedly benefit from continued improvement. Two things are of particular importance: work readiness among school graduates and, in some countries, specific vocational skills. </p>]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Can Africa continue to grow?Upated</title>
      <description>A panel of regional business leaders discusses its prospects.</description>
      <link>http://branch2.mckinsey.com/en/insights/africa/copy_of_can_africa_continue_to_grow</link>
      <guid>http://branch2.mckinsey.com/en/insights/africa/copy_of_can_africa_continue_to_grow</guid>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Jul 2013 02:25:21 GMT</pubDate>
      <ID>5525cbd6-93af-45bf-8f79-d9e6918640b1</ID>
      <category>Africa</category>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><strong>Gross corruption,</strong> constant wars, and irrational economics long made Africa a poor, troubled continent where natural-resource companies were almost the only multinationals that dared or cared to do business. But in the 1990s, the picture improved. The wars started subsiding. Many governments balanced their budgets and created a better, safer environment for companies, both foreign and domestic. And the African consumer began to stir. Now 80 million households earn at least the equivalent of $5,000 annually, the point where discretionary spending commences—an increase of 80 percent in eight years. Meanwhile, the continent’s GDP has been rising steadily, at around 5 percent a year, for the past decade, reaching $1.6 trillion in 2008. Last year, Africa was one of just two regions (the other was Asia) where GDP rose. </p>
<p>Is all this good news sustainable? At the 2010 Fortune Global Forum, in Cape Town, South Africa, McKinsey Publishing’s Rik Kirkland spoke with Absa’s Maria Ramos, Coca-Cola’s Bill Egbe, and McKinsey’s Norbert Dörr to find the answer.</p>
<!--roadblock-->
<p>Watch the video, or <a href="~/media/50D1DB095F594BAD8EEACEE13B4CC99E.ashx">download a PDF</a> of the transcript.</p>
<figure>
      <video width="400" height="300" controls="">
        <source src="http://brightcove.vo.llnwd.net/e1/uds/pd/1971571337001/1971571337001_2522840653001_Chinatech-full.mp4" />
			  </video>
    </figure>]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A yen for global growth: The Japanese experience in cross-border M&amp;A</title>
      <description>Japanese companies have embarked on an increasing number of international acquisitions in recent years. Can they learn from past failures and create value from cross-border deals?</description>
      <link>http://branch2.mckinsey.com/en/insights/asia-pacific/copy_of_a_yen_for_global_growth_the_japanese_experience_in_cross-border_m_and_38a</link>
      <guid>http://branch2.mckinsey.com/en/insights/asia-pacific/copy_of_a_yen_for_global_growth_the_japanese_experience_in_cross-border_m_and_38a</guid>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Jul 2013 02:23:24 GMT</pubDate>
      <ID>ca7d036f-648f-4526-ae8b-1981c6780971</ID>
      <category>Asia-Pacific</category>
      <dc:creator><![CDATA[Keiko Honda,  Keith Lostaglio, and Genki Oka]]></dc:creator>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><strong>An appreciating yen</strong> and a stagnant domestic market make global expansion a logical move for Japanese companies with bold growth aspirations. Indeed, Japanese companies are making international forays, albeit quietly: it is a little-reported fact that the number of outbound M&A deals in Japan has been on an upward trajectory in recent years. If the trend continues, Japanese cross-border M&A activity will soon surpass its 1990 peak. </p><p>
Deal levels would be even higher if Japanese companies were not haunted by past M&A failures. Pitfalls abound along the road to international M&A, and although some of them are now well-known and thus studiously circumvented, others—particularly those having to do with fundamental differences in business and management culture—seem almost impossible for Japanese companies to avoid. Retaining foreign talent presents a particular challenge. </p><p>
To gain insights into how Japanese companies should manage international acquisitions, we interviewed non-Japanese executives whose companies have been acquired by Japanese companies in large cross-border M&A deals within the past decade. We also conducted in-depth outside-in analyses on a handful of deals in which Japanese companies—such as Hitachi Construction Machinery, Suzuki Motors, Takeda Pharmaceuticals, and Toshiba—were able to boost international sales through cross-border M&A.<a class='link-footnote' rel='#footnote1' href='#' onclick='return false;'><sup>1</sup></a> <span id='footnote1' class='tooltip' style='display:none;'><span class='footnote-content'><span class='footnote-number'>1.</span><span class='footnote-text'>
We focused on deals in which the acquirer sought partial integration (neither full autonomy for the subsidiary nor a complete merger) since this is a common model applied by Japanese companies, many of which do not have the confidence to fully integrate an overseas entity.
</span><span class='clear'></span> </span><span class='footnote-bottom'></span></span></p><p>
Our findings indicate that there is no silver-bullet approach to capturing the greatest value from an international acquisition. Companies have had success using a variety of approaches, each tailored to the acquirer’s strategic intentions, its unique characteristics, and the dynamics of the industry. Although a company’s particular industry, context, and objectives should dictate the specific tactics it uses, the approaches we studied can give acquirers a starting point to consider—whether that starting point entails focusing on one such tactic or emulating all of them. </p><!--roadblock--><h3>Perspectives of the acquired</h3><p>
Most Japanese executives who have played the global M&A game are familiar with the most common obstacles: disagreement between the acquirer and the acquired over how much value ought to be captured immediately after the deal closes or the positioning of the new subsidiary within the parent company, assumptions by Japanese leaders that what works for their company must also work elsewhere, inattention to the acquired company’s employees, and a lack of postacquisition-management leadership and skills. </p><p>
What may be less familiar—and even surprising—to them are the observations of executives at US and European companies that have been acquired by Japanese companies. Interviews with executives from six such companies of various sizes (from $200 million to $1 billion in value) indicate a number of stumbling blocks. The first four, in particular, are detrimental to talent retention; they are the main reasons that non-Japanese executives do not stay long at such companies. </p><p><strong>A hands-off approach.</strong> Although Japanese executives may think the acquired company would prefer to be left alone—and although the parent company’s restraint may at first appear admirable and wise—many foreign executives come to feel that this is the wrong approach. One major benefit of being acquired, they say, should be that the subsidiary can fully leverage the capabilities of its parent company. Foreign executives want the acquirer to engage with its new subsidiary and jointly tackle issues as they arise. </p><p><strong>An ambiguous power structure.</strong> Non-Japanese executives have difficulty determining where the true power lies within a Japanese organization. For example, the deal executive in an M&A situation could have a lofty title (such as senior managing director). The target company might therefore focus on building a relationship with this person, continue to interact with him after the acquisition, and belatedly discover that he actually has no direct reports and no influence over day- to-day business. In one case, the deal executive was kept on staff only because he was a favorite of the former CEO. </p><p><strong>The tyranny of the middle.</strong> Our interviewees said that middle managers at the parent company can be destructive forces: they derive power from their proximity to the Japanese CEO and try to control information. A common example: if the acquired company requests additional capital investment for growth, middle managers may choose not to raise this request to the CEO. When the leaders of the acquired company follow up with the CEO a few months later, they learn that the CEO was never informed of the request. Incidents such as this can cause middle management to lose the respect of line leaders at the acquired company. </p><p><strong>The glass ceiling for foreigners.</strong> Japanese companies often have an insular culture. The general assumption is that a foreigner can rise only so high in the organization. Foreign executives thus consider leaving not because of unsatisfactory compensation but because they feel their careers are unfairly capped. </p><p><strong>Detail orientation.</strong> American and European executives have difficulty understanding Japanese attention to detail. A Japanese company’s due-diligence checklist, for example, is typically three times longer than that of an acquisition-savvy Western company, in part due to Japanese companies’ risk aversion. In a postacquisition setting, a Japanese company would want to understand, for instance, the discrepancy between a sales forecast and actual sales. It could very well decide to investigate assumptions made a year ago, whereas a Western company would care only about the actual sales figure and how to improve it. </p><p><strong>Poor postacquisition planning.</strong> Attention to detail notwithstanding, Japanese companies tend to be laissez-faire about what happens immediately after a deal closes. They do not see value in creating a concrete architecture in the interim to ensure a successful transition. Foreign executives often lament that transition governance and interim processes for decision making, resource allocation, and escalation of business-critical issues are insufficiently discussed. </p><p><strong>Sudden metamorphosis from friendly partner to distant boss.</strong> Our interviewees reported several experiences in which the initial integration phase was friendly and collaborative, then abruptly morphed into an intense discussion about steep cost reduction. Although this happens in non-Japanese settings as well, it is particularly pronounced in Japanese M&A because Japanese buyers can be extremely polite—to a point that foreigners sometimes find misleading. In one case, even though the acquirer had already decided to eliminate the target company’s research department, executives still made multiple visits to the target’s research sites to keep up appearances. When employees at the target company learned that the decision was made months ago, their trust in the parent company crumbled. </p><h3>Four approaches</h3><p>
To find out how Japanese companies have addressed one or more of these pitfalls, we examined the approach of the very small number of companies—14, to be exact—that completed at least five acquisitions during the past decade and generate more than half their revenues from overseas markets. In each of the deals we examined, the acquirer used a different postacquisition approach depending on the focus of the change program (exhibit). The approaches are not mutually exclusive. A company can emulate elements from all of them, depending on its particular industry, context, and objectives. </p> [[exhibit 1]]<h3 class="sm black">Establishing mentorship or exchange programs to build leadership talent</h3><p>For acquirers whose main objectives include leadership development, one tactic involves pairing high-potential managers from the acquired company with an executive from the parent company as a coach and mentor. This helps build alignment between the acquirer and the acquired. The frequent and direct communication between leaders at both entities—without having to go through middle management—also allows for tighter coordination. </p><p>
When in 2002 Japanese automaker Suzuki Motor acquired a majority stake of Indian company Maruti Udyog, Suzuki engineered change at the top. It appointed a Suzuki executive as president and CEO of Maruti and took over 6 of the 11 board seats. But it also promoted four high-potential Maruti leaders—in sales, marketing, R&D, and administration—to corporate-officer roles and assigned each a functional executive from Suzuki as a mentor. The pairs were held jointly accountable for formulating new strategies. If postacquisition performance is any indication, the mentorship program has worked: Maruti’s sales have quadrupled, and profits are up 17 times from 2002 levels. </p><p>
Another promising tactic is two-way dispatch of executives (from acquirer to target and vice versa). When Takeda acquired US pharmaceutical company Millennium in 2008, it engineered an exchange of personnel to facilitate mutual understanding of corporate cultures. It invited Millennium’s CEO to join Takeda’s management team. Researchers from both companies traveled between Japan and the United States to strengthen their research capabilities. In 2011, Takeda transferred several Millennium researchers to its new research center in Japan. And Takeda recently named Millennium’s head of strategy—a Westerner—as head of business development for Takeda, showing the company’s openness to high-potential leaders from its subsidiary. Thanks to Millennium, which has been put in charge of all oncology efforts at Takeda, the company is now preparing to begin trials of three or four cancer-drug candidates per year—a significant increase from historical levels. </p><p>
These talent-development programs signal to foreign executives that the parent company is willing to invest in their professional advancement, giving them confidence that they can break through the perceived glass ceiling. </p><h3 class="sm black">Creating a special coordination unit at the division level</h3><p>
Another model entails the creation of a dedicated coordination office or unit to manage the integration. Depending on the company’s objective, the unit can be large or small. A large coordination office may make sense if there is a strong appetite for capturing value from cost synergies (by streamlining operations) and revenue synergies (by launching new initiatives that leverage both companies’ strengths). If the goal is intervention in one or two functions, a smaller, SWAT-type team may be more apt. In either case, the model helps avoid a leadership gap in postacquisition management. With a dedicated team, there is no question as to who is leading the integration effort. Toshiba acquired US-based Westinghouse Electric in 2006 to raise Toshiba’s global presence in nuclear generation. Toshiba sought to influence Westinghouse while also allowing it a degree of autonomy—which was critical, since the two companies had different types of nuclear technology. Toshiba set up two coordination offices: one within Westinghouse, whose members were drawn from Toshiba and its strategic partners Shaw Group and IHI (both of which had minority stakes in Westinghouse), and another within Toshiba. The offices worked together on strategy development and implementation. Three years later, Toshiba had record orders, including its first US orders for two large-scale projects. </p><p>
Hitachi Construction Machinery took a slightly different tack when it acquired a majority stake in Indian construction-equipment manufacturer Telcon, a joint venture with Tata Motors, in 2010. With the goal of increasing the quality of Telcon’s products, Hitachi dispatched seven Hitachi experts to the Telcon functions that needed fundamental change, such as quality assurance and product design. This specialist team, which was expanded in 2010, had full authority to direct Telcon’s performance-improvement efforts and created plans to optimize manufacturing processes, support services, and employee training. By creating a dedicated team, a company can begin to build internal skills that will prove useful in subsequent acquisitions. In the best cases, the individuals chosen for the coordination office are high-potential executives with excellent communication skills and business savvy. </p><h3 class="sm black">Developing local trainers as change agents</h3><p>In the third model, the front line is the focus of change. Employees from the foreign company are brought to Japan for “train the trainer” sessions that are more than a means of technology transfer— they also become opportunities to promote Japanese corporate values and management philosophy. These sessions help create a sense of belonging among the acquired employees that can, in turn, lead to greater motivation and higher employee-retention rates. </p><p>
When a Japanese manufacturer acquired a Southeast Asian company in 2006, it became the industry’s second-largest player. The acquirer was deliberate in how it chose to transfer its technology to its new subsidiary: it abandoned its traditional system of sending senior Japanese engineers to overseas subsidiaries to serve as trainers. Instead, select employees from the acquired company came to Japan for training, then returned to their home countries to train local employees. Approximately 700 non-Japanese employees have now undergone training in Japan; 60 of them have gone on to further study and been designated expert trainers. Although the Japanese corporation suffered along with the rest of the industry during the economic crisis, the combined company was recently able to beat the market leader for a high-profile contract—an achievement in which the new subsidiary played a critical role. </p><p>
By choosing not to dispatch its own employees but rather to bring in employees from the acquired company, Japanese companies can create room for “translation”: the change agents at the new subsidiary come to understand the corporate strategy and the vision for the integrated entity, and they develop a greater understanding of and appreciation for the technical advantages that each company offers. These change agents become effective champions of Japanese techniques and practices. </p><h3 class="sm black">Implementing company-wide culture-infusion programs</h3><p>
To infuse Japanese business culture into an acquired company, acquirers can launch initiatives that differ completely from those preceding them and ensure frequent communication on all fronts (for example, through employee newsletters or town halls). The most effective initiatives appear to be informal mechanisms that model Japanese norms while also bridging the divide between management and the front line. Company-wide programs, implemented correctly, can help motivate and retain target-company employees.</p><p>Suzuki, for instance, gave all Maruti employees sufficient exposure to Suzuki’s unique way of doing things. It promoted an open corporate culture, which was foreign and jarring in the Indian context. Top management and employees eat in the same cafeteria. Everyone, from the CEO to the factory worker, wears the same uniform to work. All employees—again, including the CEO—participate in morning exercise routines. (Although several Japanese companies hold dear the ritual of morning exercises, no others, to our knowledge, have introduced it at a non-Japanese subsidiary.)</p><div class="articleBreak"></div><p>These case examples should give Japanese executives the confidence to venture beyond Japan’s borders. Our findings indicate that there are a variety of promising approaches to postacquisition management and that leaders of Japanese companies must develop their own winning approach—sometimes through trial and error and constant refinement. Their first step should be to compile a list of acquisition targets that make sense given their strategic intentions. They should then come up with guiding principles and a blueprint for a postacquisition-management approach, tailored to their company’s strengths and the key value drivers of the industry. Japanese companies can—and indeed, if they want to grow, must—go global.<br /></p><div class="about-authors"><h3 class="sm black">About the authors</h3><p><b>Keiko Honda</b> is a director in McKinsey’s Tokyo office, where <b>Keith Lostaglio</b> and <b>Genki Oka</b> are partners.</p></div>]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A CEO’s guide to innovation in China in master</title>
      <description>Dynamic domestic players and focused multinationals are helping China churn out a growing number of innovative products and services. Intensifying competition lies ahead; here’s a road map for navigating it.</description>
      <link>http://branch2.mckinsey.com/en/insights/asia-pacific/copy_of_a_ceos_guide_to_innovation_in_china</link>
      <guid>http://branch2.mckinsey.com/en/insights/asia-pacific/copy_of_a_ceos_guide_to_innovation_in_china</guid>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Jul 2013 02:23:23 GMT</pubDate>
      <ID>2cbefcae-1fad-40a9-9438-1f536de7e419</ID>
      <category>Asia-Pacific</category>
      <dc:creator><![CDATA[Gordon Orr and Erik Roth]]></dc:creator>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><strong>China is innovating.</strong> Some of its achievements are visible: a doubling of the global percentage of patents granted to Chinese inventors since 2005, for example, and the growing role of Chinese companies in the wind- and solar-power industries. Other developments—such as advances by local companies in domestically oriented consumer electronics, instant messaging, and online gaming—may well be escaping the notice of executives who aren’t on the ground in China.</p>
<p>As innovation gains steam there, the stakes are rising for domestic and multinational companies alike. Prowess in innovation will not only become an increasingly important differentiator inside China but should also yield ideas and products that become serious competitors on the international stage.</p>
<!--roadblock-->
<p>Chinese companies and multinationals bring different strengths and weaknesses to this competition. The Chinese have traditionally had a bias toward innovation through commercialization—they are more comfortable than many Western companies are with putting a new product or service into the market quickly and improving its performance through subsequent generations. It is common for products to launch in a fraction of the time that it would take in more developed markets. While the quality of these early versions may be variable, subsequent ones improve rapidly.<a href="#" class="link-footnote" onclick="return false;" rel="#footnote1"><sup>1</sup></a> <span class="tooltip" id="footnote1" style="display: none;"><span class="footnote-content"><span class="footnote-number">1.</span><span class="footnote-text"> Commercialization differs from <i>shanzhai</i>, or “copycat innovation.” Many executives in the developed world misunderstand <i>shanzhai</i>, believing that it is purely the replication of an innovation developed in another market. Although this does occur, products developed through the <i>shanzhai</i> approach incorporate features specifically for the Chinese market. <i>Shanzhai</i> is quite prevalent in consumer products categories such as packaged goods and electronics. It can also be found in the business-to-business domain, where local companies produce knockoffs of successful foreign products or business models. </span><span class="clear"></span></span><span class="footnote-bottom"></span></span></p>
<p>Chinese companies also benefit from their government’s emphasis on indigenous innovation, underlined in the latest five-year plan. Chinese authorities view innovation as critical both to the domestic economy’s long-term health and to the global competitiveness of Chinese companies. China has already created the seeds of 22 Silicon Valley–like innovation hubs within the life sciences and biotech industries. In semiconductors, the government has been consolidating innovation clusters to create centers of manufacturing excellence.</p>
<p>But progress isn’t uniform across industries, and innovation capabilities vary significantly: several basic skills are at best nascent within a typical Chinese enterprise. Pain points include an absence of advanced techniques for understanding—analytically, not just intuitively—what customers really want, corporate cultures that don’t support risk taking, and a scarcity of the sort of internal collaboration that’s essential for developing new ideas.</p>
[[Sidebar sidebar]]
<p>Multinationals are far stronger in these areas but face other challenges, such as high attrition among talented Chinese nationals that can slow efforts to create local innovation centers. Indeed, the contrasting capabilities of domestic and multinational players, along with the still-unsettled state of intellectual-property protection (see sidebar, “Improving the patent process”), create the potential for topsy-turvy competition, creative partnerships, and rapid change. This article seeks to lay out the current landscape for would-be innovators and to describe some of the priorities for domestic and multinational companies that hope to thrive in it.</p>
<h3>China’s innovation landscape</h3>
<p>Considerable innovation is occurring in China in both the business- to-consumer and business-to-business sectors. Although breakthroughs in either space generally go unrecognized by the broader global public, many multinational B2B competitors are acutely aware of the innovative strides the Chinese are making in sectors such as communications equipment and alternative energy. Interestingly, even as multinationals struggle to cope with Chinese innovation in some areas, they seem to be holding their own in others.</p>
<h3 class="sm black">The business-to-consumer visibility gap</h3>
<p>When European and US consumers think about what China makes, they reflexively turn to basic items such as textiles and toys, not necessarily the most innovative products and rarely associated with brand names.</p>
<p>In fact, though, much product innovation in China stays there. A visit to a shop of the Suning Appliance chain, the large Chinese consumer electronics retailer, is telling. There, you might find an Android-enabled television complete with an integrated Internet-browsing capability and preloaded apps that take users straight to some of the most popular Chinese Web sites and digital movie-streaming services. Even the picture quality and industrial design are comparable to those of high-end televisions from South Korean competitors.</p>
<p>We observe the same home-grown innovation in business models. Look, for example, at the online sector, especially Tencent’s QQ instant-messaging service and the Sina Corporation’s microblog, Weibo. These models, unique to China, are generating revenue and growing in ways that have not been duplicated anywhere in the world. QQ’s low, flat-rate pricing and active marketplace for online games generate tremendous value from hundreds of millions of Chinese users.</p>
<p>What’s keeping innovative products and business models confined to China? In general, its market is so large that domestic companies have little incentive to adapt successful products for sale abroad. In many cases, the skills and capabilities of these companies are oriented toward the domestic market, so even if they want to expand globally, they face high hurdles. Many senior executives, for example, are uncomfortable doing business outside their own geography and language. Furthermore, the success of many Chinese models depends on local resources—for example, lower-cost labor, inexpensive land, and access to capital or intellectual property—that are difficult to replicate elsewhere. Take the case of mobile handsets: most Chinese manufacturers would be subject to significant intellectual property–driven licensing fees if they sold their products outside China.</p>
<h3 class="sm black">Successes in business to business</h3>
<p>Several Chinese B2B sectors are establishing a track record of innovation domestically and globally. The Chinese communications equipment industry, for instance, is a peer of developed-world companies in quality. Market acceptance has expanded well beyond the historical presence in emerging markets to include Europe’s most demanding customers, such as France Télécom and Vodafone.</p>
<p>Pharmaceuticals are another area where China has made big strides. In the 1980s and 1990s, the country was a bit player in the discovery of new chemical entities. By the next decade, however, China’s sophistication had grown dramatically. More than 20 chemical compounds discovered and developed in China are currently undergoing clinical trials.</p>
<img alt="China solar-cell factory" src="~/media/McKinsey/dotcom/Insights/Asia-Pacific/A CEOs guide to innovation in China/solar-cell.ashx?mw=510">
<p class="grayNote small">Workers produce solar-cell modules in a factory in China’s Jiangsu Province.<br>© Imaginechina/Corbis</p>
<p>China’s solar- and wind-power industries are also taking center stage. The country will become the world’s largest market for renewable-energy technology, and it already has some of the sector’s biggest companies, providing critical components for the industry globally. Chinese companies not only enjoy scale advantages but also, in the case of solar, use new manufacturing techniques to improve the efficiency of solar panels.</p>
<p>Success in B2B innovation has benefited greatly from friendly government policies, such as establishing market access barriers; influencing the nature of cross-border collaborations by setting intellectual-property requirements in electric vehicles, high-speed trains, and other segments; and creating domestic-purchasing policies that favor Chinese-made goods and services. Many view these policies as loading the dice in favor of Chinese companies, but multinationals should be prepared for their continued enforcement.</p>
<img alt="Wind Turbine" src="~/media/McKinsey/dotcom/Insights/Asia-Pacific/A CEOs guide to innovation in China/turbine.ashx?mw=510">
<p class="grayNote small">Wind turbine manufacturing in China’s Shandong Province.<br>
© Guo Xulei/Xinhua Press/Corbis</p>
<p>Despite recent setbacks, an interesting example of how the Chinese government has moved to build an industry comes from high-speed rail. Before 2004, China’s efforts to develop it had limited success. Since then, a mix of two policies—encouraging technology transfer from multinationals (in return for market access) and a coordinated R&D-investment effort—has helped China Railways’ high-speed trains to dominate the local industry. The multinationals’ revenue in this sector has remained largely unchanged since the early 2000s.</p>
<p>But it is too simplistic to claim that government support is the only reason China has had some B2B success. The strength of the country’s scientific and technical talent is growing, and local companies increasingly bring real capabilities to the table. What’s more, a number of government-supported innovation efforts have <i>not</i> been successful. Some notable examples include attempts to develop an indigenous 3G telecommunications protocol called TDS-CDMA and to replace the global Wi-Fi standard with a China-only Internet security protocol, WAPI.</p>
<h3 class="sm black">Advantage, multinationals?</h3>
<p>Simultaneously, multinationals have been shaping China’s innovation landscape by leveraging global assets. Consider, for example, the joint venture between General Motors and the Shanghai Automotive Industry Corporation, which adapted a US minivan (Buick’s GL8) for use in the Chinese market and more recently introduced a version developed in China, for China. The model has proved hugely popular among executives.</p>
<p>In fact, the market for vehicles powered by internal-combustion engines remains dominated by multinationals, despite significant incentives and encouragement from the Chinese government, which had hoped that some domestic automakers would emerge as leaders by now. The continued strength of multinationals indicates how hard it is to break through in industries with 40 or 50 years of intellectual capital. Transferring the skills needed to design and manufacture complex engineering systems has proved a significant challenge requiring mentorship, the right culture, and time.</p>
<p>We are seeing the emergence of similar challenges in electric vehicles, where early indications suggest that the balance is swinging toward the multinationals because of superior product quality. By relying less on purely indigenous innovation, China is trying to make sure the electric-vehicle story has an ending different from that of its telecommunications protocol efforts. The government’s stated aspiration of having more than five million plug-in hybrid and battery electric vehicles on the road by 2020 is heavily supported by a mix of extensive subsidies and tax incentives for local companies, combined with strict market access rules for foreign companies and the creation of new revenue pools through government and public fleet-purchase programs. But the subsidies and incentives may not be enough to overcome the technical challenges of learning to build these vehicles, particularly if multinationals decline to invest with local companies.</p>
<h3>Four priorities for innovators in China</h3>
<p>There’s no magic formula for innovation—and that goes doubly for China, where the challenges and opportunities facing domestic and multinational players are so different. Some of the priorities we describe here, such as instilling a culture of risk taking and learning, are more pressing for Chinese companies. Others, such as retaining local talent, may be harder for multinationals. Collectively, these priorities include some of the critical variables that will influence which companies lead China’s innovation revolution and how far it goes.</p>
<img alt="China high-speed train" src="~/media/McKinsey/dotcom/Insights/Asia-Pacific/A CEOs guide to innovation in China/ChinaTrain.ashx?mw=510">
<p class="grayNote small">A Chinese-built high-speed train at the Wuhan Railway Station, in Wuhan, China.<br>© Guo Xulei/Xinhua Press/Corbis</p><h3 class="sm black">Deeply understanding Chinese customers</h3>
<p>Alibaba’s Web-based trading platform, Taobao, is a great example of a product that emerged from deep insights into how customers were underserved and their inability to connect with suppliers, as well as a sophisticated understanding of the Chinese banking system. This dominant marketplace enables thousands of Chinese manufacturers to find and transact with potential customers directly. What looks like a straightforward eBay-like trading platform actually embeds numerous significant innovations to support these transactions, such as an ability to facilitate electronic fund transfers and to account for idiosyncrasies in the national banking system. Taobao wouldn’t have happened without Alibaba’s deep, analytically driven understanding of customers.</p>
<p>Few Chinese companies have the systematic ability to develop a deep understanding of customers’ problems. Domestic players have traditionally had a manufacturing-led focus on reapplying existing business models to deliver products for fast-growing markets. These “push” models will find it increasingly hard to unlock pockets of profitable growth. Shifting from delivery to creation requires more local research and development, as well as the nurturing of more market-driven organizations that can combine insights into detailed Chinese customer preferences with a clear sense of how the local business environment is evolving. Requirements include both research techniques relevant to China and people with the experience to draw out actionable customer insights.</p>
<p>Many multinationals have these capabilities, but unless they have been operating in China for some years, they may well lack the domestic-market knowledge or relationships needed to apply them effectively. The solution—building a true domestic Chinese presence rather than an outpost—sounds obvious, but it’s difficult to carry out without commitment from the top. Too many companies fail by using “fly over” management. But some multinationals appear to be investing the necessary resources; for example, we recently met (separately) with top executives of two big industrial companies who were being transferred from the West to run global R&D organizations from Shanghai. The idea is to be closer to Chinese customers and the network of institutions and universities from which multinationals source talent.</p>
<h3 class="sm black">Retaining local talent</h3>
<p>China’s universities graduate more than 10,000 science PhDs each year, and increasing numbers of Chinese scientists working overseas are returning home. Multinationals in particular are struggling to tap this inflow of researchers and managers. A recent survey by the executive-recruiting firm Heidrick & Struggles found that 77 percent of the senior executives from multinational companies responding say they have difficulty attracting managers in China, while 91 percent regard employee turnover as their top talent challenge.</p>
<p>Retention is more of an issue for multinationals than for domestic companies, but as big foreign players raise their game, so must local ones. Chinese companies, for example, excel at creating a community-like environment to build loyalty to the institution. That helps keep some employees in place when competing offers arise, but it may not always be enough.</p>
<p>Talented Chinese employees increasingly recognize the benefits of being associated with a well-known foreign brand and like the mentorship and training that foreign companies can provide. So multinationals that commit themselves to developing meaningful career paths for Chinese employees should have a chance in the growing fight with their Chinese competitors for R&D talent. Initiatives might include in-house training courses or apprenticeship programs, perhaps with local universities. General Motors sponsors projects in which professors and engineering departments at leading universities research issues of interest to the automaker. That helps it to develop closer relations with the institutions from which it recruits and to train students before they graduate.</p>
<p>Some multinationals energize Chinese engineers by shifting their roles from serving as capacity in a support of existing global programs to contributing significantly to new innovation thrusts, often aimed at the local market. This approach, increasingly common in the pharma industry, may hold lessons for other kinds of multinationals that have established R&D or innovation centers in China in recent years (read about AstraZeneca’s experience in “Three snapshots of Chinese innovation”). The keys to success include a clear objective— for instance, will activity support global programs or develop China-for-China innovations?—and a clear plan for attracting and retaining the talent needed to staff such centers. Too often, we visit impressive R&D facilities, stocked with the latest equipment, that are almost empty because staffing them has proved difficult.</p>
<h3 class="sm black">Instilling a culture of risk taking</h3>
<p>Failure is a required element of innovation, but it isn’t the norm in China, where a culture of obedience and adherence to rules prevails in most companies. Breaking or even bending them is not expected and rarely tolerated. To combat these attitudes, companies must find ways to make initiative taking more acceptable and better rewarded.</p>
<p>One approach we found, in a leading solar company, was to transfer risk from individual innovators to teams. Shared accountability and community support made increased risk taking and experimentation safer. The company has used these “innovation work groups” to develop everything from more efficient battery technology to new manufacturing processes. Team-based approaches also have proved effective for some multinationals trying to stimulate initiative taking (read about General Motors’ approach in “Three snapshots of Chinese innovation”).</p>
<p>How fast a culture of innovation takes off varies by industry. We see a much more rapid evolution toward the approach of Western companies in the way Chinese high-tech enterprises learn from their customers and how they apply that learning to create new products made for China (read a perspective on the evolution of its semiconductor sector in “Thee snapshots of Chinese innovation”). That approach is much less common at state-owned enterprises, since they are held back by hierarchical, benchmark-driven cultures.</p>
<h3 class="sm black">Promoting collaboration</h3>
<p>One area where multinationals currently have an edge is promoting collaboration and the internal collision of ideas, which can yield surprising new insights and business opportunities. In many Chinese companies, traditional organizational and cultural barriers inhibit such exchanges.</p>
<p>Although a lot of these companies have become more professional and adept at delivering products in large volumes, their ability to scale up an organization that can work collaboratively has not kept pace. Their rigorous, linear processes for bringing new products to market ensure rapid commercialization but create too many hand-offs where insights are lost and trade-offs for efficiency are promoted.</p>
<p>One Chinese consumer electronics company has repeatedly tried to improve the way it innovates. Senior management has called for new ideas and sponsored efforts to create new best-in-class processes, while junior engineers have designed high-quality prototypes. Yet the end result continues to be largely undifferentiated, incremental improvements. The biggest reason appears to be a lack of cross-company collaboration and a reliance on processes designed to build and reinforce scale in manufacturing. In effect, the technical and commercial sides of the business don’t cooperate in a way that would allow some potentially winning ideas to reach the market. As Chinese organizations mature, stories like this one may become rarer.</p>
<div class="articleBreak"></div>
<p>China hasn’t yet experienced a true innovation revolution. It will need time to evolve from a country of incremental innovation based on technology transfers to one where breakthrough innovation is common. The government will play a powerful role in that process, but ultimately it will be the actions of domestic companies and multinationals that dictate the pace of change—and determine who leads it.</p>
<div class="about-authors">
<h3 class="sm black">About the authors</h3>
<p><b>Gordon Orr</b> is a director in McKinsey’s Shanghai office, where <b>Erik Roth</b> is a principal.</p>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>IP Title</title>
      <description>descriptino</description>
      <link>http://branch2.mckinsey.com/en/insights/manufacturing/ip_article_testing</link>
      <guid>http://branch2.mckinsey.com/en/insights/manufacturing/ip_article_testing</guid>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Jul 2013 02:17:49 GMT</pubDate>
      <ID>3de1a048-04b3-47d3-b4c2-9dee7b03522b</ID>
      <category>Manufacturing</category>
      <dc:creator><![CDATA[authors]]></dc:creator>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<a href="~/media/30975660DA5C4C0D800900F1357D37A9.ashx">A_Winning_30_trillion_decathlon_intro</a>]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The value of China's emerging middle class</title>
      <description />
      <link>http://branch2.mckinsey.com/en/insights/china/copy_of_the_value_of_emerging_middle_class_in_china</link>
      <guid>http://branch2.mckinsey.com/en/insights/china/copy_of_the_value_of_emerging_middle_class_in_china</guid>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Jul 2013 07:32:47 GMT</pubDate>
      <ID>64af21ee-797e-4384-bf62-980dda096f3b</ID>
      <category>China</category>
      <dc:creator><![CDATA[Diana Farrell, Ulrich A. Gersch, and Elizabeth Stephenson]]></dc:creator>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>As global companies entered China, many focused mainly on serving China’s urban affluent consumers. However, if they continue this strategy of simply skimming the cream from the top, they risk missing the real opportunity–the emerging middle class.</p>

<p>During the next 20 years, a huge middle class with enormous spending power will emerge in China’s cities. As incomes increase, the spending patterns of this group of consumers will evolve, fueling various levels of growth across consumption categories. </p>
<p>Though the potential benefits are enormous, serving this middle class has unique challenges and companies will need to think creatively to succeed.</p>
<ul class="raqs">
    <li><a href="https://www.mckinseyquarterly.com/Economic_Studies/Productivity_Performance/The_value_of_Chinas_emerging_middle_class_1798?gp=1" target="_blank"><span class="ico sprite raquoIco"></span><span class="txtLg">Read more on the <em>McKinsey Quarterly</em> site</span> </a></li>
</ul>
<p> </p>]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Sample Article: An interview with a US Defense Department agency director</title>
      <description>David Fisher talks about his experiences after he went from the private sector to the biggest organization in the US government.</description>
      <link>http://branch2.mckinsey.com/en/insights/business_technology/br_sample_code</link>
      <guid>http://branch2.mckinsey.com/en/insights/business_technology/br_sample_code</guid>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 May 2013 12:44:08 GMT</pubDate>
      <ID>e53697a7-7602-4b6a-b006-933d282a01fd</ID>
      <category>Business  Technology</category>
      <dc:creator><![CDATA[James M. Kaplan and Kreg Nichols]]></dc:creator>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><strong>Public-sector entities,</strong> like many commercial ones, are increasingly undertaking large transformation programs to streamline and improve their core operations. Nowhere is this task more challenging than in the US Department of Defense (DoD), which is committed to transforming its business practices to support faster and more agile operations. This multiyear mission will touch all aspects of the DoD, which has annual net operating costs exceeding $620 billion—including more than $30 billion for technology—2.9 million people, and a supply chain involving 5.2 million items.</p>
<p>[[exhibit exhibit 3]]</p>
<p>
In 2005, the DoD established the Business Transformation Agency (BTA) to help guide transformation efforts throughout the department. The BTA’s responsibilities include deploying enterprise IT systems, publishing the Business Enterprise Architecture, and helping to carry out investment decisions. The agency, for example, oversees programs that manage pay and travel for the armed services, makes proposals to organizations such as the army and the navy (called “components” inside the Pentagon) about how they can transform themselves most effectively, and encourages standardization throughout the department.</p>
[[Interactive slideshow]]
<p>
Few people have as good a position to reflect upon the DoD’s transformation as David Fisher, the BTA’s first official director. Fisher joined the DoD from Silicon Valley, where as a consultant he helped private-sector companies to implement large enterprise systems. As a special assistant to the deputy undersecretary of defense for financial management, Fisher helped guide an enterprise-level business transformation and served on the team that launched the BTA. McKinsey’s James Kaplan and Kreg Nichols met with him in his office, in Arlington, Virginia, near Washington, DC, to discuss the differences between public- and private-sector transformations, as well as what he has learned about managing megaprojects.</p>
[[Sidebar sidebar]]
<p><strong>The <em>Quarterly</em>:</strong> Coming from Silicon Valley, how similar do you think the public and private sectors are?</p>
<p><strong>David Fisher:</strong> While the mission may be different, many of the business challenges are the same—for example, tracking supply chains or making certain that people are paid correctly and on time. But the public sector differs in some significant ways. For example, the scale is very different. The size and scope of the Department of Defense are challenging. The best way to think about our size is to take a look at our budget. In all, last year we had gross costs of over $600 billion, more than the sum of the revenues of, say, Wal-Mart, GE, and IBM. It’s enormous, and there’s nothing comparable to it in the private sector.</p>

<p>
Also, our leadership changes regularly—at least every eight years, when presidential administrations turn over, and generally more often. This is a challenge when you consider that huge organizations in the public and private sectors work at transformations for a long time, sometimes up to ten years, before really starting to reap the benefits. Paul Brinkley, the deputy undersecretary of defense for business transformation, reminds us that IBM was undergoing transformation for ten years before the company really started to reap the benefits of overhauling the supply chain, for example. Even in the best situations, transformations take a long time to accomplish. We look to commercial business for an indicative timeline, but you’d have to combine four or five of the Fortune 10 to get the scale of the DoD.</p>
[[interactive interactive2]]
<p><strong>The <em>Quarterly</em>:</strong> What have you been able to use from your commercial-sector experience?</p>
<p><strong>David Fisher:</strong> My experience working with large companies helped prepare me for this type of role by giving me a willingness to buck the cultural trend and to suggest new ways of doing business. The BTA has been trying to apply the best practices from the commercial world, especially about how we govern and manage IT investments. If there are processes that we can streamline to help programs deliver capabilities faster, without getting bogged down in some of the administrative activities, we try to do that.</p>

<p>
This can be hard to do in a complex, hierarchical environment like the Department of Defense. Fortunately, many people around me, who have more experience within the government culture, have proved to be tremendously valuable at identifying constraints we face in public projects—constraints that just wouldn’t be there in the private sector.</p>
<p>
The department has been trying to modernize the way it does business for a long time, and we still have a long way to go. Every administration tries, and I’m sure we make some progress each time. But on the whole, we’re not where we want to be—or where we need to be. We want to build on the good work that’s been done before us, but we also need to question previous actions that weren’t successful and to offer new solutions.</p>
<p><strong>The <em>Quarterly</em>:</strong> What are the goals of your transformation efforts?</p>
<p><strong>David Fisher:</strong> Our overall objective is to guide business transformation efforts at the enterprise level of the Department of Defense in order to improve the DoD’s ability to perform its mission. We do that sometimes directly, sometimes indirectly. The BTA has a combination of operational and technical roles to play—for example, we manage the systems that handle travel and payroll for about 1.5 million employees of the DoD. But a big part of our role is to identify skill sets that are scattered throughout the DoD and unite them so that its components can work better together. For example, we bring the functional people and the technical people together so that a set of data standards affecting multiple areas can be agreed on.</p>
<p>
Successful coordination among the components doesn’t come from exercising authority but rather from exerting influence. People in the components don’t have to open the door to us, and I’m not empowered to make them open the door. But if I can demonstrate value, they’re going to open the door to me, whether I’m empowered or not. It’s all about adding value. There are certain things that we have authority for, but even in an environment where you have authority, your authority will only carry you so far in the effort to move things forward in a positive direction.</p>
<p><strong>The <em>Quarterly</em>:</strong> What are the main challenges in deploying technology to support the transformation?</p>
<p><strong>David Fisher:</strong> We spend about $2 billion each year on IT business transformation, half of it on enterprise resource planning systems throughout the Department of Defense. Much of the work for these ERP systems focuses on deciding what should be centralized, at the DoD enterprise level, and what should be managed by components—the military services, defense agencies, combatant commands, and military health services. As in any large organization, the people at the enterprise level are consumers of information. As long as information in different systems can be aggregated in a standard way, these people can do their jobs. On the other hand, some decision making is distributed, occurring within organizations that make up the DoD. The challenge lies in the gray area. Where is it more effective to have a single system at the center as opposed to multiple versions that adhere to common standards?</p>
<p>
[video Sample Chaptered video]
We have 27 systems in our enterprise portfolio today, and many of these are centralized only because the components did not have the ability to run their own when these systems were implemented years ago. As the capabilities of the components mature, we must ask if there are more efficient and effective ways to complete those transactions while still providing the members of our cross-component community with the information they need to do their jobs.</p>
<p><strong>The <em>Quarterly</em>:</strong> How do you manage such a large-scale transformation?</p>
<p><strong>David Fisher:</strong> Much depends on governance and on discipline in setting and implementing standards. Consider our experience implementing a set of standards for financial data. Initially, the reaction in the field was that this would cost too much to embed in individual IT systems, so we came up with a two-pronged approach.</p>
<p>
In the short term, we agreed to create a bridge system to the components’ legacy accounting systems, to save costs. It wasn’t a perfect solution, but it moved us toward interoperable data at a relatively low cost in a short time frame. Our longer-term challenge involved integrating these standards into various ERP systems. It was critical to get this right, from the beginning. Again, the components’ managers were concerned that this would be expensive and difficult to integrate with their SAP and Oracle systems. So we deployed ERP experts among the components who worked with teams there to identify ways to configure the ERP systems so they could work with standardized data. It’s been very successful.</p>
<p><strong>The <em>Quarterly</em>:</strong> How do you keep people motivated and set performance measures?</p>
<p><strong>David Fisher:</strong> When I left the commercial environment, I thought one of the great things about leaving was putting behind me the need to meet quarterly profit-and-loss targets and to deal with the short-term decision making that results from a quarterly focus. But now that I don’t have those constraints, I miss having the motivation to hit quarterly numbers. So you have to look for different kinds of motivators to keep projects on time.</p>
<p>
The people who go into public service are unbelievably passionate about what they do. There is a tangible internal motivation about doing public service that is different from what you find in the commercial marketplace. It’s not something you can necessarily put your finger on, but it’s real. We appreciate that. It’s very important. That said, we have to find ways to measure accountability. In the commercial world, there’s the P&L—you’re held accountable for the numbers. We are always in search of ways to hold people accountable, not least because if you succeed at something, you want to be recognized for it.</p>
<p>
We and the rest of the Defense Department have recently begun to move away from an old tenure-based performance model to a new system—the National Security Personnel System—that is closer to pay for performance. This is the type of system that’s familiar to commercial enterprises, but it’s new to this public environment, so we had to spend some time explaining that the goals had to be objective, measurable, time constrained. It’s been somewhat controversial because not everyone likes this shift. But as a manager, I have found it a positive shift, especially in terms of getting people to think about time. Sometimes, impatience is exactly right because within the public sector, things do tend to run on for a while. We need to build in that internal motivator that makes people ask, what did I get done today?</p>
<p>
In the end, however, while people care about their compensation, just as they should, it’s a small part of what motivates people here. It’s about the contribution to public service. One of the things that rallies the passion of these folks is seeing that they’re making a difference on a national security–related issue that helps the people on the ground.</p>
<p><strong>The <em>Quarterly</em>:</strong> With such large-scale technology deployments, what have you learned about managing megaprojects?</p>
<p><strong>David Fisher:</strong> Many of the things that would portend a successful ERP implementation of small to medium size would portend success for the large programs at the DoD. We’ve looked at the top reasons ERP implementations fail. Many failures come down to governance, change management, requirements management, customization, the skill sets of the people involved, and testing. Those concepts are immutable, regardless of size and scale. Our challenge with these immense projects is that implementation takes such a long time, spanning several generations of IT development. That can be problematic and leave an opportunity for endless analysis and debate.</p>
<p>
It’s also important to clarify what we’re trying to optimize, since one person’s definition of the enterprise may be different from another’s. From my perspective, the enterprise is the Department of Defense. But if I go to the army or navy, they might define the enterprise differently; if they’re trying to optimize the army or navy as opposed to the DoD, we end up with different solutions.</p>
<p>
Let me give you one example of how the BTA’s involvement helped the army reexamine the scope of some of its systems to good effect. The army had three big ERP systems—one that handled finance and two for logistics (a more tactical system for the front end and a more wholesale system for the back end). All three systems were operating fairly independently. Our observation was that, although these independent systems may be optimizing the parts, they were suboptimizing the whole in terms of business processes, management, and the utilization of technology.</p>
[video Sample Video]
<p>
Through some pretty heavy engagements—some well received, others not—we were able to demonstrate that there was a better way to use technology to reduce risks the army would face in the way the systems communicated, reconciled data, and otherwise performed together. We recommended that the army connect the three systems more closely because, for example, each of the logistics transactions was eventually going to be a financial transaction. If you look at things that way from the beginning, it fosters an environment where you look at the business from end to end. The army has now adopted some of those concepts and has a cross-domain governance model. So we got the conversation going and it’s had this positive impact. We weren’t empowered to do any of that by our authority. We were passionate about it, and we were able to convince the army to let us in on the dialogue and help them come to decisions that represented a change for the better.</p>
<p><strong>The <em>Quarterly</em>:</strong> Any other big lessons to pass along?</p>
<p><strong>David Fisher:</strong> Question every assumption. We often assume that we have to do something in a certain way because it’s the policy or the way we’ve done it before. Question that assumption, and if it doesn’t make sense, find out who owns the policy or who owns the way it was done before. Even laws change. Sometimes the answer is no, and that’s it. But if you have a case that helps everyone to agree that the old way doesn’t make sense and that there’s a better way, a transformational way, of doing things, question the old way.  </p>
<div class="about-authors">
<h3 class="sm black">About the authors</h3>
<p><strong>James Kaplan</strong> is a principal in McKinsey’s New York office, and <strong>Kreg Nichols</strong> is an associate principal in the Atlanta office.</p>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Exploding the myths of offshoring</title>
      <description />
      <link>http://branch2.mckinsey.com/en/insights/employment_and_growth/exploding_the_myths_of_offshoring</link>
      <guid>http://branch2.mckinsey.com/en/insights/employment_and_growth/exploding_the_myths_of_offshoring</guid>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Apr 2013 23:00:46 GMT</pubDate>
      <ID>ac79713e-1645-4593-bf10-82206a72ec81</ID>
      <category>Employment and growth</category>
      <dc:creator><![CDATA[Martin N. Baily, Diana Farrell]]></dc:creator>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>With the digital revolution and the dramatic fall in international telecommunications costs comes the prospect that white-collar jobs—once insulated from global competition—can be performed offshore, in low-wage nations such as India, where labor can be hired for as little as one-tenth its cost in the United States. Call-center agents, data processors, medical technicians, and software programmers could all find their jobs at risk from the nation's growing trade in services with emerging markets. In fact, offshoring is frequently blamed for the agonizingly slow pace of job growth in the United States, despite a recovering economy.</p>
<p>Even free traders have wavered in their beliefs. Critics warn that millions of people in the United States will become jobless. The response from Congress has been to include in a fiscal 2004 spending bill a provision prohibiting federal agencies from outsourcing some kinds of work to private companies that use workers in foreign countries. Indeed, 23 states are considering similar restrictions; 4 have already passed them. Jobs and trade have become the hot-button issues of the 2004 presidential election race.</p>
<p>The current debate is misplaced, however, because the problem is neither trade itself nor globalization more broadly but rather the question of how the country should allocate the benefits of global trade. Trade in services, like other forms of international trade, benefits the United States as a whole by making the economic pie bigger and raising the standard of living. Outsourcing jobs abroad can help keep companies profitable, thereby preserving other US jobs. The cost savings can be used to lower prices and to offer consumers new and better types of services. By raising productivity, offshoring enables companies to invest more in the next-generation technologies and business ideas that create new jobs. And with the world's most flexible and innovative economy, the United States is uniquely positioned to benefit from the trend. After all, despite a large overall trade deficit, the country has consistently run a surplus in its international trade in services.</p>
<ul class="raqs">
    <li><a href="https://www.mckinseyquarterly.com/Operations/Exploding_the_myths_of_offshoring_1453" target="_blank"><span class="ico sprite raquoIco"></span><span class="txtLg">Read more on the <em>McKinsey Quarterly</em> site</span> </a></li>
</ul>]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Exploding the myths about offshoring</title>
      <description />
      <link>http://branch2.mckinsey.com/en/insights/employment_and_growth/exploding_the_myths_about_offshoring</link>
      <guid>http://branch2.mckinsey.com/en/insights/employment_and_growth/exploding_the_myths_about_offshoring</guid>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Apr 2013 23:00:46 GMT</pubDate>
      <ID>2029f949-1f6d-4aca-9168-752d3dd74379</ID>
      <category>Employment and growth</category>
      <dc:creator><![CDATA[Martin N. Baily, Diana Farrell]]></dc:creator>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>In this essay, Martin Baily, a Senior Fellow at the Institute for International Economics and a Senior Advisor to the McKinsey Global Institute (MGI), and Diana Farrell, Director, MGI, reflect on the current heated debate about offshoring and put the issue in perspective. The authors cite MGI research that demonstrates the sizeable benefits the US stands to gain from offshoring through corporate savings, additional exports, repatriated profits, greater productivity, and new jobs.</p>
<p>While free trade creates wealth and improves a nation's standard of living, not all groups reap the same benefits, particularly in the short term. The reality of the emerging global economy is that the workforce is experiencing higher turnover than ever before. The challenge is how to make that inevitable process less painful and share more of the wealth being created.</p>
<p>Baily and Farrell cite concrete options for political and business leaders to help workers make the transition. Developing countries on their end must open their economies to attain the full benefits that free trade makes possible. Case evidence from MGI's research demonstrates how developing countries benefit from foreign direct investment. By resisting further liberalization, developing economies risk missing out on tremendous growth opportunities. </p>]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>French employment 2020: Five priorities for action</title>
      <description />
      <link>http://branch2.mckinsey.com/en/insights/employment_and_growth/french_employment_2020</link>
      <guid>http://branch2.mckinsey.com/en/insights/employment_and_growth/french_employment_2020</guid>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Apr 2013 23:00:46 GMT</pubDate>
      <ID>12b93c6f-ac06-4ae5-967e-57001fd73d69</ID>
      <category>Employment and growth</category>
      <dc:creator><![CDATA[Eric Labaye, Charles Roxburgh, Clarisse Magnin, and Jan Mischke]]></dc:creator>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>France’s labor market has been relatively resilient in the face of the global financial crisis of 2008 and 2009 and of the sovereign-debt crisis, which gathered full force last year. But unemployment has begun to rise again. Achieving a considerable boost to employment is now critical because it is difficult to see how, without reversing this decline, France can sustain a social safety net that is already under significant strain.</p>
<p>Until the 1990s, France was among Europe’s leading economies in per capita GDP. By 2010, however, the country had dropped to 11th out of the EU-15. Low labor force participation of seniors and young people, as well as high unemployment rates are the main drivers of this per capita GDP gap. </p>
<p>A report from the McKinsey Global Institute finds that to meet even moderate ambitions for employment and prosperity, France must create more than twice as many net new jobs annually as it did during the past 20 years.</p>
<p>Unless France acts, by 2020 it may face a shortfall of 2.2 million highly skilled workers, and 2.3 million low-skilled workers will be unable to find jobs. Addressing this intensifying structural mismatch of skills is required to increase employment.</p>
<p style="margin-top: 30px;"><span class="mck_h6">Exhibit</span></p>
<p><img width="510" height="426" style="margin-bottom: 30px;" alt="Projected 2020 employment in France" src="~/media/4306713F731F499DA582B1D20A50960A.ashx" /></p>
<p>Drawing on European best practices, the report recommends that France should set five priorities for its 2020 labor agenda:</p>
<ul class="bullListSep">
    <li>reform labor market conditions for seniors to increase their level of workforce participation </li>
    <li>boost the overall skills of students and workers and better adapt their skills to the knowledge economy’s market demands </li>
    <li>improve labor costs and the flexibility of the labor market </li>
    <li>support job-creating growth for the high- and low-skilled alike </li>
    <li>improve mechanisms to ensure that employment policies are effective and efficient </li>
</ul>]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Five myths about how to create jobs</title>
      <description />
      <link>http://branch2.mckinsey.com/en/insights/employment_and_growth/five_myths_about_how_to_create_jobs</link>
      <guid>http://branch2.mckinsey.com/en/insights/employment_and_growth/five_myths_about_how_to_create_jobs</guid>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Apr 2013 23:00:46 GMT</pubDate>
      <ID>ba85a3f4-5667-414c-9c90-da625eee7dbd</ID>
      <category>Employment and growth</category>
      <dc:creator><![CDATA[James Manyika and Byron Auguste]]></dc:creator>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The costly retirement of 76 million US baby boomers will swell the ranks of the elderly to more than 20 percent of the population of the United States during the next 20 years. In Europe and Japan, the elderly will come to account for more than 30 percent of the population during the same period. This transformation is about to create a new sense of urgency to get the most from every government dollar. Public services beyond health care and pensions for seniors will face epic squeezes, and officials will struggle to balance the needs of retirees and younger citizens while still holding taxes to politically acceptable levels. Boosting the government's performance will be an imperative no country can ignore.</p>
<p>To be sure, attempts have been made before. In the United States, former Vice President Al Gore's efforts to "reinvent government" in the early 1990s scored some successes. The administration of President George W. Bush has made efforts to reform civil service rules that inhibit some sensible management practices. The Government Accountability Office (formerly the General Accounting Office) has shown perennial leadership in prodding government departments to address their management challenges. In the United Kingdom, Peter Gershon's recent review of government efficiency1 has galvanized work to improve productivity across the public sector, with a target of £20 billion in savings by the end of 2008.</p>
<p>But veterans of reform efforts agree that they have barely begun to scratch the surface of the government's performance potential. One reason is that reforms take sustained attention—often rare when they become caught up in partisan or interest group politics. What's more, political cultures remain oriented to legislation, not to executing and managing programs. Few people make their name by improving the way government runs.</p>
<p>Nonetheless, the coming era's extraordinary fiscal pressures will force leaders to overcome these obstacles. In the developed world, the state commands a large share of the economy, so improving the performance of government departments can generate hundreds of billions of dollars of value. Our experience working with public institutions in 50 countries has shown us that the opportunity, though hard to capture, is large enough to take some of the sting out of the hard choices that aging societies face. With the first baby boomers becoming eligible for retiree health and pension benefits in just a few years, there is no time to lose.</p>
<ul class="raqs" sizset="78" sizcache="4">
    <li><a href="https://www.mckinseyquarterly.com/Five_myths_about_how_to_create_jobs_2526" target="_blank"><span class="ico sprite raquoIco"></span><span class="txtLg">Read more on the <em>McKinsey Quarterly</em> site</span> </a></li>
</ul>]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Beyond cheap labor: Lessons for developing economies</title>
      <description />
      <link>http://branch2.mckinsey.com/en/insights/employment_and_growth/beyond_cheap_labor</link>
      <guid>http://branch2.mckinsey.com/en/insights/employment_and_growth/beyond_cheap_labor</guid>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Apr 2013 23:00:46 GMT</pubDate>
      <ID>436b15e3-29c3-4170-a0b9-1400099350bb</ID>
      <category>Employment and growth</category>
      <dc:creator><![CDATA[Diana Farrell, Antonio Puron, and Jaana K. Remes]]></dc:creator>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Buoyed by the North American Free Trade Agreement (NAFTA), Mexico in the 1990s was the bustling factory floor of the Americas. But since 2000, as China rose to assume that role, more than 270,000 Mexicans have lost assembly jobs, hundreds of factories have closed their doors, and Mexico's trade deficit with China has grown to more than $5 billion. The ubiquitous "Made in China" stamp, found on everything from toys to textiles to statues of Our Lady of Guadalupe, has become the incarnation of the single greatest perceived threat to Mexico's economic prosperity—and a symbol of the pitfalls of globalization.</p>
<p>Mexico's fears are not unique. China's economic surge and its entry into the World Trade Organization have sparked alarm across the developing world. In middle-income countries such as Brazil, Poland, Portugal, and South Korea, a rising standard of living makes their position as low-wage producers and exporters increasingly tenuous.</p>
<p>Rather than fixating on jobs lost to China, these countries should remember a fact of economic life: no place can remain the world's low-cost producer forever—even China will lose that title one day. Instead of trying to defend low-wage assembly jobs, Mexico and other middle-income countries should focus on creating jobs that add higher value. Only if more productive companies with higher-value-added activities replace less productive ones can middle-income economies continue down the development path. Even so, being part of the global economy requires these countries, like Lewis Carroll's Alice in Through the Looking Glass, to do a lot of running just to stay in the same place. Unfortunately, for too many of them the focus on China—and, more broadly, political rhetoric against globalization—are blocking reform efforts.</p>
<p class="mck_h3_md">Blame China?</p>
<p>To developing countries watching foreign investors head east, China's economic prowess might seem invincible, but history suggests otherwise. Only 20 years ago, for example, the United States was convinced that the superior business models and industrial policies of Germany and Japan would shutter every last domestic factory door. In the 1990s, the United States fretted about the threat from the high-tech industries of South Korea and Taiwan, while presidential candidates warned of the "giant sucking sound" made by the migration of jobs to Mexico under NAFTA. These days, the United States is more concerned about the effect of China's economy on its trade balance and employment rate.</p>
<p>Nearly all countries worry about jobs lost to others—a fact often exploited for political ends. The demagoguery obscures the fact that countries must evolve to meet the challenges presented by new competitors outside their borders.</p>
<p>Mexico is a case in point. Like most middle-income countries, it has grown more prosperous through freer trade and liberalization. Its average household income is now more than twice the level in China and other low-wage countries, and its manufacturing wage rates reflect this increasing prosperity. But the maquiladora assembly operations that line the US border—often the most visible face of Mexico's entry into the global economy—are only a small part of the cause. Since NAFTA came into effect, in 1994, the country has received upward of $170 billion in foreign direct investment—more than three times the amount that India attracted. Yet less than 15 percent of this investment has gone to the maquiladoras; the vast majority has been motivated by a desire to sell into Mexico's large domestic market, not to produce cheap goods for export. Our research shows that non-maquiladora investments have generated a wide range of benefits for Mexico's economy by creating jobs, boosting competition and productivity, lowering prices, and enhancing consumer choice. Consider the impact of foreign investment on Mexico's automobile market: consumers can now choose from dozens of models, compared with just a few of them before. In the retailing industry, the price of fresh food in Mexico City is 40 percent below its level in 1993, the year before NAFTA opened up the economy. The lesson for Mexico and for other countries where jobs are going offshore is this: don't overestimate the value of low-wage employment.</p>
<ul class="raqs">
    <li><a href="https://www.mckinseyquarterly.com/Economic_Studies/Country_Reports/Beyond_cheap_labor_Lessons_for_developing_economies_1545?gp=1#Exhibit1" target="_blank"><span class="ico sprite raquoIco"></span><span class="txtLg">Read more on the <em>McKinsey Quarterly</em> site</span> </a></li>
</ul>]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>An economy that works: Job creation and America's future</title>
      <description />
      <link>http://branch2.mckinsey.com/en/insights/employment_and_growth/an_economy_that_works_for_us_job_creation</link>
      <guid>http://branch2.mckinsey.com/en/insights/employment_and_growth/an_economy_that_works_for_us_job_creation</guid>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Apr 2013 23:00:46 GMT</pubDate>
      <ID>754b2dd8-1b8d-4d88-be08-d6c15ae5a8fc</ID>
      <category>Employment and growth</category>
      <dc:creator><![CDATA[James Manyika, Susan Lund, Byron Auguste, Lenny Mendonca, Tim Welsh, Sreenivas Ramaswamy]]></dc:creator>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>For the United States to return to full employment—finding work for the currently unemployed and accommodating new entrants into the labor force this decade—the US economy will need to create 21 million jobs by 2020, according to MGI's analysis.</p>
<p></p>
<p>To understand how this might happen, MGI launched a research project that combines extensive sector analysis, interviews with human resource executives, a proprietary survey of 2,000 business leaders, and our own scenario analysis and modeling.</p>
<p>The research analyzes the causes of slow job creation in the period before the recession and during the recovery and the implications of these forces for future job growth. The research projects how the US labor force will evolve over the next ten years and creates different scenarios for job growth based on extensive analysis of sector trends. MGI's central finding is that a return to full employment will occur in only the most optimistic job-growth scenario. This will require not only a robust economic recovery but also a concerted effort to address other factors that impede employment, including growing gaps in skill and education.</p>
<p>The report offers a range of illustrative solutions based on lessons from US states and other countries that MGI hopes will add to the national conversation on jobs.</p>
<p class="mck_h3_md">Findings include:</p>
<p></p>
<ul class="bullListSep">
    <li>Recoveries are increasingly becoming "jobless" due to firm restructuring, skill and geographic mismatches between workers and jobs, and sharp decline in new start-ups.</li>
    <li>The US needs to create 21 million new jobs by 2020 to regain full employment—and only achieves this in our most optimistic job-growth scenario.</li>
    <li>The US workforce will continue to grow until 2020, but under current trends, many workers will not have the right skills for the available jobs. Technology is changing the nature of work: Jobs are being disaggregated into tasks, work is becoming virtual, and firms are relying on flexible labor (temporary, contract workers). These trends offer new opportunities for creating jobs in the United States, a trend that some companies do not fully appreciate.</li>
    <li>Progress in four dimensions will be essential for reviving the US job-creation machine: Develop the US workforce-skill to better match what employers are looking for; expand US workers' share of global economic growth by attracting foreign investment and spurring exports; revive the nation's spark by supporting emerging industries, ensuring more of them scale up in the United States, and reviving new business start-ups; and speed up regulatory decision-making that blocks business expansion and new investment. </li>
</ul>
<p>The report is part of a series of MGI perspectives on the theme of US growth and renewal.</p>]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Employment performance</title>
      <description />
      <link>http://branch2.mckinsey.com/en/insights/employment_and_growth/employment_performance</link>
      <guid>http://branch2.mckinsey.com/en/insights/employment_and_growth/employment_performance</guid>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Apr 2013 23:00:46 GMT</pubDate>
      <ID>63b5ed8b-2243-42d4-8c3e-1a601767a8c8</ID>
      <category>Employment and growth</category>
      <dc:creator><![CDATA[Bill Lewis, Thomas Gerstner, René Limacher, Mike Longman, Mineki Toyama, Michele Appendino, Tomas Calleja, Michel Paulin, Kathy Huang, Eric Zitzewitz, et al.]]></dc:creator>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Unemployment is viewed as a serious problem in many industrial nations, but the reasons for it are not well understood. Among MGI's findings across seven industries is that Japan and the US have lower rates of unemploymen than European countries because they have created jobs in the market part of the economy. Differences in employment performance ultimately stem from differences in the rates at which industrial economies evolve.</p>
<p class="mck_h3_md">Synthesis</p>
<p>In most of the countries studied, there were employment declines in three manufacturing industries. In market services, the general evidence points to increasing employment. The sizes of the increases in the service sector employment vary widely, with the US having the largest increase overall.</p>
<p class="mck_h3_md">Objectives and Approach</p>
<p>There is no shortage of reports about employment but they all tend to focus on the issue from a macroeconomic perspective. MGI's work is based on the premise that understanding the causes of employment behavior at the industry level would allow us to determine the relative importance of particular labor, product, and capital market factors.</p>
<p class="mck_h3_md">Aggregate Analysis</p>
<p>Four main factors effect the evolution of economies: productivity growth rates, innovation, trade and foreign direct investment, and consumption and investment patterns. MGI's fundamental hypothesis is that if there are barriers to the evolution of economies that prevent the transfer of resources into expanding firms and industries, then the result can be a slowing of overall job growth.</p>
<p class="mck_h3_md">Automotive Sector</p>
<p>Intense competition in the 1980s increased cost pressures and triggered restructuring in automotive industries worldwide. Employment fared best in Japan where demand growth in the local market was combined with cost-driven improvements in trade performance.</p>
<p class="mck_h3_md">Computer Sector</p>
<p>Despite being more innovative, the US computer industry did not create as many jobs as Japan. Earlier structural changes in the American industry explain much of this paradox.</p>
<p class="mck_h3_md">Furniture Sector</p>
<p>As in most mature manufacturing sectors, the long-term employment trend in the furniture industry has been and will be downward. Innovation helped to slow this trend in the US, Italy, and Germany.</p>
<p class="mck_h3_md">Banking Sector</p>
<p>Product, labor, and capital market barriers effected employment through changes in competitive intensity. The US, France, and Spain all experienced employment declines in traditional banking products as competitive intensity increased in the 1980s.</p>
<p class="mck_h3_md">Retailing Sector</p>
<p>Retail is experiencing a structural shift as old formats disappear and new innovative ones offer more value to the customer and operate with greater efficiency. Rigidities in the product and labor markets retarded the emergence of high-value formats in France, Germany, and Japan, which in turn has led to lower overall employment.</p>
<p class="mck_h3_md">Film/TV/Video Sector</p>
<p>In the high visibility film/TV/video sector, innovation is the driving force in both the creation and destruction of jobs. Slower employment growth in Europe can be explained by regulations that have inhibited the emergence of new segments.</p>
<p class="mck_h3_md">Construction Sector</p>
<p>The myriad rules and regulations governing the construction sector in Europe and Japan provide an excellent example of how product market restrictions stifle output. Faster output growth - together with slower gains in productivity - resulted in better employment performance for the US.</p>
<p class="mck_h3_md">Implications</p>
<p>Policymakers have numerous opportunities to encourage job creation by deregulating, particularly in the product market, which is the area of greatest opportunity as it could lead to job creation across the wage spectrum.</p>]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Changing the fortunes of America's workforce: A human-capital challenge</title>
      <description />
      <link>http://branch2.mckinsey.com/en/insights/employment_and_growth/changing_the_fortunes_of_us_workforce</link>
      <guid>http://branch2.mckinsey.com/en/insights/employment_and_growth/changing_the_fortunes_of_us_workforce</guid>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Apr 2013 23:00:46 GMT</pubDate>
      <ID>deaaea6c-ca5e-410d-bba8-815c1f6b961f</ID>
      <category>Employment and growth</category>
      <dc:creator><![CDATA[Diana Farrell, Martha Laboissiere, Imran Ahmed, Jan Peter aus dem Moore, Tilman Eichstadt, Lucia Fiorito, Alexander Grunewald, Jorge Hargrave, James Hoyt, Diana Kapsa, Tanya Khakbaz, Thomas Lamatsch, Dorothy Liao, Jenny Liao, Robin Matthias, Sara Parker, Ying Shi, Claudia Steinwender, Soyoko Umeno, Gina Campbell, and Katherine Hinkebein, et al.]]></dc:creator>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Rising income dispersion in the United States and other advanced nations has become a source of concern. Since the early 1970s, incomes for the highest US earners have raced ahead, while those at the bottom of the income distribution have stood still and those in the middle barely increased. Strikingly, even in the current recession, this underlying trend is not reversing. </p>
<p>In an effort to provide a comprehensive, well-founded explanation to policymakers and other interested parties, the McKinsey Global Institute and McKinsey Social Sector Office have conducted a study of changes in income dispersion and their causes from 1991 to 2005, the height of the economic cycle. The study analyzed a broader, deeper data set than previous research in the area, making it the first attempt to estimate the contribution to rising dispersion of fundamental changes in the US economy’s mix of industries and occupations. Its findings show that redeveloping America’s human capital should be the focus of labor market policy coming out of the recession. </p>
<p>Understanding the patchwork of the United States’ labor market is key to understanding what has happened to income growth. Labor income largely accounts for 75 to 85 percent of household pretax income across the income distribution, and the analysis shows that differential rates of growth in labor incomes were the most significant sources of the differential rates of household income growth across the income distribution. For this reason, the research takes as its starting point the labor market rather than household incomes as most previous studies have done, resulting in a more detailed picture than was previously available. </p>
<p>The report examines eight clusters of industry/occupation pairs or jobs in which employees experienced similar income levels, income growth, and employment growth over the period. The analysis reveals that 71 percent of  US workers are in jobs for which there has been a decrease in demand from employers, an increase in supply of eligible workers, or both.  </p>
<p>The research also analyzes nine possible drivers of changes in labor income. Incomes and employment for the top-earning 22 percent of workers grew fast, mostly because new technologies and new opportunities in global markets ramped up demand for advanced skills. </p>
<p>Education has played a critical role in giving workers access to higher-earning job clusters. Moreover, an undersupply of workers with the skills to fill the kinds of jobs fostered by new technologies in more complex organizations means that people with those skills have been able to win income premiums. Having the appropriate education or training is the ticket to higher-paid work. </p>
<p>The analysis showed that migration and deunionization depressed levels of compensation for labor in repetitive manual jobs and administrative support in the four lowest-earning clusters across all industries. </p>
<p>At a deeper structural level, global economic integration and technological advances have combined to produce permanent changes in the skill levels required to flourish in the US labor market, the research concludes. Unless the mass of America’s human capital can be developed fast, the nation risks another period in which growth resumes but income dispersion persists, with Americans in the bottom and middle-earning income clusters never really benefiting from the recovery.</p>
<p>While there is no single cause or “silver bullet” remedy for rising income dispersion, upgrading the productivity, skills, and rewards in the service sector is the key challenge.</p>]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Part III: The emerging global labor market: How supply and demand for offshore talent meet</title>
      <description />
      <link>http://branch2.mckinsey.com/en/insights/employment_and_growth/the_emerging_global_labor_market_supply_and_demand</link>
      <guid>http://branch2.mckinsey.com/en/insights/employment_and_growth/the_emerging_global_labor_market_supply_and_demand</guid>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Apr 2013 23:00:45 GMT</pubDate>
      <ID>9b8b23ea-bfb1-4a1e-a27f-a51d8fd98adf</ID>
      <category>Employment and growth</category>
      <dc:creator><![CDATA[Diana Farrell, Martha Laboissiére, Robert Pascal, Charles de Segundo, Jaeson Rosenfeld, Sascha Stürze, Fusayo Umezawa]]></dc:creator>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Global resourcing may raise wages in some occupations in the lowest cost supply countries, but the practice will not significantly impact wages or employment in developed countries. Of all the occupations, engineering has the lowest supply of suitable talent relative to demand.</p>
<p>At an aggregate level, the potential supply of suitable talent from the low-wage countries we studied exceeds the likely demand for it by two-fold. </p>
<p>In practice, companies hiring offshore tend to follow each other to locations that have a track record in providing offshore talent. The resulting agglomeration of companies in popular locations has some positive effects, such as accelerating improvements in infrastructure, communications and the business environment. But the pattern also leads to local wage inflation and high levels of attrition. MGI found that wages for engineers and generalists could double in the lowest wage countries, but will remain below 30 percent of the level of wages for engineers in the United States, or the current level of wages for these two occupations in Mexico and Brazil. In contrast, the effects of offshoring on employment and wages in developed countries will be negligible. </p>
<p>Companies can find more suitable locations offshore if they rationally analyze the factors that are most important to them, including their home market, their first language, what activity they want to outsource, the scale on which they want to offshore, and whether they want to outsource or set up a captive operation. That means different companies will assign different costs and benefits to the same location. </p>]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Part I: The emerging global labor market: The demand for offshore talent in services</title>
      <description />
      <link>http://branch2.mckinsey.com/en/insights/employment_and_growth/the_emerging_global_labor_market_demand_for_offshore_talent</link>
      <guid>http://branch2.mckinsey.com/en/insights/employment_and_growth/the_emerging_global_labor_market_demand_for_offshore_talent</guid>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Apr 2013 23:00:45 GMT</pubDate>
      <ID>f3a22a07-6f0b-47b5-9736-b1f24631c1c3</ID>
      <category>Employment and growth</category>
      <dc:creator><![CDATA[Diana Farrell, Martha Laboissiére, Robert Pascal, Jaeson Rosenfeld, Charles de Segundo, Sascha Stürze ]]></dc:creator>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Although 11 percent of the world's 1.46 billion service jobs can be theoretically performed remotely, the number of those jobs offshored by 2008 will remain modest. An estimated 1.1 percent of total demand for labor in services will go offshore due mainly to internal company barriers.</p>
<p></p>
<p>Only a small fraction of employment that could potentially go offshore will ever do so. </p>
<p>Eleven percent (161 million jobs) of the 1.46 billion service jobs worldwide could be performed remotely. As a rule, the more customer facing functions a sector has, the lower its potential to resource those functions remotely. Consequently, this potential varies depending on the industry. The lowest potential is in retail, for example, where 3 percent of employment may be globally resourced. Packaged software, however, could see 49 percent of its services work done remotely. </p>
<p>We estimate that total offshore employment amounted to about 1.7 million jobs in 2003. In 2008, total offshore employment will reach an estimated 1.1 percent of total demand for labor in services from developed countries, equivalent to 4.1 million employees. </p>
<p>Some occupations are also more amenable to remote employment than others. Engineering and finance and accounting occupations are the most amenable (52 percent and 31 percent, respectively), while generalist and support staff occupations are the least (9 percent and 3 percent, respectively) because of the close interactions they entail with customers or colleagues. However, because every industry employs many generalists and support staff, these occupations have the highest number of jobs that could be filled by remote talent — a combined total of 26 million positions. </p>
<p>The gap between the current and potential levels of adoption is mainly explained by internal company barriers rather than regulatory deterrents. Most notably operational issues, management attitudes to offshoring, and structural issues keeping companies from outsourcing services. </p>
<p>Offshore employment will grow gradually, making no sudden impact on labor markets overall in developed countries. In fact, its growth will have less impact on patterns of employment than the decline in manufacturing employment developed countries have already experienced. </p>]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
