<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"
     xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
     xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
     xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/"
     xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
     xmlns:georss="http://www.georss.org/georss" 
     xmlns:fh="http://purl.org/syndication/history/1.0">
	<channel>
		<title>McKinsey &amp; Company: Insights and Publications</title>
		<link>http://www.mckinsey.com/insights/</link>
		<description>Your source for articles published by McKinsey &amp; Company </description>
		<language>en-us</language>
		<copyright>Copyright 2013, McKinsey &amp; Company</copyright>
		<managingEditor>test@mckinsey.com (DotCom Team)</managingEditor>
		<webMaster>web@mckinsey.com (DotCom Team)</webMaster>
		<pubDate>Fri, 30 Aug 2013 00:00:01 -0500</pubDate>
		<lastBuildDate>Fri, 30 Aug 2013 10:20:01 -0500</lastBuildDate>
		<category domain="Syndic8">Business</category>
		<!-- <generator/> --> 
		<!-- <cloud/> -->
		<ttl>5</ttl>
		<fh:incremental>false</fh:incremental>
		<atom:link rel="hub" href="http://pubsubhubbub.appspot.com"/>
		<atom:link rel="self" href="http://67.214.133.121/test/rss_v32.xml"/>

		<item>
			<title>
				<![CDATA[Game changers: Five opportunities for US growth and renewal]]>
			</title>
			<link>http://www.mckinsey.com/insights/americas/us_game_changers</link>
			<guid>http://67.214.133.121/test/rss_v29.xml#6</guid>
			<pubDate>Fri, 30 Aug 2013 09:20:01 -0500</pubDate>
			<dc:creator> </dc:creator>
			<description>
				<![CDATA[
        <p>The US economy is struggling to find a new formula for vigorous growth. But all growth opportunities are not created equal. New McKinsey research pinpoints five catalysts—in energy, trade, technology, infrastructure, and talent development—that can quickly create jobs and deliver a substantial boost to GDP by 2020. An animated video below also runs the numbers on these game changers and frames the challenge for business and government to make the most of the opportunity.</p>
      ]]>
			</description>
			<content:encoded>
				<![CDATA[
        The US economy is struggling to find a new formula for vigorous growth. But all growth opportunities are not created equal. New McKinsey research pinpoints five catalysts—in energy, trade, technology, infrastructure, and talent development—that can quickly create jobs and deliver a substantial boost to GDP by 2020. An animated video below also runs the numbers on these game changers and frames the challenge for business and government to make the most of the opportunity.
        
        Four years after the official end of the Great Recession, US economic growth remains lackluster. But there is more at work here than simply the business cycle: strains in the labor market were apparent long before 2008. Today, labor-force participation is at a 34-year low, and the United States has two million fewer jobs than it did when the recession began. Weak investment, demographic shifts, and a slowdown in productivity growth are dampening the economy’s trajectory.
        But the United States does not have to resign itself to sluggish growth. Game changers: Five opportunities for US growth and renewal, a new report from the McKinsey Global Institute (MGI), identifies specific catalysts that can add hundreds of billions of dollars to annual GDP and create millions of new jobs by 2020.
        To identify these catalysts, MGI looked for developments that are poised to achieve scale immediately and could accelerate growth across multiple sectors by 2020. We also focused on areas with an immediate window for action.
        <p></p>
		 <p> Interactive B</p>
		<div class="interactive">
		<a id="interactive" onclick="newwindow=window.open ('http://www.mckinsey.com/tools/Wrappers/Wrapper.aspx?sid={80527B84-A038-47EA-A6ED-E72BFB5CF10E}&pid={BF5B4B59-99D3-4B33-A6F7-E99C34343A1E','WrapperWindow','toolbar=no, location=no, directories=no, resizable=yes, status=no,titlebar = no,scrollbars=yes, top=0,width=1000,height=680'); newwindow.focus();return false;"><img id="svgImage" width="510" data-nosvg="http://67.214.133.121/~/media/McKinsey/dotcom/Insights/Corporate Finance/Whither the stock market/deadstocks-pop-artwork2.ashx?mw=510" src="http://www.mckinsey.com/~/media/McKinsey/dotcom/Insights%20and%20pubs/MGI/Research/Productivity%20Competitiveness%20and%20Growth/The%20Future%20of%20Manufacturing/sm_th_future_of_manufacturing_slideshow.ashx" style="border-width:0px;"></a>

		</div>

        Game changers zeroes in on five mutually reinforcing opportunities:
        Shale-gas and -oil production. Powered by advances in horizontal drilling and hydraulic fracturing, the production of domestic shale gas and oil has grown more than 50 percent annually since 2007. The shale boom could add as much as $690 billion a year to GDP and create up to 1.7 million jobs across the economy by 2020. The impact will extend to energy-intensive manufacturing industries and beyond. The United States now has the potential to reduce net energy imports to zero—but only if it can successfully address the associated environmental risks. 
        US trade competitiveness in knowledge-intensive goods. The United States is one of the few advanced economies running a trade deficit in knowledge-intensive industries. But changing factor costs, a rebound in demand, and currency shifts are creating an opening to increase US production and exports of knowledge-intensive goods, such as automobiles, commercial airliners, medical devices, and petrochemicals. By implementing five strategies to boost competitiveness in these sectors, we believe the United States could reduce the trade deficit in knowledge-intensive industries to its 2000 level or close it—which would add up to $590 billion in annual GDP by 2020 and create up to 1.8 million new jobs.
        Big-data analytics as a productivity tool. Sectors across the economy can harness the deluge of data generated by transactions, medical and legal records, videos, and social technologies—not to mention the sensors, cameras, bar codes, and transmitters embedded in the world around us. Advances in computing and analytics can transform this sea of data into insights that create operational efficiencies. By 2020, the wider adoption of big-data analytics could increase annual GDP in retailing and manufacturing by up to $325 billion and save as much as $285 billion in the cost of health care and government services.
        Increased investment in infrastructure, with a new emphasis on productivity. The backlog of maintenance and upgrades for US roads, highways, bridges, and transit and water systems is reaching critical levels. The United States must increase its annual infrastructure investment by one percentage point of GDP to erase this competitive disadvantage. By 2020, that could create up to 1.8 million jobs and boost annual GDP by up to $320 billion. The impact could grow to $600 billion annually by 2030 if the selection, delivery, and operation of infrastructure investments improve.
        A more effective US system of talent development. 
        
		<p> <strong> Exhibit in figure </strong></p>
		<figure>
		 <div class="exhibitContainer"><a name="Opportunities"></a><h4 id="headlineH4">Exhibit</h4><a id="Opportunities" exhibiturl="/tools/Wrappers/Wrapper.aspx?sid={1DE8B545-31FB-4500-AAB6-FC2EADD6000B}&amp;pid={1DF8DC40-7C9C-4FF5-8528-C5AD1B295A27}" exhibitwd="0" exhibitht="0" class="black popupIframe"><h3 id="displayTextH3" class="md"></h3></a><p id="description" class="grayNote">Five US game changers could substantially boost GDP.</p><div class="clear"></div><div class="exhibit"><a id="Opportunities" exhibiturl="/tools/Wrappers/Wrapper.aspx?sid={1DE8B545-31FB-4500-AAB6-FC2EADD6000B}&amp;pid={1DF8DC40-7C9C-4FF5-8528-C5AD1B295A27}" exhibitwd="0" exhibitht="0" class="popupIframe"><img id="svgImage" width="510" data-nosvg="http://67.214.133.121/~/media/McKinsey/dotcom/Insights/Growth/US game changers/png_MGI_US_game_changers_exhibit.ashx?mw=510" src="http://67.214.133.121/~/media/McKinsey/dotcom/Insights/Growth/US%20game%20changers/SVG_USGameChangers_ex.ashx?mw=510" style="border-width:0px;"></a><div class="clear">
		 </div></div></div>
		 </figure>
		<p>
        The nation’s long-standing advantage in education and skills has been eroding, but today real improvements are within reach. At the postsecondary level, expanding industry-specific training and increasing the number of graduates in the fields of science, technology, engineering, and math could build a more competitive workforce. At the K–12 level, enhancing classroom instruction, turning around underperforming high schools, and introducing digital learning tools can boost student achievement. These initiatives could raise GDP by as much as $265 billion by 2020—and achieve a dramatic “liftoff” effect by 2030, adding as much as $1.7 trillion to annual GDP.
        These opportunities can have immediate demand-stimulus effects that would get the economy moving again in the short term and also have longer-term effects that would build US competitiveness and productivity well beyond 2020. Taking action now could mark a turning point for the US economy and drive growth and prosperity for decades to come.  
       </p>		
       <p>
        <h4> Audio</h4>
     	<audio controls>
			<source src="http://www.mckinsey.com/assets/dotcom/mgi/interactives/role_of_us_multinational_companies/MGI_The_role_of_multinational_companies_in_US_growth_and_competitiveness.mp3" type="audio/mpeg">
			Your browser does not support the HTML5 audio tag.
		</audio>
		</p>
		<p>		
		About the authors

        Susan Lund is a principal at the McKinsey Global Institute, where James Manyika is a director; Scott Nyquist is a director in McKinsey’s Houston office; Lenny Mendonca is a director in the Washington, DC, office. </p>
                <p><a href="http://www.mckinsey.com/~/media/McKinsey/dotcom/Insights/Growth/US%20game%20changers/MGI_Game_changers_US_growth_and_renewal_Full_report.ashx">Download Full Article</a></p>
      ]]>
			</content:encoded>

		</item>

		<item>
			<title >
				<![CDATA[Rethinking infrastructure]]>
			</title>
			<link>http://www.mckinsey.com/insights/engineering_construction/rethinking_infrastructure</link>
			<guid>http://67.214.133.121/test/rss_v29.xml#5</guid>
			<pubDate>Wed, 28 Aug 2013 08:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
			<description>
				<![CDATA[
        <p>How should the world deal with the problem of insufficient or inadequate infrastructure and its threats to health, safety, and economic growth? Here global authorities and McKinsey experts share insights on tackling one of the 21st century’s biggest and most expensive problems.</p>
      ]]>
			</description>
			<content:encoded>
				<![CDATA[
		<p>How should the world deal with the problem of insufficient or inadequate infrastructure and its threats to health, safety, and economic growth? Here global authorities and McKinsey experts share insights on tackling one of the 21st century’s biggest and most expensive problems. </p>
		
        
        <figure>
          <video width="400" height="300" controls>
           <source src="http://brightcove.vo.llnwd.net/e1/uds/pd/1971571337001/1971571337001_2341035695001_50-Big-Data-revolutions-healthcare-Nicolaus-Henke.mp4">
          </video>
        </figure>
        <figure>
          <video width="200" height="100" controls>
           <source src="http://brightcove.vo.llnwd.net/e1/uds/pd/1971571337001/1971571337001_2341035695001_50-Big-Data-revolutions-healthcare-Nicolaus-Henke.mp4">
          </video>
        </figure>
        <figure>
          <video controls>
           <source src="http://brightcove.vo.llnwd.net/e1/uds/pd/1971571337001/1971571337001_2341035695001_50-Big-Data-revolutions-healthcare-Nicolaus-Henke.mp4">
          </video>
        </figure>
		<p><strong>Just</strong> to keep pace with projected global growth between now and 2030, the world will have to spend $57 trillion on roads, bridges, ports, power plants, water facilities, and other forms of infrastructure. That’s nearly 60 percent above the amount spent in the last 18 years and more than the estimated value of today’s infrastructure. To deconstruct the problem of insufficient or inadequate infrastructure and to rethink the financing and delivery of better projects at lower cost, this package convenes an ongoing dialogue among global experts in construction, organization, funding, logistics, and government relations. <p/>
				
		
        <p>Improving the design, financing, and delivery of infrastructure on a global scale doesn’t call for reinventing the wheel. Infrastructure productivity: How to save $1 trillion a year, a report from the McKinsey Global Institute (MGI) and McKinsey’s infrastructure practice, shows how practical steps can boost productivity in the sector—a long-time laggard—to achieve critical cost savings. A related slideshow examines the challenge of investing in infrastructure at a time of high government deficits and explains the savings that productivity gains can provide. And in a group of video interviews, authorities such as former US secretary of state Madeleine Albright; Rockefeller Foundation president Judith Rodin; Raymond Ch’ien, chairman of Hong Kong’s MTR Corporation; Mark Wiseman, chief executive of the Canada Pension Plan Investment Board; and others explore how efforts to rethink infrastructure can improve projects, partnerships, and outcomes for society in addressing one of the world’s most urgent issues. </p>
		
		<img src="http://www.mckinsey.com/~/media/McKinsey/dotcom/Insights/Energy%20Resources%20Materials/Daniel%20Yergin%20on%20the%20future%20of%20global%20energy/daye12_frth_feature_2x.ashx" >
		<img height="100px" width="100px" src="http://www.mckinsey.com/~/media/McKinsey/dotcom/Insights/Energy%20Resources%20Materials/Daniel%20Yergin%20on%20the%20future%20of%20global%20energy/daye12_frth_feature_2x.ashx" >
		<img height="50px" width="50px" src="http://www.mckinsey.com/~/media/McKinsey/dotcom/Insights/Energy%20Resources%20Materials/Daniel%20Yergin%20on%20the%20future%20of%20global%20energy/daye12_frth_feature_2x.ashx" >
		<img height="100" width="100" src="http://www.mckinsey.com/~/media/McKinsey/dotcom/Insights/Energy%20Resources%20Materials/Daniel%20Yergin%20on%20the%20future%20of%20global%20energy/daye12_frth_feature_2x.ashx" >
		<div height="50px" width="50px">
			<img src="http://www.mckinsey.com/~/media/McKinsey/dotcom/Insights/Energy%20Resources%20Materials/Daniel%20Yergin%20on%20the%20future%20of%20global%20energy/daye12_frth_feature_2x.ashx" >
		</div>
		<img  onload="(function(ele){ele.style.display = 'none';})(this)" src="http://www.mckinsey.com/~/media/McKinsey/dotcom/Insights/Energy%20Resources%20Materials/Daniel%20Yergin%20on%20the%20future%20of%20global%20energy/daye12_frth_feature_2x.ashx" >
      ]]>
			</content:encoded>


		</item>
		

	</channel>
</rss>
